Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Fun, fun, fun
And fancy-free
Da, da, dat
Da, da, dat, doit
Full of fun and fancy-free
That's the way I wanna be
I don't let my troubles trouble me
Dau, dau, dau
Fancy-free
Full of the, full of fun
Got no time to worry none
Too busy singin' in the sun
Sweet sun
If you should have a chronic ache
Pills won't make you strong
The only tonic you should take
Is a teaspoonful of song
So if you'd really like to be
Happy-go-lucky, just like me
Drown your frowns, my
friend and you will see
You'll see
That you'll be full of fun
And fancy-free
Come along,
Lend an ear
See it for yourself
Meet a guy who's got a song
Troubles are on the shelf
He's so happy all the livelong day
Livin' life the simple way
Knowin' it's the only way to be
Just full of fun
Full of fun and fancy-free
Everyone keeps askin' me
My recipe for livin'
It's simple as the ABC's
And hardly seems worth givin'
I've tried it out in every way
It always sees me through
It's made me what I am today
That's why I'm tellin' you
- I'm a happy-go-lucky fellow
- Ooh, doo, doo, doo
- Full of fun and fancy-free
- Doo, doo, doo
You can make the whole
world seem mellow
- If you take it in your stride like me
- Ooh, doo, doo
Don't cross a bridge or
peek 'round the corner
- Until you're there
- Oh
- Just learn to smile and in a while
- Doo, doo
You'll find trouble's
a bubble of air
- Get a happy-go-lucky feelin'
- Doo
- Keep it and I guarantee
- Ooh
- That you'll find you'll wind
up livin' in the sun
- So right
Full of fun and fancy-free
That's the way I wanna be
I don't let my troubles trouble me
Now some folks like the heavy stuff
With titles five feet wide
- Not me, I'm always out for fun
- Doo, doo, doo
- I like the lighter side, yes, sir
- Hooray
La, da, da, dee, la,
da, da, dee Uh-oh!
Don't let my troubles trouble me
Don't cross a bridge or
peek 'round the corner
Until you're there
Just learn to smile and in a while
You'll find trouble's
a bubble of air
Get a happy-go-lucky feelin'
You know, you worry too much.
In fact, everybody
worries too much.
Here. Just look at
the morning paper.
Turn to any page.
You'll find the whole
world worryin'...
about some future age.
But why get so excited?
What's gonna be is gonna be.
The end of the world's
been comin' since 1903.
That's, uh, B.C., of course.
Don't cross a bridge or
peek 'round the corner
Until you're there
Just learn to smile and in a while
You'll find trouble
You bet, you'll find trouble!
Oh! Aah! Ohh!
Take it easy, son.
Why, you're just a
bundle of nerves.
You see? Jumpy as a cat!
Comes from always
rushin' into things.
Hmm! Now what have I done?
I guess I don't know
my own strength.
Sorry to upset you, miss.
Have you on your feet in a jiffy.
- Upsy-daisy.
- Mama!
Your mama isn't here, honey.
But if I can be of service,
the name is Cricket.
Uh, J. Cricket. You
can call me Jiminy.
Oops! Sorry! Ha-ha.
Oh. Howdy, chum.
Why so glum?
Say, what's the matter? You
worried about somethin' too?
Tsk, tsk. Never saw
such a dismal pair.
A deadpan doll and a droopy bear.
You ought to try my recipe.
Be full of fun and fancy-free.
Life is a song... happy, gay.
So let's have some music.
Come on! What d'you say?
"Bongo"? Now, what in
the world is Bongo?
Oh! "A Musical Story
Sung by Dinah Shore."
Well, what are we waitin' for?
Da, da, doo, da
A ringer!
It's a gift.
Da, da, dee, da, la, doh
La, da
Take it away, Dinah!
This is the story...
- of three bears.
- Yeah, I know.
The mama bear, the papa bear,
and the itsy-bitsy baby bear.
But it's not the story you expect.
This is a love story.
It's about a little girl bear...
and a big, burly,
brawny brown bear...
who wanted very much
to be her boyfriend.
But mostly, this is a
story about Bongo.
He was a circus bear.
He was born in the circus,
grew up in the circus.
In fact, Bongo was the
star of the circus.
Why, he could juggle and
dance while on a trapeze,
walk a tightrope with
the greatest of ease.
In jujitsu, he was beyond compare.
Once threw a bull
at the county fair.
Super at wrestling
and lifting weights.
Outboxed the champs of 1 7 states.
They all packed in
from near and far...
to see this death-defying star.
With mouths wide open,
they watched his ascent...
as he daringly climbed
to the top of the tent!
Then, for a grand climax,
he would gracefully
plunge 300 feet...
into a wet sponge!
Poor Bongo.
Naturally, you'd think he'd
be handled with kid gloves,
treated like a king...
and pampered like a baby.
But, no! He was tossed
around like an old shoe.
Bongo, the bear in the gilded cage.
His thoughts would wander
to an imaginary life...
far removed from the circus.
Bongo, Bongo, Bongo
Some half-forgotten
instinct kept calling him.
For you see, Bongo was a dreamer.
Hey, Bongo! Get going! You're on!
The call of the wild kept
ringing in his ears.
Psst! Hey. Bongo!
He couldn't ignore it any longer.
Bongo, Bongo, Bongo
He had to answer the call
of the great open spaces.
Come on out, Bongo.
Bongo, Bongo
Come on out, Bongo!
Bongo, Bongo.
He was crackin' up!
Bongo, Bongo!
- He was losin' his grip!
- Bongo, Bongo, Bongo!
He had to escape, to get away!
Just gotta get away!
- Bongo, Bongo!
- Gotta get away! Gotta get away.
- Bongo, Bongo, Bongo!
- Gotta, gotta, gotta!
Bongo! Bongo!
Bongo! Bongo! Bongo!
At last he was free.
Free. Free?
Oh! But this was even
better than he'd expected!
"Oh, boy, "thought
Bongo, "this is livin'!"
Whoo!
He felt so good, he just had
to run around... and jump.
Why, he even tried to growl.
"Oh, boy! A tree. That's for me!"
Just right for climbin' too.
"Oh, well. What if I can't
climb a big old tree?
This is still the place
for a fellow like me."
- Ooh, ah, ohh
- Just lazy and loafin'...
and fancy-free.
- I love to hang around
- Ooh
The lazy countryside
Where things are nice and breezy
With nature's gang around
The lazy countryside
Where life is twice as easy
Where the crickets
You don't hear in the city
Keep a-hummin' in your ear
Oh, so pretty
And it's just too much for words
Listenin' to the
chorus of the birds
I like to stay around
The lazy countryside
And while away the hours
Just kind of play around
The lazy countryside
As free as bees and flowers
There's more fun in
takin' the sun in
And to roam the spaces wide
It's the place for me
Gee, but it's great to be
'Round the lazy countryside
There's more fun in
takin' the sun in
And to roam the spaces wide
It's the place for me
Gee, but it's great to be
'Round the lazy
Countryside
"Oh, boy," thought Bongo,
"this is the stuff."
"To stretch out under
a canopy of stars...
"studding the velvet
softness of the night.
To sleep in the peace and
quiet of the woods."
The stillness of the night
descends like a sheltering veil.
Hush. All nature sleeps.
Then came the dawn.
Ohh. Bongo felt as
stiff as a board...
and as cranky as an old bear.
Bongo was discouraged.
A fine kind of bear
he'd turned out to be!
He didn't even know how
to act like a bear.
This rough, rugged
stuff wasn't for him.
Especially on an empty stomach.
Uh-uh.
Bongo thought, "This is
just too good to be true!
"I... I'm either hungry
or I'm still dreamin'.
"Ow! I'm awake! It must be true.
Oh, this is much
better than dreamin'!"
"This must be heaven.
I-it can't be real!
"It's just too good to be true.
But let me go right on dreamin',
as long as I'm with you."
This is too good
To be true
I can't believe it's real
Can it be you
I really see
I never knew
I'd find an angel
And out of the blue
You came to me
You're all the heavenly things
That I've been dreaming of
Don't spread your wings
And fly away
But if you're only
Passing through
Then take me to heaven with you
Or is this a dream
Too good to be
True
This is too good to be true
I can't believe it's real
Can it be you
I really see
I never knew I'd find an angel
Out of the blue you came to me
You're all the heavenly things
That I've been dreaming of
Don't spread your wings
Don't fly away
But if you're only
Passing through
Then take me to heaven with you
Or is this a dream
Too good to be
True
The air grew still with a sudden chill.
No talk, no laughs, no chatter.
With the trees shaking, the ground
quaking, the crowd began to scatter.
Out of his lair came the third
bear, with murder in his eye.
He took in the scene of love
serene with jealousy and surprise.
He was the roughest,
toughest, meanest bear.
Lump jaw by name,
a villain for fair.
Well... what's this?
It's no dream. It's a nightmare!
"He-He-Hello,"
was all Bongo could say.
"Hmm. Kind of unfriendly.
Probably doesn't know who I am."
"Just a moment. This is my affair."
"He-He-Hello, Lulubelle, dear."
Gosh, Bongo was surprised.
Why should Lulubelle turn against him?
That was no way for a lady to act.
Lulubelle's feelings were hurt.
All right.
She'd give Mr. Bongo
just one more chance.
"What have I done?"
Poor Bongo.
It was too good
- To be true
- Ah
Gone were his dreams.
His world was shattered.
Why hadn't someone ever told
him about all of these things...
that really mattered?
- And now,
- Ah
well, now it was just too late.
He'd never find out that
when bears are in love,
they always say it with a slap.
When a bird loves a
bird he can twitter
When a puppy falls
in love he can yap
Every pigeon likes to coo
when he says I love you
But a bear likes to
say it with a slap
When a whippoorwill's
in love he can whipper
All the horses neck and
all the turtles snap
Every deer and every dove
has a way of makin' love
But a bear likes to
say it with a slap
You can ask any bear, Oh
There's nothin' to compare
With a love tap
Strong or weak
So if you're ready for romance
and you ever get the chance
- Grab your girl
- Give her your cheek
- So when love comes along Don't be silly
- Doo, doo, doo, doo
- Never ever waste your time like a sap
Let the others hug and kiss
but the bare facts are this
That a bear likes to
say it with a slap
- Slap, slap
- Give me a love tap
Grab your bears and swing 'em wide
Shake their fur and
scratch their hide
Give her a slap
Give her a cuff
Go 'round that floor
and strut your stuff
He slapped her once and he missed her jaw
and he wound up smackin' his mother-in-law
Now here comes Grandpa gettin' in
line, And here comes baby bear behind
- Whoo-hoo!
- Oh, oh, oh, oh
When a bird loves a
bird he can twitter
When a puppy falls
in love he can yap
Every pigeon likes to coo
when he says I love you
But a bear likes to
say it with a slap
When a whippoorwill's
in love he can whipper
All of the horses neck
and all the turtles snap
Every deer and every dove
has a way of makin' love
But a bear likes to
say it with a slap
You can ask any bear
Oh, there's nothing to compare
with a love tap strong or weak
If you're ready for romance
And you ever get the chance
Grab your girl give her your cheek
So when love comes
along don't be silly
Never ever waste
your time like a sap
Let the others hug and kiss
but the bare facts are this
That a bear likes to
say it with a slap
Slap, slap
So when love comes
along don't be silly
Never ever waste
your time like a sap
Let the others hug and kiss
But the bare facts are this
That a bear likes to
say it with a slap
"I love you, Lulubelle."
"I love you too, Bongo."
You're all the heavenly things
That I've been dreaming of
Ohh don't spread your wings
And fly away
But if you're only
Passing through
Then take me to heaven with you
Ooh
Or is this a dream
Too good to be
- True
- Is it only a dream
Too good to be true
Excuse me. There.
Now who says dreams
don't come true? Well!
Three is a crowd, they say.
So I'll drop back another day.
" Miss Luana Patten."
Mmm! Well.
Of course, it's not cricket to
read other folks' mail, but...
"A party!
Tonight!" Mmm.
"The house across the way.
"Charlie McCarthy. Mortimer Snerd!
Edgar Bergen?" Huh.
Never heard of him.
"Please come!"
Why, I'd be delighted!
Join the party
Come along
It's a cinch
Can't go wrong
Now's the time to see
what you can see
The house is just across the way
Better hurry
Don't delay
You'll be full of
fun and fancy-free
Oh, dear. Nanny goats
and petticoats.
- I'm a caution.
- Yes, you certainly are.
Tell me, what is the secret
of your lovely complexion?
- Well, I... I use saddle soap.
- I see.
Yes. If I'm not being too
personal, Ophelia...
- Yeah?
- Uh, how old are you?
- Oh, I'm, uh, a girl my age.
- A girl your age?
- Yes.
- And how old is that?
- Uh, 28.
- Twenty-eight.
I thought you were a little
bit older than that.
Well, I knocked off a few
years for good behavior.
I don't care for that.
It's kid stuff. Ha-ha.
Well, we're awfully glad
you came to our party.
- Well.
- Did you have fun?
Oh, yes, indeedy. I thought Charlie made a
pig of himself with that chocolate cake.
- Oh, you're quite right.
- Yes, I am. Yes.
Yes, I agree with you.
- Well, good night, Luana.
- Good night, Ophelia.
- Bonne nuit, Mortimer.
- Uh... ma'am?
- Bonne nuit.
- Oh, yes, ma'am. Yeah, yeah. Bunny...
Uh, bunny, bunny wee,
bunny wee. Bun...
Uh... uh, I don't
know no bunny wee.
- Good night, Charlie.
- Uh, good night.
- You know, Ophelia, you look so sweet.
- Ah, what'd you say?
- I say, I think you look so sweet.
- Yes?
- I'm going to kiss you good night.
- Oh, help, help, help!
Help, he...
Isn't that a wonderful trick?
Yes, it is. Yes. I wish I could
enjoy my first childhood...
as much as he does his second.
Now, Luana, how would you like another
piece of cake or some ice cream?
- No, thank you. I'm full up.
- Some candy?
- Care for a cigar?
- Me?
How about you, Mortimer?
- Mortimer?
- Uh... I don't smoke.
I don't mean that. Well, what shall
we do now? Any suggestions?
How would you like to go down to the
city dump and watch me slug rats?
- Certainly not.
- No?
How would you like to
hear me tell a story?
Oh, I'd love it.
Wouldn't you, Charlie?
Well, I, uh... y-y-yeah... no.
This is a story that
everyone should know.
Yes, but not everyone should
tell it. And you know who.
Well, I'm going to tell it anyway.
Now, many, many years ago...
I think I'll run out
and wind a sundial.
- You'll stay right here.
- Yes, sir.
Once upon a time, long, long ago...
Funny, nothing ever
happens nowadays.
There was a place
called Happy Valley.
Now, it was called Happy Valley...
because everyone who
lived there was happy.
- No! Well, there's a hunk of logic for you.
- Are you listening, Mortimer?
- Uh, Happy Valley?
- That's right, yes.
Now just try and imagine it. Can't
you just close your eyes and see it?
Well, I can't see very
good with my eyes closed.
My eyelids get in the way.
- You create a picture in your mind's eye.
- Oh.
That's not easy for him.
His mind gets in the way.
- Now try and paint a mental picture.
- Yeah.
I... I painted a barn once, I did.
- Well, that's very interesting.
- Yeah.
- It was... It was a red barn. It was. Yeah.
- Well, forget the barn.
- Yeah.
- And try and picture Happy Valley.
- Well, I'll... I'll work on it.
- That's the spirit.
Yeah. Yeah. I'll work on it.
Let's see, uh... Let's see, now.
It's, uh... Oh, let's
say it's about, uh...
Uh, what was the question?
- Happy Valley.
- Oh, yeah! Yeah. That's right. Yeah.
- Let's see, uh...
- Think hard!
Yeah.
Let's see, uh...
Oh, I'm tired. All
that work for nothin'.
- Can I try?
- Certainly.
Yes. I think I can
see it, Mr. Bergen.
It's beautiful.
Yes, it was one of
nature's garden spots,
nestled among the
green, rolling hills.
Can't you see the lovely brook
as it flows through the valley?
Mmm. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The winding roads,
lined with stately trees.
Trees. Yeah.
Lush fields and prosperous
farms dot the landscape.
L-Landscape. Yeah.
And high on a hilltop
overlooking the valley,
- shining like a jewel, stands...
- My red barn.
No, no. It was
something much nicer.
- It was a majestic castle!
- Oh, that's pretty.
And something very precious is
kept within these castle walls.
- My
- What is it?
It's a magic, singing harp. Listen.
What a happy day
What a sunny sky, kind of
makes you sigh in a happy way
What a very merry day
All the world is gay
When your cares are light
and your heart takes flight
And you're swept away
The air is sweet with clover
The clouds are turning over
Oh, yes
They're turning over
Just to show their silver lining
My, what a happy day
Never knew such bliss
Never read of this
In a book or play
What a lovely day
What a great big gorgeous,
sumptuous thumping, bumptious
Hum-galumptious simply scrumptious
My, what a happy day
M-M-My, what a happy day
Never knew such bliss
Never read of this in a book or play
What a lovely day
What a great big gorgeous,
sumptuous thumping, bumptious
Hum-galumptious simply scrumptious
Oh, my, oh, my
What a happy
Day
Yes, the voice of
this golden harp...
cast a magic spell of joy and
prosperity over the valley.
- But it was too good to last...
- I knew there was a catch in it.
- for one day...
- They built a schoolhouse.
No, no. One day a mysterious
shadow crept over the valley.
And then something
dreadful happened!
Aaaaaah!
What happened?
When the shadow lifted,
the golden harp was gone.
No longer was the valley happy,
for without the magic of the harp,
all was misery, misery, misery.
Just like the eighth grade.
Desolation spread over the land.
Everything was drying up.
- Dry rot.
- Yes, isn't it?
- Charlie.
- Yes, sir.
The fields of golden
corn turned to dust.
Kerplop.
The laughing brook flowed no more.
To think that this was
once Happy Valley!
Now it's Gruesome Gulch.
Days pass, weeks pass.
I pass. New deal.
What happened to all the people?
Well, suppose we look in
on these humble peasants.
- Is that a peasant?
- That's a cow, stupid.
Well, at least they had milk.
Well, she used to be a
good milker. But now...
She's an udder failure.
She was the bosom friend
of a once-proud family.
Well, they're certainly out
of the high rent district.
And there they are,
three poor farmers, gripped
by the pangs of starvation.
Still alive, still breathing,
sharing a pitiful
crust between them.
Share and share alike.
Sharing and staring.
Staring and sharing.
Uh, just tell it, don't ham it.
But are their spirits broken?
Have they lost hope?
Yes. Men facing famine,
naught left but beans.
Ahem. Bean, you mean.
If it were one man
and three beans...
But, no. One bean and three men.
Well, at least there
are no bones in it.
Just look at that
miserable creature,
doggedly struggling
to maintain life,
a gaunt, lean bag of
bones and feathers.
Truly a picture of despair.
But Donald doesn't whimper.
- Donald doesn't give up.
- Shut up!
I can't stand it!
Easy, Donald. Easy!
There. There, now.
There. Easy, Donald.
I... I'll be all right.
Yeah. I'll be all right.
I'll be all right.
He says he's all
right, but I wonder.
He's suffered too much.
What diabolical thought is being
hatched in the fevered brain...
of this poor, demented duck?
Donald! No! No!
Nice bossy, bossy.
- Nice old cowsy wowsy.
- Donald!
Donald! No, Donald!
Give it here! Let me...
I just gotta eat.
I'm so... hungry.
The little fellow was
completely out of his head.
- Cut it out, will ya? I get the idea!
- He was a pitiful sight.
- Weeks without food. Poor Donald.
- Yeah, poor me!
It was all they could do to restrain him.
You see, he had just about reached...
- the end of his rope.
- Yeah.
Oh, it was a sorry
predicament indeed.
What to do? What to do?
Well, Donald may be nuts, but he's
got the right idea. Kill the cow.
Oh, no, Charlie! The cow
was their best friend.
Well, a friend in need
is a friend indeed.
- So what?
- So, they need some steak.
No! If you're gonna kill the cow,
I don't wanna hear
the rest of the story.
Well, she wouldn't have to know.
They could sneak up on her and
surprise her. Yeah, that's what we'll do.
- We'll kill the cow.
- Oh, no, Charlie. You mustn't.
We'll get a stranglehold
on her while she's asleep.
- a-a-and then push her off the cliff.
- Oh, no!
I ain't a-gonna
listen to the story.
Well, it'll be your fault
if they starve to death.
- Why don't they sell the cow?
- That's just what they did.
Well, why didn't you say so in the
first place, and save a lot of time?
I could save a lot of time by
not telling the story at all!
Your idea is not without merit.
Well, back to the
scene of desolation.
Things are beginning to
look much brighter now,
because as Mickey goes to the village to
sell the cow, the thought of prosperity...
brings new hope to the
famished farmers.
Even Donald has fully recovered,
for soon their long-empty plates...
will overflow with food.
Hey, look! Turkey,
lobster sweet potato pie
Pancakes piled up 'til
they reach the sky
Wa-wa, wa-wa, wa-wa, wa-wa
Oh-h-h-h
I wanna eat and eat and eat and eat
And eat until I die
Turkey, lobster sweet potato pie
Pancakes piled up 'til
they reach the sky
Lots of starches
Lots of greens
Fancy chocolate-covered...
- Beans!
- What d'you mean, beans?
Yeah, fellows. I sold the
cow for some magic beans!
Beans!
But Donald!
These are not ordinary beans!
They're magic beans!
If you plant these beans in the light of
a full moon, do you know what'll happen?
Yes! We get more beans!
- No, no, Donald!
- Magic beans! Phooey!
Poor Mickey,
cheated into trading his cow
for a handful of beans.
Tsk, tsk, tsk. What a mean trick!
Swindling an innocent farmer
out of all he owned...
and lying to him, telling him
that the beans were magic.
Planted in the light
of a full moon!
What a shame to deceive a
simple little peasant.
Magic beans, indeed!
- Light of a full moon.
- Bergen? Oh, Bergen!
- What?
- There's something moving.
Why, yes. Well, maybe there
is some magic in them!
All right, now let's all keep
quiet and see what happens.
Mmm.
And all through the night, it grew,
onward and upward.
That thing is a menace to aviation.
And so, with the coming of dawn,
we find the bewildered farmers
staring at a mammoth castle,
miles above the earth.
Their curiosity was aroused,
nothing could hold them back.
Who lives there? Man or monster?
Friend or foe?
A princess or a dragon?
Well, search me.
What drew them toward
this place of mystery?
Hunger? Desperation?
Or perhaps it was
love of adventure.
What a fantastic experience,
perhaps mortal man...
has never before set foot
on this strange land.
- Well, somebody did.
- Oh, gosh! Who made them?
Well, it wasn't Cinderella.
Soon they reached the moat
surrounding the castle.
But this didn't stop them. On they went,
as if drawn by some irresistible force.
And then, suddenly, without
warning, out of the sky above...
Ooh, dragonflies!
Yeah. A-flyin' front
and draggin' behind.
- Gee, what whoppers!
- Yeah. Bombers!
Come back and fight!
Finally, they reached the castle.
The hard way.
This was the biggest
adventure of their lives.
Forgotten was their hunger,
forgotten was their fear.
It took courage to scale
these massive steps,
to make this journey
into the unknown.
But these stouthearted
lads never faltered.
Three minds with but
a single thought.:
What mystery lurked within
those cold, forbidding walls?
What strange spell hovered
over this gloomy place?
Will no one answer?
Are they walking into a trap?
Do they go in?
You know, you could stand
some rehearsal on this story.
Inside, the tremendous hall
was as silent as a tomb.
Not a sign of life anywhere.
Caught with his pants...
- Charlie!
- Caught with his pants...
- Well, his slip was showing.
They gazed in speechless wonder,
almost afraid to breathe.
Suddenly they looked up.
What was it?
Food! Yum, yum, yum, yum!
Let me at it!
Oh! Who's there? Who is it?
- That's the harp!
- Boy, oh, boy!
How'd you get here?
I was kidnapped by
that wicked giant!
- Oh. A... A giant!
- A giant!
- A giant?
- Bigger than 40 men.
- Oh, no!
An ogre who had the power to turn
himself into anything, man or beast.
That calls for a drink.
It was this heartless monster that
swooped down under cover of darkness,
carried off the golden harp and...
- brought ruin to Happy Valley.
- No!
Ohh!
- I'm a giant.
- You are not.
- You're nothing of the kind.
- Well, I'm a small giant.
- No, you're not.
- I'm, uh... I'm tougher than 40 men.
- You're not.
- Well... uh, 20 men.
- No.
- No? Ten men?
Aren't you ashamed of yourself,
Charlie? Why do you act like that?
I don't know. I guess it's just
a stage I'm goin' through.
- Well, take off that moustache.
- Yeow!
Now go over there and
behave yourself.
Yes, sir. Everything I do is wrong.
But why did the giant
want to steal the harp?
Because he was cruel and selfish. He
didn't care what happened to the valley.
He just wanted someone
to sing him to sleep.
Well, why didn't he
turn on the radio?
Well, they didn't have
radios in those days.
Yeah. That's why they
called it Happy Valley.
- What did the giant look like?
- Well, he was...
Oh... I'll try and show you.
He looked something like this.
Ha. Looks like my pig Smedley.
Never mind the
self-portraits. Ha-ha.
Well, no, that isn't right.
He... He looked more like...
more like this.
There he is now. And the giant
came home for dinner, roaring...
- Drunk.
- I was not!
- I mean, he was not.
- No.
Down the castle hall
he came, roaring...
Fe, fi, fo, fum!
Fe, fi, fo, fum
He, hi, ho, hum
I'm a most amazing guy
A most amazing guy am I
Fe, fi, fo, fum
He, hi, ho, hum
I'm the stuff, I'm tellin'
you for here's what I can do
I can change myself into an elf
Fly up high like the birdies
I can disappear into atmosphere
Peekaboo. 'Cause I
know the magic wordies
Fi, fo, fe, foy
Fe, fe, fe, fe
Fifi? I don't know no Fifi.
Those are his magic
words, you know.
Fe, fi, fo, fum.
- I smell...
- You're telling us!
Wait. He may be smarter
than he looks.
Oh, I hope he doesn't find them.
Hey, Giant, you're getting warm.
Well, don't tell him!
- Behind the jar, stupid.
- Charlie!
Pot roast! Chocolate pot roast!
With stispacio...
With dismashmee...
With dismash...
With green gravy.
Feedy, fidey,
fodey,
fum!
Gesundheit.
Oh, no, you don't! You can't
get away from Willie.
I gotcha!
I think I gotcha.
Yeah, I gotcha.
Willie.
What?
He'll have to talk fast
to get out of this one.
Well, you leave it
to Mickey. Just watch.
Ten, twenty, thirty, forty.
Boy, what a life line!
But what's this here?
What is it? What is it!
Uh-oh! I can't believe it!
- Is it bad?
- Why, i-it says here...
that you can change
yourself into anything!
Sure, sure! You wanna see me?
I can change myself into
the darndest things!
Go on, gimme somethin'.
- Anything!
- Anything?
Anything.
See? Mickey never misses a trick.
- He's got a good idea.
- Well, uh...
Can you change into a fly?
A cute, teeny-weeny,
itsy-bitsy housefly?
That's it. A housefly.
Aw, you don't want a fly.
How about a bunny
with long, pink ears?
Ha. Well, of course, if you
can't do a fly, why, uh...
All right. A fly.
- Why?
- Well, they're, uh...
- Because.
- Okay.
A teeny-weeny fly.
With pink wings.
Now for the magic wordies.
Fe, fi, fo, fum
He, hi, ho, hum
I'm a most amazing guy
Te, ti, te, ti, te, ti
You sure you don't
want a pink bunny?
Hey, what is this?
You think you fool Willie.
Yeah, a couple more good ideas
like that and they're finished.
Well, I'll admit the little
fellows are in a bad fix.
But Mickey isn't one to
give up without a struggle.
And with a little luck,
they may still pull through.
This isn't the first time
Mickey's been in a tight spot.
Anybody wanna buy
a tall, thin mouse?
No, thank you. Uh, I mean no.
Yes, things look pretty
dark for the prisoners.
Looks like their goose is cooked.
Oh, Fate may yet deal
them a winning hand.
Don't forget, there's still the magic
harp. She knows the giant's weakness.
She could be my weakness.
There might still be a
chance of escape...
if she could only use her magic
voice to put the giant to sleep.
If she can't, I know who can.
Shh. Let's all be
quiet now, and see.
In my favorite dream
Everyone is so delightful
No one's mean or spiteful
In my favorite dream
Yes, and in my favorite dream
There my heart can go romancing
Dancing to a heavenly theme
But there's something else
I look forward to
It's a secret
But here's a clue
He's my favorite
You know who
You're the hero of
My most favorite
Dream
Oh, mercy. Forgive us.
In his right vest pocket
You'll find the key
The right vest pocket
Go carefully
Oh!
Ah... Ah... Ah...
I'll smash... Ah... I'll smash...
Ah... Ah... Ah... Ah...
Ah... Ah... Ah...
Where is he?
Hello?
Nightmare.
Oh, boy.
- He made it!
- He did?
- Here he comes with the key!
- Let me have it, Mickey!
Well, it looks like
success at last.
Free from the clutches of
that terrible monster.
And now to find the beanstalk, climb
down and return home in triumph,
with a big surprise
for Happy Valley.
But wait. Mickey's going
to make doubly sure.
He's taking no chances.
Just in case the
giant might wake up.
Oh!
Ha. Should have left
well enough alone.
Come back here! Come back here!
And there goes the giant!
He's helpless now, tumbling
over and over and over,
down, down, down, down.
And so with the passing
of the wicked giant,
Happy Valley echoed once again
with song and laughter.
For with the return
of the magic harp,
peace and prosperity reigned
throughout the land.
- And the people of the valley...
- We know.
Lived happily ever after.
You're a wonderful storyteller,
Mr. Bergen. Isn't he, Charlie?
Simply thrilling.
You're even better than the
old-fashioned sleeping pill.
What's the matter, Mortimer?
Oh, the poor giant got
killed, that he did.
- I don't like them sad endings.
- Oh, now, you don't understand.
W-Willie was a nice giant, he was.
He just got too big
for his britches.
- But you don't understand.
- No, don't touch me.
I'll be all right.
Oh, excuse me.
What I'm trying to explain,
Mortimer, is that Willie the Giant...
- didn't actually exist.
- No?
No. He's a metaphysical phenomenon
of your subconscious mind,
a phantasmagoria of
your mental faculties.
Yeah?
In other words, just a
figment of your imagination.
- No!
- Yes.
So there's nothing
to be upset about.
Hey! Has anybody seen anything...
of a teensy-weensy little mouse?
No. I-I-I, uh...
Oh, Mr. Bergen!
Bergen, speak to me. Speak to me.
What's the matter with him?
Somethin' he ate?
Uh, no. It's, uh...
It's a fig, uh, fig...
fig-a-mentation of his imagination.
- No!
- Yeah.
Well, uh, good night, Willie.
Uh, don't slam the roof.
You might wake Mr. Bergen.
Now some folks don't
believe in giants
Castles up above
And others say that
bears don't talk
And never fall in love
If you really wanna find
Happiness
Peace of mind
Believe in all your dreams
And you will see
You'll be full of fun and fancy
Free and full of fun
And fancy-free
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/6y6dr
Help other users to choose the best subtitles