Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Read the charges.
Dr. Jumba Jookiba...
lead scientist of
Galaxy Defence Industries...
you stand before this council
accused of illegal
genetic experimentation.
How do you plead?
Not guilty!
My experiments
are only theoretical...
completely
within legal boundaries.
We believe you actually
created something.
Created something?! Ha!
But that would be irresponsible
and unethical.
I would never, ever...
...make more than one.
What is that monstrosity?
Monstrosity!
What you see before you
is the fiirst of a new species.
I call it Experiment 6-2-6.
He is bullet-proof, fiireproof
and can think faster
than supercomputer.
He can see in the dark
and move objects
3,000 times his size.
His only instinct:
To destroy
everything he touches!
So, it is a monster.
Hey, just a little one.
It is an affront to nature.
It must be destroyed!
Calm yourself, Captain Gantu.
Perhaps it can be reasoned with.
Experiment 6-2-6
give us some sign you understand
any of this.
Show us that there is something
inside you that is good.
Hmm?
Meega, nala kweesta!
So naughty!
I didn't teach it that.
Place that idiot scientist
under arrest!
I prefer to be called
"evil genius"!
And as for that abomination...
it is the flawed product
of a deranged mind.
It has no place among us.
Captain Gantu, take him away.
With pleasure.
Hmm.
Uncomfortable?
Oh...
Good!
The council has banished you
to exile on a desert asteroid.
So, relax... enjoy the trip
and don't get any ideas.
These guns are locked
onto your genetic signature.
They won't shoot anyone but you.
Ow! Why, you...!
May I remind the captain
that he is on duty.
Secure the cell!
Aye, Captain.
Captain on deck.
All ahead full.
Do... Does this, uh,
look infected to you?
Oh!
Quiet, you.
Gunfiire in the cell bay!
Open a channel.
He's loose on Deck C!
Red alert. Seal off the deck!
Security,
converge on door seven!
Deadly force authorised.
Fire on sight!
There he is!
Security to Bridge.
It's in the ventilation system.
He's headed for the power...
...grid.
What was that?
I don't think he's
on the ship anymore.
Confiirmed.
He's taken a police cruiser.
Yeah... he took the red one.
Yee-haw!
Hmm?!
That's it!
We got it. We got it!
Hyperdrive activated.
System charging.
He's engaged his H-drive!
Warning... guidance
is not functional.
Pursuit Commander, that crazy
trog is about to make ajump!
Break formation!
Get clear of that ship!
Navigation failure.
Do not engage hyper...
Get me Galactic Control.
Where is he?!
He's still in hyperspace.
Where will he exit?
Calculating now...
quadrant 17, section 0-0-5
area 51.
A planet called... Ee-arth.
I want an expert on this planet
in here now!
What is that?
Water. Most of the planet
is covered in it.
He won't survive in water.
His molecular density
is too great.
No...
Of course.
How much time do we have?
We have projected his landing
at three hours, 42 minutes.
Oh, we have to gas the planet.
Hold it!
Hold everything!
Earth is a protected
wildlife preserve.
Yeah. We've been using it
to rebuild
the mosquito population
which, need I remind you,
is an endangered species!
Am I to assume
you are the expert?
Oh, I don't know about "expert."
Agent Pleakley at your service.
Can we not simply destroy
the island?
No! Crazyhead!
The mosquito's food of choice,
primitive humanoid life-forms
have colonies
all over that planet.
Are they intelligent?
No, but they're very delicate.
In fact, every time an asteroid
strikes their planet
they have to begin life
all over.
It's fascinating, isn't it?
With this,
I've been able to study...
What if our military forces
just landed there?
Well, that'd be a bad idea!
These are extremely
simple creatures, miss.
Landing there would create mass
mayhem and planet-wide panic!
A quiet capture would require
an understanding of 6-2-6
that we do not possess!
Who, then, Mr. Pleakley, would
you send for his extraction?
Does he have a brother?
Close grandmother, perhaps?
Friendly cousin?
Neighbour with a beard?
He got away?
I'm sure this comes
as no surprise to you.
I designed this creature
for to be unstoppable.
Which is precisely why you
must now bring him back.
What? Me?
And to reward you
we are willing to trade
your freedom for his capture.
6-2-6 will not come easily.
Maybe direct hit
from plasma cannon
might stun him long enough to...
Plasma cannon granted.
Do we have a bargain, Dr. Jumba?
B-B-But it's a delicate planet!
Who's going to control him?
You will.
Very good, Your Highness.
I... I didn't quite...
Uh, you're notjoking!
So, tell me,
my little one-eyed one
on what poor, pitiful,
defenceless planet
has my monstrosity
been unleashed?
Mahalo nui ia
Ke Ali iwahine
O Lili ulani
O ka Wohi ku
Ka pipio mai o ke anuenue
Na waihooluu a halikeole
E nana na maka
i ke ao malama
Mai Hawaii akea i Kauai...
O Kal'kaua he inoa
O Ka pua mae ole i ka I'
Ka pua maila i ka mauna
I ke kuahiwi o Mauna Kea
Ke 'maila i K'lauea
M'lamalama i Wahinekapu
A ka luna o Uw'kahuna
I ka pali kapu o Ka auea
Ea mai ke ali i kia manu
Ua wehi i ka hulu o ka mamo
Ka pua nani a o Hawai i
O Kal'kaua he inoa
Ka pua mae ole i ka I'
Ka pua maila i ka mauna
I ke kuahiwi o Mauna Kea
Ke 'maila i K'lauea...
One, two, three, four...
...M'lamalama i Wahinekapu...
Ay-yi-yi.
...A ka luna o Uw'kahuna
I ka pali kapu o Ka auea
Mahalo nui ia
Ke Ali iwahine
O Lili ulani
O ka Wohi ku...
Ea mai ke ali i kia manu
Ua wehi i ka hulu o ka mamo
Ka pua nani a o Hawai I
O Kal'kaua he inoa...
He Inoa No Kalani Kalakaua
Kulele.
- Whoa!
Stop. Stop.
Lilo, why are you all wet?
It's sandwich day.
Every Thursday,
I take Pudge the fiish
a peanut butter sandwich.
Pudge is a fiish?
And today we were out
of peanut butter!
So I asked my sister
what to give him
and she said a tuna sandwich.
I can't give Pudge tuna!
Do you know what tuna is?
Fish?
It's fiish!
If I gave Pudge tuna,
I'd be an abomination!
I'm late because I had to go
to the store
and get peanut butter
'cause all we have
is-is stinkin' tuna!
Lilo, Lilo,
why is this so important?
Pudge controls the weather.
You're crazy.
Please! Please!
Everybody calm down!
Girls...
Shh.
Lilo...
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
I won't do it again!
Maybe we should call
your sister.
No! I'll be good!
I want to dance.
I practised.
ljust want to dance.
Ooh, she bit me.
Eww!
I called your sister.
She said to wait for her
here on the porch.
We'll try again on Sunday.
Does this look infected to you?
Yeah.
You better not have rabies.
If you have rabies
the dogcatcher is
going to have to cut...
Are you going to play dolls?
You don't have a doll.
This is Scrump.
I made her,
but her head is too big.
So I pretend a bug laid eggs
in her ears, and she's upset
because she only has
a few more days to...
Lilo!
Lilo?
Oh, no.
You better be home.
Hey! Watch where you're going!
Stupidhead!
I found a new place to dwell...
Oh, Lilo!
Lilo! Open the door, Lilo!
Go away.
You make me so lonely, baby
Lilo?
We don't have time for this.
I get so lonely...
Leave me alone to die.
Come on, Lilo
that social worker's going
to be here any minute!
You still can fiind some room...
For broken-hearted lovers
to cry away their gloom
Don't make me so lonely
I get so lonely I could die...
The bellhop's tears
keep flowin'...
You are so fiinished
when I get in there!
Well, they been so long
on Lonely Street
They ain't ever
gonna look back...
Oh, I'm going to stuff you
in the blender
push "puree,"
then bake you into a pie
and feed it
to the social worker!
And when he says,
"Mmm, this is great.
What's your secret?"
I'm going to say...
"Love...
and nurturing."
Hi. Uh...
You must be the, uh...
The stupidhead.
Oh! Oh...
Oh, you know,
I'm really sorry about that
and if I'd known who you were,
of course I never would've...
Uh... I can pay for that.
It's a rental.
Are you the guardian
in question?
Yes. I'm Nani.
Nice to meet you, Mister...?
Bubbles.
Mr. Bubbles.
That's a strange...
Yes, I know.
Are you going
to invite me in, Nani?
Uh... I thought we could
sit out here and talk.
I don't think so.
Right. Uh...
And though it's
always crowded...
This way.
You still can fiind some room
For broken-hearted lovers
to cry away their gloom
You make me so lonely, baby...
Uh... wait here.
Hey!
So...
lemonade?
Do you often
leave your sister home alone?
No. Never.
Well, except forjust now.
Uh, I had to run
to the store to get some...
Oh!
You left the stove on
while you were out?
Low heat!
Just a simmer.
Mmm!
It's coming along great.
I found that this morning.
Lilo! There you are.
Honeyface...
this is Mr. Bubbles.
Nice to meet you.
Your knuckles say "Cobra."
Cobra Bubbles.
You don't look like
a social worker.
I'm a special classifiication.
Did you ever kill anyone?
We're getting off the subject.
Let's talk about you.
Are you happy?
I'm adjusted.
I eat four food groups
and look both ways
before crossing the street
and take long naps
and get disciplined.
Disciplined?
Yeah. She disciplines me
real good.
Sometimes fiive times a day.
- With bricks.
- No...
Bricks?
Uh-huh, in a pillowcase.
Okay! That's enough sugar
for you.
Why don't you run along,
you little cutie.
The other social workers
just thought she was a scream.
Thirsty?
Let me illuminate to you
the precarious situation
in which you have
found yourself.
I am the one they call
when things go wrong
and things have
indeed gone wrong.
My friends need to be punished.
Call me next time
you're left here alone.
Yep.
In case you're wondering,
this did not go well.
You have three days
to change my mind.
- Blah.
- Eww!
Lilo!
Why didn't you wait
at the school?
You were supposed to wait there!
Lilo!
Do you not understand?
Do you want to be taken away?
Answer me!
No!
No, you don't understand?
No, what?
No!
You're such a pain!
So why don't you sell me
and buy a rabbit instead?!
At least a rabbit would behave
better than you!
Go ahead!
Then you'll be happy
because it'll be smarter
than me, too!
And quieter!
You'll like it,
'cause it's stinky, like you!
Go to your room!
I'm already in my room!
Hey.
I brought you some pizza,
in case you were hungry.
We're a broken family,
aren't we?
No.
Maybe, a little.
Maybe a lot.
I shouldn't have yelled at you.
We're sisters. It's ourjob.
Yeah, well, from now on...
I like you better as a sister
than a mom.
Yeah?
And you like me better
as a sister
than a rabbit, right?
Oh...
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Yes.
Yes, I do.
I hit Mertle Edmonds today.
You hit her?
Before I bit her.
You bit her.
Lilo, you shouldn't...
People treat me different.
They just don't know
what to say.
I'll tell you what.
If you promise
not to fiight anymore
I promise not to yell at you,
except on special occasions.
Tuesdays and bank holidays
would be good.
Yeah? Would that be good?
Oh! My camera's full again.
Aren't they beautiful?
A falling star!
I call it! Get out! Get out!
I have to make a wish!
Can't you go any faster?
Oh, no!
Gravity is increasing on me.
No, it's not!
It is, too, Lilo.
The same thing
happened yesterday.
You rotten sister!
Your butt is crushing me!
Why do you act so weird?!
It's me again.
I need someone
to be my friend...
someone who won't run away.
Maybe send me an angel...
the nicest angel you have.
What we when hit?
There it is.
It stay jammed under the fender.
We better call somebody.
We're looking for something
that can defend itself...
something that won't die...
something sturdy, you know?
Like a lobster.
Lilo, you lolo.
Do we have a lobster door?
No. We have a dog door.
We are getting a dog.
So nice to see
your pretty face again!
Jumba?
We need your name and address
at the bottom of the form...
The kennel's back this way.
Go. Pick someone out.
Hello?
Hello?!
Are there any "aminals" in here?
Hello!
Hi.
Hoh... ha...
Hi...
Wow!
Oh, yes. Mm-hmm.
All of our dogs are adoptable.
Except that one!
What is that thing?!
A dog, I think.
But it was dead this morning.
It was dead this morning?!
Well, we thought it was dead.
It was hit by a truck.
I like him! Come here, boy.
Oh! Aah!
Wouldn't you like
a different dog?
We have better dogs, dear.
Not better than him.
He can talk! Say hello.
He... Hel...
Dogs can't talk, dear.
He did.
Does it have to be this dog?
Yes, he's good.
I can tell.
You'll have to think of a name
for him.
His name is... Stitch.
Now, that's not a real name...
Hmm. Uh-uh, uh-uh-uh.
...in Iceland...
but here, it's a good name.
Stitch it is.
And there's
a two-dollar license fee.
I want to buy him!
Can I borrow two dollars?
He's all yours.
You're all mine.
Well, what's he doing?
Shh! Keep quiet.
He's listening for us.
How good is his hearing?
I mean, can he...?
Why don't you run?
Coming! I'm coming!
Stop!
I havejust determined
this situation
to be far too hazardous!
Don't worry, I won't hit her.
No! That girl is a part
of the mosquito food chain.
Here! Educate yourself.
Using a little girl
for a shield.
This is low, even for you!
Whoo-hoo!
Bah!
Tear him apart
with all both my bare hands!
Have you lost your mind?!
What is it, Stitch?
We cannot be seen!
Bad dog, barking at nothing!
You can't shoot,
and you can't be seen.
Look at you!
You look like a monster.
We have to blend in.
Okay, I got to get to work.
Stick around town and stay
out of the roads, okay?
I'll meet you at 1:00.
Hmm?
Oh!
Ah!
Okay, I guess
we should be going.
What about Stitch?
My friends!
What do you want?
I'm sorry I bit you
and pulled your hair
and punched you in the face.
Apology not accepted.
Now get out of my way
before I run you over.
I got a new dog.
His name is Stitch.
That is the ugliest thing
I have ever saw.
- Yeah.
Eww! Get it away from me!
I'm gonna get a disease!
Somebody do something!
Oh, great! He's loose.
His destructive programming
is taking effect.
He will be irresistibly drawn
to large cities
where he will back up sewers
reverse street signs
and steal everyone's left shoe.
It's nice to live on an island
with no large cities.
Are you okay?
Doo-doo, doo-doo
You can shake an apple
off an apple tree
Shake-a, shake-a, sugar,
but you'll never shake me
- Uh-uh-uh
- Doo-doo-doo
No, siree, uh-uh...
Uh-uh.
...Doo-doo-doo
Doo-doo-doo
I'm gonna stick like glue
Stick because I'm...
Stuck on you
I'm gonna run my fiingers
Through your long, black hair...
Hey, over here, little buddy.
Squeeze you tighter
than a grizzly bear
- Uh-uh-uh
- Doo-doo-doo
Yes, siree, uh-huh
Doo-doo-doo, doo-doo-doo
I'm gonna stick like glue
Stick because I'm...
Stuck on you
Hide in the kitchen
Hide in the hall
Ain't gonna do you no good
at all
'Cause once I catch ya
and the kissin' starts
A team o' wild horses
couldn't tear us apart
Try to take a tiger
from his daddy's side...
When you're ready to give up,
just let us know, heh?
Whee!
Uh-uh-uh...
Yeah!
This is you.
This is your badness level.
It's unusually high
for someone your size.
We have to fiix that.
Ay-yi-yi, Lilo!
Your dog cannot sit
at the table.
Stitch is troubled.
He needs desserts.
Oh, you didn't even eat
your sweet potato.
I thought you liked them.
Desserts!
David!
I got a new dog.
Oh! You sure it's a dog?
Uh-huh.
He used to be a collie
before he got ran over.
Yum!
Hey...
Blah!
Eww!
Howzit, Nani?
Did you catch fiire again?
Nah, just the stage.
Listen, I was wondering
if you're not doing anything
this...
David, I told you, I can't. I...
I got a lot to deal
with right now.
I know. Ljust fiigured
you might need some time...
You smell like a lawn mower.
Look, I got to go.
The kid at table three's
throwing poi again.
Maybe some other time, okay?
Don't worry.
She likes your butt
and fancy hair.
I know. I read her diary.
She thinks it's fancy?
Blech!
Oh! Mmm!
Aha! Look what I fiind!
Get restraints!
Right.
Ow! Take that! Hurry!
Uh, hold stilljust a...
Aah!
Hey, Nani!
Is that your dog?
Uh...
All is well.
Please, go about your business.
I'm okay.
Oh, your head looks swollen.
Actually, she'sjust ugly.
Darling...
He'sjoking.
Ugly... look at me...
Uh, this is not working out.
Uh, b-but...
Mm-mm.
Yeah?
Well, who wants to work
at this stupid...
fakey luau anyway.
Come on, Lilo.
Did you lose yourjob
because of Stitch and me?
Nah. The manager's a vampire
and he wanted me tojoin
his legion of the undead.
I knew it.
This is a great home.
You'll like it a lot.
See?
Uh, Lilo...
Comfy.
- Hey!
What is the matter with you?
Be careful of the little angel!
It's not an angel, Lilo.
I don't even think it's a dog.
Wejust have to take him back.
He'sjust cranky
because it's his bedtime.
He's creepy, Lilo.
I won't sleep while he's loose
in the house.
You're loose in the house
all the time
and I sleepjust fiine!
Hey, what are you doing?
Stop that, Stitch!
Hey!
Look at him, Lilo.
He's obviously mutated
from something else.
We have to take him back.
He was an orphan
and we adopted him!
What about "O'hana"?
He hasn't been here that long.
Neither have I.
Dad said O'hana means family.
Huh?
O'hana means family.
Family means...
...nobody gets left behind.
Or...?
Or forgotten.
I know. I know.
I hate it
when you use O'hana against me.
Mmm.
Don't worry, you can sleep
right next to me.
Look how curious
the puppy is.
This is my room,
and this is your bed.
This is your dolly
and bottle.
See? Doesn't spill.
I fiilled it with coffee.
Good puppy. Now get into bed.
Hey!
That's mine!
Down!
Mmm!
Be careful of that!
You don't touch this!
Don't ever touch it!
No! Don't pull on her head!
She's recovering from surgery.
No! That's from my blue period.
Mmm...
There.
You know, you wreck
everything you touch.
Why not try and make
something for a change?
Ah!
Wow. San Francisco.
Save me!
Eek!
No more caffeine for you.
This little girl is wasting
her time.
6-2-6 cannot be taught to ignore
its destructive programming.
Ooh!
Push that over.
What are you doing?
Nothing!
Uh, say, I want to try it on.
No!
Share! Let me try it!
Hey! Ow! You'rejustjealous
'cause I'm pretty!
Don't move.
A mosquito has chosen me
as her perch.
She's so beautiful.
Look, another one.
And another one!
Why, it's a whole flock.
And they like me!
They're nuzzling my flesh
with their noses.
Now they're, um, they're...
I think it might be a koala.
An evil koala.
I can't even pet it.
It keeps staring at me,
like it's going to eat me.
Hello?
Nani?
Are you there?
Now, this is interesting.
What?
6-2-6 was designed
to be a monster
but now he has nothing
to destroy.
You see, I never gave him
a greater purpose.
What must it be like
to have nothing...
not even memories to visit
in the middle of the night?
Nah!
Hmm.
Hmm...
That's the Ugly Duckling.
See? He's sad
because he's all alone
and nobody wants him
but on this page,
his family hears him crying
and they fiind him.
Then the Ugly Duckling is happy
because he knows
where he belongs.
Hmm...
Want to listen to the King?
You look like an Elvis fan.
Nani.
Nani!
Uh... yeah?
Look.
We can't go on together
With suspicious minds...
Suspicious minds...
We can build our dreams...
On suspicious minds...
Heard you lost yourjob.
Well, uh, actually,
ljust quit thatjob
because, you know,
the hours arejust not conducive
to the challenges
of raising a child...
Hey!
I am so sorry about that.
What is that thing?
That's my puppy.
Really?
Thus far, you have been adrift
in the sheltered harbour
of my patience
but I cannot ignore
you beingjobless.
Do I make myself clear?
Perfectly.
And next time I see this dog
I expect it to be
a model citizen... capisce?
Uh... yes?
Newjob.
Model citizen.
Good day.
You look like an angel...
Mrs. Hasagawa?
I'm here to answer
your newspaper ad.
Elvis Presley was
a model citizen.
Walk like an angel...
I've compiled a list
of his traits
for you to practise.
Number one is dancing.
I can't talk now, dear.
I'm waiting for someone
to answer my ad.
That's why I'm here.
Hands on your hips.
Now follow my lead.
Ooh-hoo.
You fooled me
with your kisses...
Ah! That's my want ad.
I know!
Heaven knows how you lied to me
You're not the way...
Whoa, whoa!
Why is everything so dark?
I am all about coffee.
Let's move on to step two.
Walk like an angel...
Elvis played guitar. Here.
Talk like an angel...
Hold it like this,
and put your fiingers here.
See? Now you try.
...and I make great cappuccinos
and lattes with...
I wish I could, Nani,
but ljust hired Teddy
and with tourist season
ending...
Concierge-er-ing is my life.
You look like an angel...
ljust love to answer phones...
This is the face of romance.
Walk like an angel...
She looks like
she could use some lovin'.
Talk like an angel,
but I got wise...
Oh, we might have something.
Good. Now kiss her.
The devil in disguise...
I'm sure Elvis had
his bad days, too.
I'm all about saving people?
I thought
that I was in heaven...
Actually, I do think
we have an opening.
Really?
Okay, this is it.
But I was sure surprised...
Time to bring it all together.
Oh, that'd be so great!
You have no idea
how badly I need thisjob.
The devil in your eyes
You're the devil in disguise...
It's all you!
Knock 'em dead!
The devil in disguise
You're the devil in disguise...
Don't crowd him!
Oh, yes, you are
The devil in disguise...
The devil in disguise,
oh, yes...
Hey, knock it off!
Hey, Lilo!
Howzit... Nani?
We've been having a bad day.
Hmm...
Hey, I might not be a doctor
but I know
that there's no better cure
for a sour face
than a couple of boards
and some choice waves.
What you think?
I think that's a great idea.
- Aloha e, aloha e
- 'Ano'ai ke aloha e
'Ano'ai ke aloha e
'Ano'ai ke aloha e...
There's no place I'd rather be
Than on my surfboard out at sea
Lingering in the ocean blue
And if I had one wish come true
I'd surf till the sun sets
beyond the horizon
Awikiwiki, mai lohilohi
Lawe mai i ko papa he'e nalu
Flying by on a Hawaiian
roller coaster ride
Awikiwiki, mai lohilohi
Lawe mai i ko papa he'e nalu
Pi'i na nalu, la lahalaha
O ka moana, hanupanupa
- Lalala i ka la hanahana
- Whoo!
- Me ke kai hoene i ka pu'e one
- Whoo! Yeah!
Helehele mai kakou e
Hawaiian roller coaster ride
There's no place I'd rather be
Than on a seashore dry, wet free
On golden sand is where I'd lay
And if I only had my way
I'd play till the sun sets
beyond the horizon
Lalala i ka la hanahana
Me ke kai hoene i ka pu'e one
It's time to try the Hawaiian
roller coaster ride
Hang loose, hang ten,
howzit, shake a shaka
No worry, no fear,
ain't no biggy, brahda
Cuttin' in, cuttin' up,
cuttin' back, cuttin' out
Front side, back side,
goofy-footed, wipe out
Let's getjumpin',
surf's up and pumpin'
Coastin' with
the motion of the ocean
Whirlpools swirling,
cascading, twirling
Hawaiian roller coaster ride...
Oh, can't complain, Mom.
I'm camping out
with a convicted criminal
and, uh... oh, I had my head
chewed on by a monster!
Wait...
something is not right.
6-2-6 is returning
willingly to water.
Oh, hold on, Mom... another call.
Mr. Pleakley, you are overdue.
I want a status report.
Oh, uh, things are going well.
He cannot swim!
Things are going well.
Jumba, aren't they going well?
Why will he risk drowning?
Jumba?
Jumba, help me out here.
I would have expected you back
by now, with 6-2-6 in hand.
Just a few things left to pack
and, uh, we'll be...
Hang up.
We are going swimming.
Huh?
There's no place I'd rather be
Than on my surfboard out at sea
Lingering in the ocean blue
And if I had one wish come true
I'd surf till the sun sets
beyond the horizon
Awikiwiki, mai lohilohi
Lawe mai i ko papa he'e nalu
Flying by
On a Hawaiian
roller coaster ride
Awikiwiki, mai lohilohi
Lawe mai i ko papa he'e nalu
Pi'i na nalu, la lahalaha
O ka moana, hanupanupa
Lalala i ka la hanahana
- Yeah!
- Me ke kai hoene i ka pu'e one
Helehele mai kakou e
Hawaiian roller coaster ride.
Lilo!
What happened?
Oh... some lolo
must have stuffed us
in the barrel.
Where's Stitch?
Get off of her!
What happened?
Stitch dragged her down.
We lost Stitch!
Lilo? Lilo, look at me.
Look at me, baby. Are you hurt?
No.
He's unconscious,
but I think he's alive.
David, take Lilo.
This isn't what it looks like.
We were...
It-It'sjust that...
I know you're trying, Nani
but you need to think
about what's best for Lilo...
even if it removes you
from the picture.
I'll be back tomorrow morning
for Lilo.
I'm sorry.
Nani?
Is there something I can do?
No, David.
Uh, I need
to take Lilo home now.
We have a lot to talk about,
Lilo.
Thanks.
You know, I really believed
they had a chance.
Then you came along.
Lilo, honey...
we have to, uh...
Don't worry.
You're nice, and someone
will give you ajob.
I would.
Come here.
Aloha Oe, Aloha Oe
E ke onaona noho i ka lipo
One fond embrace, a ho'i a'e au
Until we meet again.
That's us before...
It was rainy,
and they went for a drive.
What happened to yours?
I hear you cry at night.
Do you dream about them?
I know that's why
you wreck things
and push me.
Our family's little now
and we don't have many toys
but if you want,
you could be part of it.
You could be our baby
and we'd raise you to be good.
"O'hana" means family.
"Family" means
nobody gets left behind
but if you want to leave,
you can.
I'll remember you, though.
I remember everyone that leaves.
L... L...
Lost.
I'm lost.
Help!
I don't like the ocean!
Oh, look,
a friendly little dolphin.
They helped sailors
in the war...
It's a shark!
It's a shark,
and it ain't friendly!
It looks like a dolphin.
Tricky fiish! Tricky fiish!
Oh, octopus, come and help me?
An octo... octopus is worse
than a shark!
I hate this planet!
Oh...
little monster!
Uh, Agent Pleakley here.
I have lost patience
with you both.
Have you captured 6-2-6
or not?
Um...
Uh, uh...
Consider yourselves fiired
and prison-bound.
Your incompetence is nothing
short of unspeakable!
But, uh... mm...
We're fiired!
Now we do it my way!
Your way?
Oh... uh, wait!
It seems I have overestimated
Jumber and Blinkley.
Uh, Jumba and Pleakley.
Whatever.
The mission is injeopardy.
This could be your chance to
redeem yourself, Captain Gantu.
How soon will you be prepared
to leave?
Immediately.
Don't run.
Don't make me shoot you.
You were expensive.
Yes. Yes, that's it.
Come quietly.
Mm... waiting.
For what?
Family.
Ah!
You don't have one.
I made you.
Oh... maybe I could...
You're built to destroy.
You can never belong.
Now come quietly
and we will take you apart.
No, no, no, no,
don't, don't run!
Don't run!
Lilo.
I didn't hear you get up.
Baby, what's wrong?
Stitch left.
Really?
It's good he's gone.
He didn't want to be here,
anyway.
We don't need him.
Lilo...
sometimes you try your hardest
but things don't work out
the way you want them to.
Sometimes things have to change
and maybe sometimes
they're for the better...
even if...
Nani!
David!
I think I found you ajob.
You what?!
Old man Kukhkini's store
but we got to hurry.
Oh, um, okay. Lilo?
Baby, this is really important.
I need you to stay here
for a few minutes.
I'm going to be right back.
Lock the door
and don't answer it
for anyone, okay?
Things are fiinally
turning around.
Aw, David, I owe you one.
That's okay.
You canjust date me,
and we'll call it even.
Come back here, you little...!
Stitch?
What is it?
Shh!
Oh, hiding
behind your little friend
won't work anymore.
Didn't I tell you?
We got fiired this morning.
New rules.
Ha!
Ooh.
Oh, ooh! Ow! Ow! Ow!
You ain't nothin'
but a hound dog...
What are we going to do?
Cryin' all the time...
Ooh! I love this song!
Pliers.
Screwdriver.
Check.
Come out, my friend
from whomever
you're hiding behind.
Well, you ain't never
caught a rabbit
And you ain't no friend
of mine...
What the...?
Ooh!
Come on!
What's the big deal?
I'll put you
back together again.
I'll make you taller
and not so fluffy!
I like fluffy!
No... No...
No!
Oh, leave my mother out of this!
You could do with a makeover.
I tried
to give you my good looks
but let's face it,
something went wrong.
No!
Quick! Follow me!
If we make it to...
You're alive!
They're all over the place!
Running away? Here...
let me stop you.
You always get in way!
Where's the girl?
What have you done to the girl?
Hello? Cobra Bubbles?
Aliens are attacking my house.
No, no, no! No aliens!
Blue punch buggy!
No punch back.
They want my dog!
There's no need
to alert the authorities.
Everything's under control.
Lilo, who was that?
Oh, good,
my dog found the chain saw.
Lilo! Don't hang...!
Ha!
You shouldn't play with guns.
Oh, okay.
Thank you.
Oh, ljust remembered.
It's your birthday!
Happy birthday!
Merry Christmas!
It's not Christmas.
Happy Hanukkah!
We're leaving Stitch?
Trust me.
This is not going to end well.
- One potato.
- Two potato.
- Three potato.
- Four.
- Five potato.
- Six potato.
Seven potato, more.
My... mother... told... me...
you... are... it.
Oh, I win!
Thanks. Mahalo plenty.
You won't be disappointed.
I'll show up early to help
with the morning deliver...
Oh, don't turn left.
No.
One of them had a giant eye
in the middle of his face.
Oh, Lilo!
Please... don't do this.
You know I have no choice.
No! You're not taking her!
I'm the only one
who understands her!
You take that away,
she won't stand a chance!
You're making this harder
than it needs to be.
You don't know what you're
doing! She needs me!
Is this what she needs?!
It seems clear to me
that you need her
a lot more than she needs you.
Lilo! Lilo!
- Lilo!
Lilo!
You ruined everything.
You're one of them?
Ooh!
Get out of here, Stitch.
Surprise!
And here I thought you'd be
diffiicult to catch.
Ho-ho-ho. Silly me.
Lilo?
Lilo!
There you go,
all buckled up for the trip.
And look... I even caught you
a little snack.
No! Stop!
Lilo.
Aah!
Okay, talk.
I know you had something
to do with this.
Now where is Lilo?
Talk! I know you can.
Okay, okay.
Where's Lilo?
Lilo...
Now all your washing is up!
You're under arrest!
Read him his rights.
Listen carefully.
Hello? Galactic Command?
Experiment 6-2-6 is in custody.
We'll wait right here.
Huh?
Don't interact with her.
Where's Lilo?
Who?
What?!
Lilo... my sister.
Uh, sorry, we do not know
anyone by this, uh...
Lilo! She's a little girl...
this big!
She has black hair
and brown eyes
and she hangs around
with that thing!
Uh...
We know her.
Bring her back.
Oh, we can't do that. Uh-uh.
That would be a misuse
of Galactic resources.
See, problem is...
we'rejust here for him.
So she's gone?
Look at the bright side.
You won't have to yell
at anyone anymore.
Come.
O'hana.
Huh?
Hey! Get away from her.
No! What did you say?
O'hana means family.
Family means...
...nobody gets left behind.
Or forgotten.
Yeah.
Hey...
What?!
After all you put me through
you expect me to help you
just like that?!
Just like that?!
lh.
Fine.
Fine? You're doing what he says?
Uh, he's very persuasive.
Persuasive?!
What exactly are we doing?
Rescue.
We're going to get Lilo?
lh.
Oh, good! I was hoping
to add theft, endangerment
and insanity to my list
of things I did today.
You, too?
Oh! Yeah, yeah, yeah!
What?
Did you think we walked here?
This is Gantu,
requesting hyperspace clearance.
Stand by for clearance.
Clearance is granted
on vector C-12.
Connect me
to the Grand Councilwoman.
Gantu, what's going on?
I thought you'd like to know
that the little abomination
is... is...
Yes, Captain?
I'll call you back.
How did you get out of there?
So what exactly are we doing?
Don't worry,
is all part of plan.
We are professionals.
Hey! Get that out of your mouth!
Hold on!
Okay, is show time!
This is it!
Go! Go! Go!
Little savage! Get off my ship!
Stitch!
Computer,
locate Experiment 6-2-6.
6-2-6 located.
We fiinish this now.
Stitch is unconscious.
What do we do now?
We stay close.
Hope for a miracle.
That's all we can do.
No!
Don't leave me, okay?
Okay.
Target 6-2-6 is in motion.
Speed is 84.
Impossible!
Stitch!
Hmm?
Abomination.
Stupidhead.
Yee-haw!
Aloha!
You're vile! You're foul!
You're flawed!
Also cute and fluffy!
You came back.
Nobody gets left behind.
Lilo!
Good dog.
Auwe!
David!
Hey, Lilo.
Can you give us a ride
to shore?
Uh...
Sure!
But I have to make two trips.
So you're from outer space, huh?
I heard the surfiing's choice.
We have 6-2-6.
Take him to my ship.
Leave him alone.
Hold on.
Grand Councilwoman,
let me explain.
Silence!
I am retiring you,
Captain Gantu.
Actually, credit for the capture
goes to...
Goes to me.
You'll be lucky if you end up
on a FluffTrog farm
after we sort this thing out.
Uh...
I think I should...
You!
You're the cause of all this!
If it wasn't
for your Experiment 6-2-6
none of this...
Stitch.
What?
My name Stitch.
Stitch, then.
If it wasn't for Stitch...
Does Stitch have to go
in the ship?
Yes.
Can Stitch say good-bye?
Thank you.
Who are you?
This is my family.
I found it all on my own.
It's little and broken...
but still good.
Yeah. Still good.
Does he really have to go?
You know as well as I
that our laws are absolute.
I cannot change
what the Council has decided.
Lilo, didn't you buy
that thing at the shelter?
Hey!
Three days ago,
I bought Stitch at the shelter.
I paid two dollars for him.
See this stamp? I own him.
If you take him
you're stealing.
Aliens are all about rules.
You look familiar.
CIA. Roswell. 1973.
Ah, yes. You had hair then.
Take note of this.
This creature has been sentenced
to life in exile
a sentence that shall be
henceforth served out here...
on Earth...
and as caretaker
of the alien life-form, Stitch
this family is now
under the offiicial protection
of the United Galactic
Federation.
We'll be checking in
now and then.
I was afraid
you were going to say that.
This won't be easy to explain
back at headquarters.
I know what you mean.
Don't let those two get
on my ship.
CIA?
Former.
Saved the planet once.
Convinced an alien race
that mosquitoes
were an endangered species.
Now, about your house...
Wait.
Lord Almighty,
I feel my temperature rising
Ooh
Higher and higher
It's burning through
to my soul
Baby, baby, baby
You're gonna set me on fiire
Yeah
My brain is flaming
I don't know which way to go
Yeah
'Cause your kisses
lift me higher
Like the sweet song of a choir
You light my morning sky
With burning love
Mmm... ooh, ooh, ooh
I feel my temperature rising
Mmm
Help me, I'm flaming
I must be a hundred and nine
Burning, burning, burning
And nothing can cool me
Mmm
ljust might turn into smoke
But I feel fiine, yeah
'Cause your kisses
lift me higher
Like a sweet song of a choir
And you light my morning sky
With burning love
Burning love
Mmm
It's coming closer
The flames are
now licking my body
Won't you help me?
I feel like I'm slipping away
Oh, yeah
It's hard to breathe
And my chest isjust a-heaving
Mmm, mmm
Lord have mercy,
it's burning a hole in me
Yeah
'Cause your kisses
lift me higher
Like the sweet song of a choir
You light my morning sky
With burning love
Burning love
Burning love!
I'mjust a hunk,
a hunk of burning love
I'mjust a hunk, a hunk
of burning love
I'mjust a hunk,
a hunk of burning love
I'mjust a hunk, a hunk
of burning love
I'mjust a hunk,
a hunk of burning love
I'mjust a hunk, a hunk
of burning love
I'mjust a hunk,
a hunk of burning love
I'mjust a hunk, a hunk
of burning love
I'mjust a hunk,
a hunk of burning...
Love.
Do, do, do
ljust can't help
falling in love with you
Wise men say
Only fools rush in
But I can't help
Falling in love with you
Shall I stay?
Would it be a sin?
If I can't help
Falling in love with you
Like a river flows to the sea
So it goes,
some things are meant to be
Some things are meant to be
Take my hand
Take my whole life too
For I can't help
Falling in love with you
Wise men say
Only fools rush in
But I can't, I can't help
Falling in love with you
Take my hand
Take my whole life too
But I can't help
Falling in love with you
Oh, I can't help
Falling in love
Falling in love with you
That's the way love goes
That's the way it goes
And my whole life, too
ljust can't help
fallin' in love with you
That's the way love goes
ljust can't help myself
So falling, baby, for you
Falling in love with you
That's the way love goes
That's the way it goes
'Cause I can't help
Falling in love with you
With you...
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/tjk3
Help other users to choose the best subtitles