Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Make mine music
And my heart will sing
And it's always spring
All the world goes romancing
When melody fills the night
And even the stars go dancing
To the music of the moonlight
Make mine music
And I'll dream of you
And the dream comes true
Music will play the shadows away
When everything seems to go wrong
So make mine music
And life will be a song
Make mine music
Gather round me, children,
and I'll tell a story
Of the mountains
in the days when guns was law
When two families got disputin'
It was bound to end in shootin'
So just listen
and I'll tell you what I saw
Oh, the Martins and the Coys
They was reckless mountain boys
And they took up family feudin'
when they'd meet
Every durn time!
They could shot each other quicker
than it took your eye to flicker
They could knock a squirrel's eye out
at 90 feet
All their fightin' started
one bright Sunday morning
I remember!
Cos old Grandpa Coy
was full of mountain dew ...
Just as quiet as a church mouse
He stole into the Martins' henhouse
Cos the Coys,
they needed eggs for breakfast too
After that they started out
to fight in earnest
And they scarred the mountains up
with shot and shell
There was uncles, brothers, cousins
Why, they bumped them off by dozens
Just how many bit the dust
is hard to tell
Oh, the Martins and the Coys
They were reckless mountain boys
At the art of killin'
they became quite deft
Mighty deft
They all knowed they shouldn't do it
But before they hardly knew it
On each side
they only had one person left
Only one person left
Now, the sole remaining Martin
was a maiden
And as pretty as a picture was this Grace
- While the one survivin' boy
- Was the handsome Henry Coy
And the folks all knew
they'd soon meet face to face
- After her, Henry!
- Go get her, boy!
- Knock him off, Gracie!
- Shoot that Coy!
So they finally met
upon a mountain pathway
And Henry Coy,
he aimed his gun at Grace
Right at Grace
He was set to pull the trigger
when he saw her pretty figure
You could see
that love had kicked him in the face
Oh, the Martins and the Coys
They were reckless mountain boys
But they say their ghostly cussin'
gives you chills
Cos the hatchet sure was buried
when sweet Grace and Henry married
It broke up the best durn feud
in these here hills
Come on, everybody, let's dance!
Way down yonder, not far off,
a jay bird died with the whoopin' cough
Do si do, little more dough,
chicken in the bread pan pickin' out dough
"Granny, will your dog bite?". "No, child,
no, he lost his teeth a long time ago"
Now swing your partners,
And promenade the hall,
Same old road, same old train
Watch that monkey walk that rail
Now first couple out to the right
Go round that couple and take a peek
Come back to the centre
and shake your feet
Round that couple and peek once more
Back in the centre and circle four
Swing your partner and call your hound
Right foot up and left foot down
Bottom of your foot
make a hole in the ground
Now you're tall with a smile
Once and a half and go hog wild
Sooey, hog, sooey!
Look at him run!
What's the hurry, Henry?
Now you may think
that this is where the story ended
But I'm tellin'you
them ghosts don't cuss no more
Cos since Grace and Henry wedded
they fight worse than all the rest did
And they carry on the feud
just like before
Roll along, blue bayou
Through the silv'ry foam
In the deep
where sleepy shadows roam
While we roll, blue bayou
In your dreamy light
Memories echo in my heart tonight
I hear the echo of our song of love
Murmuring low
And here am I
Still haunted by
The ghost of long ago
Roll along, blue bayou
Through the silv'ry foam
Roll the blue and sleepy shadows home
Roll along, blue bayou
Through the silv'ry foam
In the deep
where sleepy shadows roam
While we roll, blue bayou
In your dreamy light
Memories echo in my heart tonight
Roll along, blue bayou
Through the silv'ry foam
Roll the blue
and sleepy shadows home
Roll along, blue bayou
Through the silv'ry foam
Roll the blue and sleepy shadows home
Across the blue moon
Boy!
Hop in the old jalop and...
Head for the malted shop and...
All the cats join in
Down goes my last two bits
Comes up one banana split
And all the cats join in
Drop your jack in the old jukebox
Play your favourite disc
When you dance with the bobby socks
You dance at your own risk
RIP
Everybody swing
Yes, swing till the rafters ring
And all the cats join in
Rafters ringing, how they're swinging
All the cats join in
I'm so lonely and blue
When I'm without you
I don't know what I'd do, sweetheart.
Without you
The joy and tears
that love endears
Would have no meaning
If I didn't have you
To keep me dreaming
At the close of each day
When I'm without you
And my heart kneels to pray
I pray about you
You take a star
And lead it far away from heaven
And the star will be lost
As I'm lost without you
At the close of each day
When I'm without you
And my heart kneels to pray
I pray about you
You take a star
And lead it far away from heaven
And the star will be lost
As I'm lost without you
Oh, what a lark
to ride out to the park
And just to see Casey
They travelled for miles
and they stand in the aisles
And just to see Casey
The ladies
don't understand baseball a bit
They don't know a strike
from a foul or a hit
But when they see Casey
that dame has got it
Casey, the pride of them all
The outlook wasn't brilliant
for the Mudville nine that day
The score was four to two
With but one inning left to play
Listen, ya bunch of bush leaguers,
it's the ninth inning!
It's the wind-up! The blow-off!
Come on, unbutton your shirts!
Now get in there and fight!
Who's up next?
Cooney!
The coach was really worried
when Cooney went to bat
For all he had to offer
was 300 pounds of fat
Ah, but Cooney was determined,
he tried to do his worst
He kept his batting average, all right
And as usual died at first
You're out!
Hooray for our side! Hooray! Hooray!
- Aw, shut up!
- Sit down!
- I'll kick the stuffin' out of him!
- Yeah, run that guy outta town!
Barrows was the next one up,
and Barrows made a hit
Wow, he smacked a beauty -
right in the pitcher's mitt
You're out!
A straggling few got up to go
Ah, but the loyal fans stood pat
They'd put up even money now
were Casey at the bat
Ah, but Flynn preceded Casey
Of all the stupid guys
The bat is getting in his hair
Now the hair is getting in his bat
Egad! He let drive a single -
much to his own surprise
Safe!
The next one in the line-up
was "No Hit" Jimmy Blake
Of all the mugs in Mudville
he was the biggest fake
But he was really blazing
and to the wonderment of all
Blake the Fake
tore the cover off the ball
And when the dust had lifted
and they saw what had occurred
There was Jimmy safe at second
and Flynn a-huggin' third
Cosy, isn't it?
You're safe!
We want Casey! We want Casey!
We want Casey!
Oh, Casey's the guy
with his eye on the ball
But mostly the ladies
Casey's the guy who's the idol of all
Casey is mighty and manly
Casey's a dangerous gent
Egad, when he goes to bat,
hang onto your hat
He's batting a thousand percent
with the ladies
Oh, Casey has nerve
and he knows every curve
He's no hokey-pokey
He gets away
with that old double play
He's sure okey-dokey
He makes all the ladies go gaga,
it's true
No wonder they swoon
when he comes into view
He was the Sinatra of 1902
Casey, the pride of them all
The pitcher's nerves were jagged
and his knees began to shake
Ah, can't catch me! Can't catch me!
One eye was watching Flynn
and the other eye watching Blake
While the frightened pitcher
ground the ball into his hip
Defiance gleamed in Casey's eye
A sneer curled Casey's lip
And now the leather-covered sphere
came hurtling through the air
And Casey stood a-watching it
in haughty grandeur there
Close by the sturdy batsman
the ball unheeded sped
"That ain't my style," said Casey
Strike one!
... the umpire said
From the benches, black with people,
there went up a mighty roar
Like the beating of the ocean
on a stern and distant shore
Kill him! Kill the umpire!
... yelled the cutie from the stand
And it's likely they'd have killed him
Had not Casey raised his hand
With a smile of Christian charity
great Casey's visage shone
He stilled the rising tumult
and bade the game go on
He signalled to the pitcher
and once more the spheroid flew
But Casey still ignored it
and the umpire said, quote:
Strike two!
Unquote.
"Fraud!" cried the maddened thousands,
and the echo answered "Fraud!"
But one scornful look from Casey...
And the audience was awed
They saw his face grow stern and cold
They saw his muscles strain
And they knew that Casey
would not let that ball go by again
The sneer has gone from Casey's lip
His teeth are clenched in hate
He pounds with cruel violence
his bat upon the plate
And now the pitcher holds the ball
And now he lets it go
And now the air is shattered
by the force of Casey's blow
Somewhere in this favoured land
The sun is shining bright
Ah, yes...
Somewhere bands are playing sweet
And somewhere hearts are light
Somewhere men are laughing
Somewhere children shout
But there is no joy in Mudville -
Mighty Casey has struck out
Casey, the pride of them all!
Whaddaya know? The game is over.
Two silhouettes
Together in the afterglow
Become as one
When lights are low
And with the night slumbering on
We'll build a dream for two
A perfect dream
Set to a theme lovely as you
Two hearts on fire
Will soon inspire
The stars to dance
The flames that stray
Will light the way
To our romance
And when I hold you in my arms
To my heart's delight
Two silhouettes
will drift away into the night
Two hearts on fire
Will soon inspire
The stars to dance
The flames that stray
Will light the way
To our romance
And when I hold you in my arms
To my heart's delight
Two silhouettes
Will drift away
Into the night
Now, this is the story of...
Peter and the Wolf.
As you know, in the musical score
of Peter and the Wolf
each character is represented
by an instrument in the orchestra -
Peter by the string quartet.
The bird, whose name is Sasha,
by a flute, way up high.
Sonia, the duck, by an oboe. Like this...
And here is Ivan, the cat,
represented by a clarinet
in a very low register.
Grandpapa is an old bassoon.
The shooting of the hunters' guns
by the kettledrums.
And there is also a wolf.
Little does that wolf know
what's in store for him this day.
For our hero, little Peter,
armed to the teeth,
is setting forth to capture him.
There seems to have been
a change of plans.
For Peter's grandpapa
thinks that little boys like Peter
should not go out to hunt the wolf.
This is very embarrassing
for a great hunter.
This is Sasha,
the little bird we told you about.
Excitable little chap, isn't he?
Forgetful, too.
"Hello, Petey. Where you goin'?
Can I go, Petey? Can I?"
"Oh, boy, a gun!"
"Loaded, too. "
"Goin' hunting? Oh, that's for me!"
"Everything's OK, Petey.
Come on, let's go. "
The wolf!
But it isn't the wolf at all.
It's only Sonia the duck.
"Hello, Sonia. "
"Hello, Petey. "
Now Sonia wants to join the party.
Imagination is a wonderful thing.
But sometimes it can run away with you.
"You coward!"
Now who's this?
Oh, it can't be...
Oh, no. It's Ivan the cat.
Hello, Ivan.
Ivan's a peaceful, fun-loving sort - maybe
a little shy on brains. You know the type.
Hey, look out, Sasha!
"Stop it, stop it, stop it, stop it!"
Oh, how can they ever get any place if
they're going to fight among themselves?
Ivan, you ought to be ashamed.
"You big bully!"
"You cat in the grass!"
Come on, Sasha. Ivan's sorry.
He won't do it again.
And so, once more,
our little band of intrepid hunters
sets forth to find the wolf.
And they find him.
Sonia! Sonia!
Behind you! Look out!
W-O-L-F!
Oh, that wolf is everywhere!
Peter, do something!
Oh, no.
Look, Peter, why don't you...
Maybe if you could...
Then maybe, Peter... Oh, well...
Peter, don't just stand that way.
Don't stand that way, either.
Oh, Sonia!
This is no time to relax.
Poor Sonia.
Well, that's one gone.
Goodbye, Sonia.
Will this crime go unavenged?
Not if little Sasha can help it.
You beast!
Take this! And this! And this!
How do you like this, eh?
And this, eh?
How about this, eh?
Not so good, eh?
Good work, Sasha!
Trouble.
Sasha! Sasha, get up!
Get up! Get out of there!
Look out, please, for over-confidence.
This is bad.
This is very bad.
Saved!
Just when things are looking blackest...
Hark! What's that we hear?
What's this we see?
The hunters!
Misha, Yasha and Vladimir.
That's Vladimir in the middle.
Wait a minute, I'll show you.
W-O-L-F. Wolf.
Wolf?
To the rescue!
Oh, Peter, you're safe!
You've captured the wolf.
Oh, happy day!
I think I'll say that again.
Oh, Peter, what a hero!
You too, Ivan.
Everybody's happy - except the wolf.
But little Sasha isn't happy.
He's thinking of his lost playmate, Sonia.
Sonia...
Sonia?
Sonia! Then you're not dead!
You're safe!
Oh, Sonia,
this is the most wonderful, wonderful day!
The wolf is captured - Peter caught him!
One, two, three...
Johnnie Fedora met Alice Bluebonnet
In the window of a department store
'Twas love at first sight
And they promised one night
They'd be sweethearts for evermore
Johnnie would serenade Alice
Toora-lay, toora-li, toora-lu
He sang of a beautiful palace
Of a beautiful hatbox for two
But Johnnie Fedora
lost Alice Bluebonnet
To a patron of the department store
Her beauty was sought by
the girl she was bought by
For twenty-three ninety-four
Johnnie, O Johnnie
Your Alice Bluebonnet
Will always be waiting for you
So don't give up hoping
And don't give up dreaming
For true love will come smiling through
Johnnie Fedora
was lonely and stranded
In the window of the department store
When, lo and behold
He was suddenly sold
And his heart became gay once more
Johnnie sang out like a robin
Toora-lay, toora-li, toora-lu
To strangers he'd come up a-bobbin'
"I thought you were someone I knew "
He looked for her uptown
and crosstown and downtown
From the Brooklyn Bridge
to the Jersey shore
It all seemed in vain
Till he heard the refrain
Of the song Alice sang of yore
Johnnie, O Johnnie!
Your Alice Bluebonnet
Will always be waiting for you
So don't give up hoping
And don't give up dreaming
For true love will come smiling through
Johnnie kept yearning,
he kept on returning
To the window of the department store
His voice became hushed
He was literally crushed
And it started to rain and pour
Each place he went he kept calling
- Toora-lay
- Toora-li
- Toora-lu
- La la la
His spirits kept falling and falling
For his Alice was nowhere in view
But hey-noni-noni,
an ice man found Johnnie
And he cut him
to fit on his horse's ears
'Twas done without malice
For beside him was Alice
And they lived on for years and years
Giddup!
You Johnnie Fedoras
You Alice Bluebonnets
Whenever you find yourself blue
You'll find it's June in December
If you just remember
That true love will come smiling through
This is how it all began
Just a little back-page item
about a voice that sang at sea
And then this fantastic news appeared
on the front page
And then in screaming headlines
Extra! Read all about it! Paper!
A singing whale?
- Whaddaya know ?
- Imagine that
Huh! I don't believe it
I don't believe it
For who ever heard
of an operatic whale?
I don't believe it
And headline followed headline
Then doctors and experts
And men of anatomical biology
Debated and argued
And quoted ichthyology
Impossible! Preposterous!
We savagely deny it
Magnificent! Miraculous!
We certainly certify it
And even the great impresario
Of the Grand Opera
Raised an eyebrow
And tried and tried to figure it out
This whale, she's maybe
swallowed an opera singer.
That's it! This whale,
she's a-swallowed an opera singer!
I find-a the great Signor Donatelli
in-a the fish market.
I discovered the great Lilli Garli
in-a the honky-tonky.
Why not I find-a the opera singer
in-a the belly of a whale, huh?
I do it!
Oh, get me a great big schooner
and get me a good harpooner
Photographers and reporters
from all the newspapers
Publicity! Publicity!
Publicity!
Publicity, yes. But to Whitey the seagull,
it was opportunity -
the big opportunity
for his friend Willie the whale.
There was no time to lose.
He must bring these two together.
Well, there was Tetti-Tatti now.
And Tetti-Tatti
was in for a wonderful surprise.
Because Willie
hadn't swallowed any opera singer,
he could really sing.
Listen.
Mamma's little baby
loves shortnin', shortnin'
loves shortnin' bread
Mamma's little baby
loves shortnin', shortnin'
loves shortnin' bread
Two little chillun, lyin' in bed
One of 'em sick
and the other 'most dead
Called for the doctor,
the doctor said
"Feed them chillun on shortnin' bread"
Mamma's little baby
loves shortnin', shortnin'
loves shortnin' bread
Mamma's little baby
loves shortnin', shortnin'
loves shortnin' bread
After all these years of casting
his "Shortnin' Bread" upon the waters,
now at last
success lay just over the waves.
Willie! Willie, look!
That's you, Willie!
He's looking for you!
It's your big opportunity.
Willie's going to be a great star.
Our Willie, going to sing grand opera.
Goodbye, my friends.
I'm off to be discovered
At last, the long years of patient waiting,
the endless hours of faithful practice
were about to be rewarded.
As Willie sped to his audition
he wondered what to sing
for his opening number.
What would impress this impresario?
How about a bit of Figaro?
Yes, sure, Figaro.
There she's blows! There she's blows!
Figaro.
Figaro!
Figaro! Figaro! Figaro!
Figaro! Figaro! Figaro! Figaro!
Figaro!
Shoot-a de whale!
Hurry up, hurry up!
Rescue the opera singer!
Don't-a worry, we'll a-save you!
Bravo!
Bravissimo! Bravo!
Ah, but they hadn't heard the half of it.
They hadn't even heard a third of it.
For Willie was no ordinary singing whale.
Willie could sing in three separate voices:
tenor...
baritone...
and bass.
Why, Willie was a singing miracle.
Let-a me up! This is the mutiny!
Mamma mia!
He's-a swallowed two opera singers!
He's-a swallowed three opera singers!
Stubborn, deluded Tetti-Tatti.
For right before his very eyes was the
biggest discovery in all musical history.
Just imagine, a whale singing opera
on the very stage of the Met.
Bravo! Bravissimo!
Je suis Méphisto
Roi d'enfer
Je veux...
Ta vie
I got him! I got him!
Vittoria!
Now Willie will never sing at the Met.
But don't be too harsh on Tetti-Tatti.
He just didn't understand.
You see, Willie's singing was a miracle,
and people aren't used to miracles.
And you, faithful little friend,
don't be too sad.
Because miracles never really die,
and somewhere in whatever heaven
is reserved for creatures of the deep,
Willie is still singing -
in a hundred voices,
each more golden than before.
And he'll go on singing, amid
the applause and the cheering, forever.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org