Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
♪ MELODY TIME ♪
♪ IT'S TIME TO SWING ALONG ♪
♪ TO A HAPPY LAND OF SONG ♪
♪ WHERE LOVE IS THE THEME ♪
♪ MELODY TIME ♪
♪ IT'S TIME FOR SWEET ROMANCE ♪
♪ WON'T YOU GIVE
YOUR HEART A CHANCE ♪
♪ TO JOIN IN AND SING ♪
♪ JOIN IN AND SING ♪
♪ TAKE A TIP FROM THE BIRDS ♪
- ♪ YOU DON'T NEED WORDS ♪
- ♪ NO WORDS ♪
♪ FOR MUSIC HAS CHARM ♪
♪ IT'S THE LANGUAGE OF LOVE ♪
♪ WHEN YOUR LOVE'S
IN YOUR ARMS ♪
♪ RHYTHM AND RHYME ♪
♪ SURE HELP A HEART ALONG ♪
♪ SO COME ON
AND SING A SONG ♪
♪ IT'S MELODY TIME ♪
YES, IT'S MELODY TIME.
TIME TO HITCH YOUR WAGON
TO A SONG.
'CAUSE A SONG'S
THE ONE AND ONLY THING
THAT'LL TAKE YOU
OVER THE RAINBOW
TO THE LAND
WHERE MUSIC IS KING.
SO, COME ON AND
JOIN IN THE FUN.
THERE'S SOMETHING HERE
FOR EVERYONE.
YOU'LL FIND
RHYTHM AND ROMANCE,
REASON AND RHYME,
SOMETHING RIDICULOUS...
♪ SOMETHING SUBLIME ♪
♪ YOU CAN'T GO WRONG
IF YOU SWING ALONG ♪
♪ WITH MELODY, HARMONY
COME TO THE JUBILEE ♪
♪ IT'S MELODY TIME! ♪
A MEMORY OF WINTERTIME
LONG AGO,
OF CLEAR CRISP AIR,
OF NEW FALLEN SNOW,
OF AN ETCHING OF FROST
ON A WINDOWPANE.
AN ECHO OF SLEIGH BELLS
HEARD FROM THE LANE.
HERE IN THIS WONDERLAND,
ROMANCE IS THE THEME.
FOR THIS IS A STORY
OF LOVE'S YOUNG DREAM.
♪ DON'T YOU KIND OF
LOVE DECEMBER? ♪
♪ WHEN THE MERRY
SNOW BELLS CHIME? ♪
♪ WE'RE TOGETHER ♪
♪ ONCE UPON A WINTERTIME ♪
♪ EVERY SINGLE
SNOWFLAKE FALLING ♪
♪ PLAYS A JINGLE
DOWN YOUR SPINE ♪
♪ LOVELY WEATHER ♪
♪ ONCE UPON A WINTERTIME ♪
♪ ON THE FROZEN POND
FOLKS ARE SWAYING ♪
♪ SWEETHEART, WHO CARES? ♪
♪ WE'LL HAVE MORE FUN
SLEIGHING ♪
♪ BEHIND TWO
CHESTNUT MARES ♪
♪ WHEN WE SAY
"GOODBYE, DECEMBER" ♪
♪ MERRY BELLS
NO LONGER CHIME ♪
♪ WE'LL REMEMBER ♪
♪ ONCE UPON A WINTERTIME ♪
♪ DON'T YOU KIND OF
LOVE DECEMBER? ♪
♪ WHEN THE MERRY
SNOW BELLS CHIME ♪
♪ WE'RE TOGETHER
ONCE UPON A WINTERTIME ♪
♪ EVERY SINGLE
SNOWFLAKE FALLING ♪
♪ PLAYS A JINGLE
DOWN YOUR SPINE ♪
♪ HERE WE ARE TOGETHER
LOVELY WEATHER ♪
♪ ONCE UPON A WINTERTIME ♪
♪ JINGLE BELLS, JINGLE BELLS
JINGLE ALL THE WAY ♪
♪ ON THE FROZEN POND
FOLKS ARE SWAYING ♪
♪ SWEETHEART, WHO CARES? ♪
♪ WE'LL HAVE MORE FUN
SLEIGHING ♪
♪ BEHIND TWO
CHESTNUT MARES ♪
♪ WHEN WE SAY
"GOODBYE, DECEMBER" ♪
♪ MERRY BELLS
NO LONGER CHIME ♪
♪ WE'LL REMEMBER
ONCE UPON A WINTERTIME ♪
♪ REMEMBER DECEMBER
[RUSHING WATER]
♪ ON THE FROZEN POND
FOLKS ARE SWAYING ♪
♪ SWEETHEART, WHO CARES? ♪
♪ WE'LL HAVE MORE FUN
SLEIGHING ♪
♪ BEHIND TWO
CHESTNUT MARES ♪
♪ WHEN WE SAY
"GOODBYE, DECEMBER" ♪
♪ MERRY BELLS
NO LONGER CHIME ♪
♪ WE'LL REMEMBER ♪
♪ ONCE UPON A WINTERTIME ♪
FREDDY MARTIN,
AN ARDENT ADMIRER
OF THE CLASSICS,
INSPIRED BY RIMSKY-KORSAKOV'S
FLIGHT OF THE BUMBLEBEE,
HAS CHOSEN TO INTERPRET
THIS LIVELY FANTASY
IN HIS OWN UNIQUE STYLE.
IN A FLIGHT THAT IS
FAST AND FURIOUS,
A CONFUSED LITTLE CHARACTER
TRIES DESPERATELY TO ESCAPE
FROM THE HECTIC HARMONY
OF AN INSTRUMENTAL NIGHTMARE.
[PIANO PLAYS JAZZY
FLIGHT OF THE BUMBLEBEE]
ON THE PAGES OF
AMERICAN FOLKLORE,
A LEGION OF MIGHTY MEN
HAVE LEFT THE SYMBOLS
OF THEIR GREATNESS.
THERE WAS PAUL BUNYAN'S AX.
JOHN HENRY'S HAMMER.
DAVY CROCKETT'S RIFLE.
AND THEN, QUITE UNEXPECTEDLY,
ONE COMES UPON A TIN POT HAT,
A BAG OF APPLE SEED,
AND A HOLY BOOK.
AND STRANGELY ENOUGH,
THESE ARE THE SYMBOLS
OF ONE OF THE MIGHTIEST
MEN OF ALL.
JOHN CHAPMAN.
A REAL LIFE PIONEER.
WITH THE PASSING YEARS HOWEVER,
REALITY HAS GIVEN WAY TO LEGEND.
UNTIL TODAY, WE KNOW
THIS REMARKABLE MAN
SIMPLY AS JOHNNY APPLESEED.
THIS IS HIS STORY.
TOLD BY AN OLD SETTLER
WHO KNEW JOHNNY WELL.
LISTEN.
[NARRATOR] WELL, SIR,
EVERY TIME I SEE
AN APPLE BLOSSOM SKY,
I THINK OF JOHNNY APPLESEED.
'CAUSE OF COURSE
THEM CLOUDS UP THAR,
THEY AIN'T REALLY
CLOUDS AT ALL. NO, SIR.
SHUCKS, THERE WOULDN'T BE
NO APPLE BLOSSOM SKY
IF IT WEREN'T FOR
THE FACT THAT JOHNNY...
BUT NOW HOLD ON, HERE.
GUESS I BETTER START
BACK TO THE BEGINNING.
THAT'S WHEN JOHNNY
LIVED ON A FARM,
NEAR PITTSBURGH TOWN.
THE YEAR WAS 1806,
OR MAYBE THERE AROUND.
NOW JUST TO LOOK AT HIM,
YOU'D SAY JOHNNY APPLESEED
NEVER WOULD MAKE A PIONEER.
HE WAS SUCH A SAWED-OFF
SCRAWNY LITTLE FELLA.
OF COURSE, THAT DIDN'T
PHASE JOHNNY NONE.
SHUCKS, HE HAD HIS APPLE TREES
IN THE MORNING SUN,
AND THE EVENING BREEZE.
[WHISTLING]
♪ THE LORD IS GOOD TO ME ♪
♪ AND SO I THANK THE LORD ♪
♪ FOR GIVING ME
THE THINGS I NEED ♪
♪ THE SUN AND RAIN
AND AN APPLE SEED ♪
♪ YES, HE'S BEEN GOOD TO ME ♪
[WHISTLING]
♪ I OWE THE LORD SO MUCH ♪
♪ FOR EVERYTHING I SEE ♪
♪ I'M CERTAIN IF IT
WEREN'T FOR HIM ♪
♪ THERE'D BE NO APPLES
ON THIS LIMB ♪
♪ HE'S BEEN GOOD TO ME ♪
♪ OH, HERE AM I
'NEATH THE BLUE, BLUE SKY ♪
♪ DOING AS I PLEASE ♪
♪ SINGING WITH MY
FEATHERED FRIEND ♪
♪ HUMMING WITH THE BEES ♪
♪ I WAKE UP EVERY DAY ♪
♪ AS HAPPY AS CAN BE ♪
♪ BECAUSE I KNOW THAT
WITH HIS CARE ♪
♪ MY APPLE TREES
THEY WILL STILL BE THERE ♪
♪ OH, THE LORD IS GOOD TO ME ♪
WORKING, SINGING,
CAREFREE AND GAY.
THAT'S HOW JOHNNY
SPENT EACH DAY.
ATTENDING TO HIS APPLE TREES.
BUT LATELY, LITTLE JOHNNY HERE
WOULD FEEL A STIR IN THE AIR.
A RUMBLING, ROLLING UNDERBEAT
OF RESTLESS MEN
WITH RESTLESS FEET.
♪ GET ON THE WAGON
ROLLING WEST ♪
♪ OUT TO THE GREAT UNKNOWN ♪
♪ GET ON THE WAGON
ROLLING WEST ♪
♪ OR YOU'LL BE LEFT ALONE ♪
♪ WE'VE MADE A HOME BEFORE
WE'RE STARTING OUT AGAIN ♪
♪ WE AIN'T AFEARED
OF MAN OR BEAST ♪
♪ WE'RE STRONG-HEARTED MEN ♪
♪ SO, GET ON THE WAGON
ROLLING WEST ♪
♪ SEEKING A LAND THAT'S NEW ♪
♪ GET ON THE WAGON
ROLLING WEST ♪
♪ THERE'S PLENTY OF ROOM
FOR YOU ♪
♪ GET ON THE WAGON
ROLLING WEST ♪
♪ OUT TO THE GREAT UNKNOWN ♪
♪ GET ON THE WAGON
ROLLING WEST ♪
♪ OR YOU'LL BE LEFT ALONE ♪
♪ THE RIVERS MAY BE WIDE ♪
♪ THE MOUNTAINS MAY BE TALL ♪
♪ BUT NOTHING STOPS
THE PIONEER ♪
♪ WE'RE TRAIL-BLAZERS ALL ♪
♪ GET ON THE WAGON
ROLLING WEST ♪
♪ OUT TO THE GREAT UNKNOWN ♪
♪ GET ON THE WAGON
ROLLING WEST ♪
♪ OR... ♪
[SINGING FADES]
POOR JOHNNY.
HE WEREN'T NO PIONEER
AND HE KNOWED IT.
IT WAS ALL JUST PRETEND.
AND THEM FOLKS GOING WEST
TO BUILD THIS NATION
SURE MADE PICKING APPLES
LOOK LIKE A PLUM
USELESS OCCUPATION.
WELL, SIR, THAT'S WHEN
A MIRACLE HAPPENED.
"WELL, WHAT'S HOLDING YOU,
JOHNNY?" SAYS A VOICE.
GO ON. GO ON OUT WEST,
IF THAT'S YOUR CHOICE.
WELL, SIR, IT WAS AN ANGEL.
JOHNNY'S OWN PRIVATE
GUARDIAN ANGEL.
MIGHT LOOK MIGHTY QUEERSOME
TO YOU AND ME.
BUT, YOU KNOW,
THAT'S JUST THE WAY
JOHN FIGURED HE'D BE.
WELL, SPEAK UP, BOY.
DON'T STAND THERE GAWKIN'.
UNLOCK YOUR JAW
AND GET TO TALKIN'.
YES, SIR. YES, SIR!
WHY DON'T I GO WEST?
'CAUSE I AIN'T GOT THE MUSCLE.
OR THE BREADTH OF CHEST.
OUT THERE, IT'S
THE STRONG MEN WHO SURVIVE.
I'M ABOUT THE PUNIEST
FELLER ALIVE.
SHAME TO YOU, JOHNNY.
YOU GOT FAITH, AND COURAGE,
AND A LEVEL HEAD.
BUT SHUCKS, YOU SEE, SIR.
ALL I KNOW IS APPLE TREES.
AND WHAT'S WRONG WITH APPLES,
IF YOU PLEASE?
AIN'T THEY ABOUT
THE FINEST FRUIT
IN ALL THE LAND?
WHY, SHOOT, MAN.
THEY TAKE THE CAKE.
JUST THINK, JOHNNY,
OF ALL THE THINGS
THAT APPLES MAKE.
THERE'S APPLE PICKLES.
♪ OH, SO TASTY APPLE TARTS
AND APPLE PASTRY ♪
♪ APPLE DUMPLINGS,
NOT TO MENTION ♪
- APPLE SAUCE?
- YES.
♪ THERE'S APPLE FRITTERS
LIGHT AS THISTLE ♪
♪ AND FOR FOLKS
TO WET THEIR WHISTLE ♪
[BOTH] ♪ TANGY APPLE CIDER
IN A GLASS ♪
♪ STEW 'EM, FRY 'EM
BOIL 'EM, BAKE 'EM ♪
♪ APPLE PIE AND
APPLE CAKE 'EM ♪
♪ YOU CAN COOK 'EM ANY WAY ♪
♪ THERE'S APPLE THIS
AND APPLE THAT ♪
♪ THE RECIPES'D
FILL YOUR HAT ♪
♪ WHY I COULD CARRY ON
LIKE THIS ALL DAY! ♪
♪ SO, PACK YOUR STUFF
AND GET A-GOIN' ♪
♪ GET THEM APPLE TREES
A-GROWIN' ♪
♪ THERE'S A LOT OF WORK
OUT THERE TO DO ♪
[BOTH] ♪ THERE'S A LOT
OF WORK TO DO ♪
YES, SIR!
I MEAN, NO SIR.
YOU SEE, SIR...
I AIN'T GOT THE TRAPS,
AIN'T GOT THE GEAR.
OR NONE OF THE THINGS
I'LL NEED OUT THERE.
YOU AIN'T GOT THE...
DADGUMMIT, BOY.
I'M ASHAMED OF YOU!
YOU GOT THE STUFF
TO SEE YOU THROUGH.
WHY, YOU GOT ALL
THE SEEDS YOU'RE NEEDING.
AND FOR PRETTY
DARN GOOD READING,
♪ THERE AIN'T NOTHING
FINER THAN YOUR BOOK ♪
HERE'S A MIGHTY HANDY BONNET.
EVEN GOT A HANDLE ON IT.
♪ TURN IT UPSIDE DOWN
AND YOU CAN COOK ♪
♪ SO, COME ON, SON
AND GET A-GOIN' ♪
♪ GET THEM APPLE TREES
A-GROWIN' ♪
[BOTH] ♪ THERE'S A LOT
OF WORK OUT THERE TO DO ♪
♪ OH, THERE'S
A LOT OF WORK TO DO ♪
[NARRATOR] WELL, SIR,
THAT'S HOW IT ALL BEGAN.
THAT'S HOW JOHNNY ALL ALONE
SET OUT TO MEET
THE GREAT UNKNOWN.
IT WAS A MIGHTY BIG
AND FEARSOME PLACE
FOR A MAN TO FACE.
A LITTLE MAN AND ALL ALONE.
WITHOUT NO KNIFE,
WITHOUT NO GUN.
AND THOUGH THE FOREST
IS DARK AND WIDE,
WITH FEARSOME CRITTERS
ON EVERY SIDE,
JOHNNY JUST KEPT WALKING ON.
WALKED UNTIL AT LAST HE FOUND
A LITTLE SPOT OF OPEN GROUND.
WITH FERTILE SOIL
AND WARMSOME BREEZE.
A LIKELY PLACE
FOR APPLE TREES.
NOW THE VARMINTS HERE,
THEY COULDN'T KNOW
IF JOHN WAS FRIEND
OR JOHN WAS FOE.
SO, SOME TOOK OFF
IN SUDDEN FLIGHT.
SOME GOT SET
TO CLAW AND BITE.
BUT IF JOHNNY SEEN 'EM,
HE PAID NO HEED.
JUST GOT BUSY
PLANTING APPLE SEED.
[WHISTLING]
NOW THEM VARMINTS
COME FROM EVERYWHERE.
TO WATCH THAT MAN
A-DIGGIN' THERE.
DIDN'T LIKE WHAT
THEY WERE SEEING.
DIDN'T TRUST NO HUMAN BEING.
YEP, THAT ORNERY HUMAN
HAD TO GO.
BUT WHO WAS A-GONNA
TELL HIM SO?
WELL, NOT A SOUL
COULD ANSWER THAT.
TILL HERE COME ALONG
A BLACK AND WHITE CAT.
NOW HE WEREN'T TOO BRIGHT,
BUT HE DIDN'T MUCH CARE.
HE KNOWED HE HAD
A CERTAIN AIR... ABOUT HIM.
WELL, SIR, THAT DONE IT.
THE CRITTERS NE'ER SEEN
THE BEAT OF THAT.
THE LIKES OF A HUMAN
LIKING THAT CAT.
WHY SHUCKS,
THIS LITTLE MAN
HAD WENT AND BUSTED
EVERY PRECEDENT.
HE WAS THE VERY FIRST TO COME
WITHOUT NO KNIFE,
WITHOUT NO GUN.
AND SO IT WAS,
FROM THAT TIME ON,
EVERY LAST LIVING VARMINT
WAS A FRIEND TO JOHN.
- THEY SURELY WAS.
- [JOHN WHISTLING]
♪ THE LORD IS GOOD TO ME ♪
♪ AND SO I THANK THE LORD ♪
[ECHOING] ♪ FOR GIVING ME
THE THINGS I NEED ♪
♪ THE SUN, AND RAIN
AND THE APPLE SEED ♪
♪ YES, HE'S BEEN GOOD TO ME ♪
WELL, AS TIME WENT BY,
JOHNNY KEPT RIGHT ON
PLANTING HIS APPLE TREES.
AND MAKING FRIENDS EVERYWHERE.
AND HIS BEST FRIENDS
WAS THE PIONEERS.
FOR OF COURSE,
JOHN WAS PLANTING MORE
THAN AN APPLE TREE.
HE WAS PLANTING HIS OWN
BOUNDLESS FAITH
AND COURAGE, TOO.
AND THAT GIVE FOLKS
NEW HEART.
NEW HOPE IN THE JOB
THEY HAD TO DO.
AND AS MORE AND MORE PIONEERS
COME TO PUSH BACK THE FOREST,
THE KINDLY DEEDS
OF LITTLE JOHNNY APPLESEED
SPREAD THROUGHOUT THE LAND.
AND MORE THAN ONCE,
WITH A GOOD
OLD-FASHIONED JUBILEE,
FOLKS WOULD HONOR
JOHNNY APPLESEED.
AND THE FRUIT
OF THE APPLE TREE.
♪ COME RIGHT OUT TO
THE RIGHT OF THE RING ♪
♪ INSIDE ARCH
AND OUTSIDE UNDER ♪
♪ IT AIN'T GONNA RAIN
WITHOUT NO THUNDER ♪
♪ FIRST AND THIRD,
BALANCE, SWING ♪
♪ COME RIGHT OUT TO
THE RIGHT OF THE RING ♪
♪ BUCKLE UP FOUR
WITH EIGHT HANDS ROUND ♪
♪ I'LL SWING YOURS,
YOU SWING MINE ♪
♪ I'LL SWING MY GIRL,
HALF THE TIME ♪
[FIDDLE MUSIC]
♪ WHEN YOU'RE STRAIGHT
TO A DO-SI-DO ♪
♪ CHICKEN IN THE BREAD PAN
KICKIN' OUT DOUGH ♪
♪ BIG PIG ROOTIN' UP
A LITTLE TATER ROW ♪
♪ ONE MORE CHANGE
AND HOME YOU GO ♪
NOW SOMETIMES,
IF JOHN WAS A-PASSIN' BY,
HE'D MOSY OVER AND KIND OF
LOOK IN ON THE DOINGS.
'CAUSE IT SURE
TICKLED HIM TO SEE
HOW THE FRUIT
OF HIS LABORS
BROUGHT ALL KINDS
OF FOLKS TOGETHER
AND MADE 'EM
GOOD NEIGHBORS.
♪ NOW DUCK FOR THE APPLE
FOUR IN A ROW ♪
♪ THANK YOU, SON
CORNERS GO ♪
♪ APPLE CORE
BALTIMORE ♪
♪ BITE THAT APPLE
TO THE CORE ♪
[CHIPMUNK LAUGHING]
♪ READY NOW! ♪
♪ ALAMADE LEFT WITH
THE OL LEFT HAND ♪
♪ BACK TO YOUR PARTNER
RIGHT AND LEFT ♪
♪ WHIRL 'EM RIGHT ♪
AND WHIRL 'EM WRONG ♪
♪ STRAIGHTEN 'EM OUT
AND TROT 'EM ALONG ♪
♪ RIGHT AND LEFT
FOUR IN A ROW ♪
♪ SECOND COUPLE
ON THE CORNERS GO ♪
♪ APPLE CORE,
BALTIMORE ♪
♪ GENT AND THE PRETTY GIRL
TRY ONCE MORE ♪
[CROWD LAUGHING]
- [BELL RINGING]
- [WOMAN] COME AND GET IT!
THE VICTUALS ON,
THE TABLE'S SET.
IT'S ALL WAITING TO BE ATE.
COME AND GET IT!
[CROWD SHOUTING]
- [MAN] APPLE PICKLES.
- [2ND MAN] MIGHTY TASTY!
- APPLE BUTTER.
- APPLE PASTRY.
- APPLE DUMPLINGS.
[WOMAN] HOW'D YOU LIKE
SOME APPLE SAUCE?
YES, MA'AM.
YEP, JOHNNY DID BRING FOLKS
A HEAP OF HAPPINESS.
SHUCKS, HE WEREN'T
LOOKING FOR THANKS.
DIDN'T HAVE TIME FOR IT.
HE KNOWED A MAN
CAN'T TAKE NO REST,
IF HE AIMS TO PLANT
THE WHOLE DARN WILDERNESS
IN APPLE TREES.
AND SO IT WAS,
FOR MORE THAN 40 YEARS,
JOHN WALKED AND PLANTED
THAT OLD FRONTIER.
YES, SIR.
40 YEARS OF WALKING
AND PLANTING.
AND IN THAT SPACE
OF TWO SCORE YEARS,
THIS LITTLE MAN...
HE THROWED HIS SHADOW
CLEAR ACROSS THE LAND.
ACROSS 100,000
MILES SQUARE.
AND IN THAT SHADOW EVERYWHERE,
YOU'LL FIND HE LEFT
HIS BLESSINGS THREE.
♪ LOVE AND FAITH ♪
♪ AND THE APPLE TREE ♪
BOY, FOR SLEEPING,
YOU TAKE THE CAKE.
COME ON, GET UP!
[WHISTLING]
WE GOT A LONGSOME TRIP
TO MAKE.
WHY, MR. ANGEL,
HOW D'YA DO?
I'M FINE.
AND HOW BE YOU?
I'M FINE, JUST FEELING...
WHAT!
WHO'S THAT SLEEPING
IN THE EVENING DUSK?
WHY, THAT'S JUST
YOUR HUSK, JOHN.
- YOUR MORTAL HUSK.
- MY HUSK?
YOU MEAN TO SAY...
I'M PASSED AWAY?
DAGNABIT, ANGEL!
I JUST CAN'T GO.
GOT CROPS TO HARVEST,
SEEDS TO SOW.
NOW, HOLD ON, BOY.
DOWN HERE ON EARTH,
YOUR WORK IS THROUGH.
BUT YONDER...
WELL, WE NEED YOU, JOHNNY.
YEP, WE SURE DO.
YOU THINK WE HAVE
MOST ALL WE PLEASE.
BUT WE AIN'T.
WE'RE KINDA SHORT
ON APPLE TREES.
WELL, I SWAN!
I DIDN'T KNOW.
WHAT ARE WE WAITING FOR?
COME ON, LET'S GO!
♪ WE'RE WASTING TIME
LET'S GET A-GOIN' ♪
♪ GET THEM APPLE TREES
A-GROWIN' ♪
[BOTH] ♪ THERE'S A LOT
OF WORK UP THERE TO DO ♪
♪ OH, THERE'S A LOT
OF WORK TO DO ♪
WELL, SIR, NOW YOU KNOW
THE REASON WHY
WHENEVER I SEE
THAT CERTAIN SKY
I THINK OF LITTLE JOHN.
'CAUSE IT'S LIKE I SAID,
IF YOU RECALL,
THEM CLOUDS AIN'T REALLY
CLOUDS AT ALL.
THEY'RE APPLE BLOSSOMS,
IF YOU PLEASE.
FROM JOHN'S HEAVENLY
ORCHARD OF APPLE TREES.
♪ AND SOMEDAY THERE'LL
BE APPLES THERE ♪
♪ FOR EVERYONE
IN THE WORLD TO SHARE ♪
♪ THE LORD IS GOOD TO ME ♪
THERE'S DRAMA,
THERE'S EXCITEMENT
AND THERE'S HARMONY FOR THREE
IN THIS STORY
OF ADVENTURE ON THE SEA.
NOW, FEATURED IN THIS EPIC,
IS A SHIP OF PROUD DESIGN.
NO, IT'S NOT THIS OCEAN LINER.
WE TAKE A DIFFERENT LINE.
SO, WITH A HUFF AND A PUFF
AND A CHUG, CHUG, CHUG.
AND A PERKY LITTLE HOOT.
WE INTRODUCE OUR HERO,
THE TUGBOAT LITTLE TOOT.
♪ LITTLE TOOT WAS JUST A TUG ♪
♪ JUST A HAPPY HARBOR TUG ♪
♪ AND HE CAME FROM
A LINE OF TUGBOATS ♪
♪ FINE AND GRAY ♪
♪ BUT IT SEEMS
THAT LITTLE TOOT ♪
♪ SIMPLY DIDN'T GIVE A HOOT ♪
♪ THOUGH HE TRIED TO BE GOOD
HE NEVER COULD BEHAVE ♪
♪ CHUG-A-CHUG-A-CHUG,
HEAVE HO, MY LAD ♪
♪ I'M A BIG TOOT
JUST LIKE MY DAD ♪
♪ PULL BIG BOATS
WITH THE OL' HEAVE HO ♪
♪ AND AWAY WE GO! ♪
♪ CHUG-A-CHUG-CHUG-CHUG
CHUG-A-CHUG-CHUG-CHUG ♪
WHEE!
♪ HE MADE
THE OCEAN LINERS WAIT ♪
♪ WHILE HE MADE
A FIGURE EIGHT ♪
♪ WITH THE GREATEST OF EASE
HE CUT THROUGH THE SEAS ♪
♪ AND SLIDE ♪
♪ BUT HE WENT TOO FAR
ONE DAY ♪
♪ WHEN HE SLID
IN BIG TOOT'S WAY ♪
♪ AND IT WASN'T A JOKE
FOR IT NEARLY BROKE ♪
♪ BIG TOOT'S PRIDE ♪
[SPUTTERING]
[COUGHING]
♪ WON'T YOU EVER GROW UP,
LITTLE TOOT ♪
♪ WHEN THERE'S WORK
TO BE DONE ♪
♪ ALL YOU THINK OF IS FUN ♪
♪ WON'T YOU EVER GROW UP,
LITTLE TOOT! ♪
♪ OH, LITTLE TOOT
HAD QUITE A SCARE ♪
♪ HE DECIDED THEN AND THERE ♪
♪ THAT HE'D TRY TO BE GOOD
AS GOOD AS HE COULD BE ♪
[TOOTING]
♪ SO, WHEN HIS DAD
CAME PUFFIN' SLOW ♪
♪ WITH A MIGHTY SHIP IN TOW ♪
♪ LITTLE TOOT
WENT TO HELP HIM ♪
♪ TAKE IT OUT TO SEA ♪
♪ CHUG-A-CHUG-A-CHUG
HEAVE HO, MY LAD ♪
♪ I'M A BIG TOOT
JUST LIKE MY DAD ♪
♪ PUSH BIG BOATS
WITH THE OL' HEAVE HO ♪
♪ AND AWAY WE GO ♪
♪ CHUG-A-CHUG-CHUG-CHUG
CHUG-A-CHUG-CHUG-CHUG ♪
- WHOO!
- [WHISTLE]
[DISTRESS SIGNAL]
[SIRENS]
♪ WON'T YOU EVER GROW UP ♪
♪ LITTLE TOOT ♪
♪ WHEN YOU GET INTO TROUBLE ♪
♪ YOU GET INTO IT DOUBLE ♪
♪ WON'T YOU EVER GROW UP ♪
♪ LITTLE TOOT? ♪
♪ WHAT A SHAME
WHAT A SHAME ♪
♪ YOU'VE DISGRACED
YOUR FATHER'S NAME ♪
♪ WON'T YOU EVER GROW UP ♪
♪ LITTLE TOOT ♪
[BELL RINGING]
[SNIFFING]
[SHIP BELL]
BAD BOY.
SHAME.
TOO BAD.
HUMPH!
[THUNDER]
♪ HE WAS DRIFTING ALL AROUND ♪
♪ WHEN A STORM
CAME CRASHING DOWN ♪
♪ IN THE BILLOWING SEA ♪
♪ HE TOSSED AND TOSSED
AND TOSSED ♪
♪ AND HIS HEART
WAS FILLED WITH FEAR ♪
♪ FOR HE KNEW
THE ROCKS WERE NEAR ♪
♪ WITH THE WAVES IN PURSUIT
LITTLE TOOT KNEW ALL WAS LOST ♪
♪ THEN HE SAW
A ROCKET'S FLARE ♪
♪ COME A-BURSTING IN THE AIR ♪
♪ AND HE SUDDENLY KNEW
THAT HE MUST DO OR DIE ♪
♪ FOR A SHIP
WAS IN DISTRESS ♪
♪ AND AS HE PUFFED AN SOS ♪
♪ HE RACED TO THE RESCUE
OF THE SHIP NEARBY ♪
[DISTRESS SIGNAL]
TRY, TRY, TRY!
DO OR DIE, DO OR DIE
DO OR DIE, DO OR DIE!
[BIRD SQUAWKING]
[TOOTING]
♪ WELL, IT SEEMS YOU'VE
GROWN UP, LITTLE TOOT ♪
♪ YOU'RE A BRAVE,
YOU'RE A BRAVE ♪
♪ BRAVE LITTLE TOOT ♪
♪ CAN'T YOU HEAR
THAT CHEERING CROWD? ♪
♪ YOU HAVE MADE
YOUR DADDY PROUD ♪
♪ YOU ARE NOW A BIG TOOT
LITTLE TOOT ♪
♪ YES, YOU'RE NOW A GREAT
BIG TOOT, LITTLE TOOT ♪
[TOOTING]
THERE'S POETRY
IN TREES THEY SAY.
AND WELL, ONE DAY
A POET FOUND IT.
THEN A MUSIC MASTER
WOVE AROUND IT MELODY.
AN ARTIST TOUCHED IT.
GAVE IT FORM IN COLORS
RICH AND WARM.
NOW WE BRING TO YOU
THESE THREE:
POEM, PICTURE, MELODY.
A SIMPLE TRIBUTE TO A TREE.
♪ I THINK THAT I
SHALL NEVER SEE ♪
♪ A POEM ♪
♪ LOVELY AS A TREE ♪
♪ A TREE WHOSE HUNGRY MOUTH ♪
♪ IS PRESSED ♪
♪ AGAINST THE EARTH'S ♪
♪ SWEET FLOWING BREAST ♪
♪ A TREE THAT LOOKS ♪
♪ AT GOD ALL DAY ♪
♪ AND LIFTS HER LEAFY ARMS ♪
♪ TO PRAY ♪
♪ A TREE THAT MAY
IN SUMMER WEAR ♪
♪ A NEST OF ROBINS
IN HER HAIR ♪
♪ UPON WHOSE BOSOM
SNOW HAS LAIN ♪
♪ WHO INTIMATELY
LIVES WITH RAIN ♪
♪ POEMS ARE MADE ♪
♪ BY FOOLS LIKE ME ♪
♪ BUT ONLY GOD ♪
♪ CAN MAKE A TREE ♪
TO THE INTOXICATING
RHYTHM OF THE SAMBA,
A TALENTED MISS SERVES UP
A MUSICAL COCKTAIL
WITH A TRUE
LATIN AMERICAN FLAVOR.
SO, IF THREE BOISTEROUS
BIRDS OF A FEATHER
FALL UNDER THE INFLUENCE
OF THIS TORRID TROPICAL TEMPO,
DON'T BLAME THEM.
BLAME IT ON THE RHYTHM
OF THE SAMBA.
♪ IF YOUR SPIRITS
HAVE HIT A NEW LOW ♪
♪ AND THEY LONG
TO HIT A NEW HIGH ♪
♪ ONE LITTLE MUSICAL COCKTAIL ♪
♪ WILL LIFT THEM TO THE SKY ♪
♪ MIX A JIGGER OF RHYTHM ♪
♪ WITH A STRAIN
OF A FEW GUITARS ♪
♪ ADD A DASH OF THE SAMBA ♪
♪ AND A FEW MELODIOUS BARS ♪
♪ AND THEN, AND THEN ♪
♪ YOU TAKE A SMALL CABAÇA ♪
[SHAKING]
♪ ONE PANDEIRO ♪
♪ TAKE A CUÍCA ♪
♪ YOU'VE GOT THE FASCINATING
RHYTHM OF THE SAMBA ♪
♪ IF GUITARS ARE STRUMMING ♪
♪ BIRDS ARE HUMMING ♪
♪ DRUMS ARE DRUMMING ♪
♪ THEN YOU CAN BLAME IT ON
THE RHYTHM OF THE SAMBA ♪
♪ FOR THERE IS SOMETHING
'BOUT THE BEAT YOU CLING TO ♪
♪ THAT'S THE TYPE OF SONG
YOU SING TO ♪
♪ BUT THE KIND OF THING
YOU SWING TO ♪
♪ WHEN YOU GET TO BOUNCING
WITH THE BEAT IN YOUR FEET ♪
♪ FOR WHEN YOU'RE BOUNCING
TO THE BEAT YOU'RE REELING ♪
♪ WITH THE CARIOCA FEELING ♪
♪ BUT IF YOU WANT
TO HIT THE CEILING ♪
♪ HERE IS ALL
YOU HAVE TO DO ♪
♪ YOU TAKE A SMALL CABAÇA ♪
♪ ONE PANDEIRO ♪
♪ TAKE A CUÍCA ♪
♪ YOU GOT THE FASCINATING
RHYTHM OF THE SAMBA ♪
[SHAKING]
[ORGAN PLAYS]
[BIRD LAUGHING]
[DRUMS PLAYING]
[SINGING]
[SINGING CONTINUES]
[LAUGHING]
HERE'S A TALL TALE STRAIGHT
FROM THE CHUCK WAGON.
JUST THE WAY THE OLD-TIMERS
USED TO TELL IT.
ACCORDING TO THEM,
PECOS BILL
WAS THE ROUGHEST, TOUGHEST,
ROOTENEST, TOOTENEST,
SHOOTENEST COWPOKE
THAT EVER LIVED.
WELL, ANY STORY
ABOUT OLD PECOS
IS BOUND TO BE RIGHT
STRONG MEDICINE, SO...
MAYBE IT'S BEST TO SASHAY
INTO IT KINDA GENTLE LIKE.
♪ SHADES OF NIGHT ARE FALLIN' ♪
♪ AS THE WIND BEGINS TO SIGH ♪
♪ AND THE WORLD
IS SILHOUETTED ♪
♪ 'GAINST THE SKY ♪
[WHISTLING]
♪ BLUE SHADOWS ♪
♪ ON THE TRAIL ♪
♪ BLUE MOON ♪
♪ SHINING THROUGH THE TREES ♪
♪ AND THE PLAINTIVE WAIL ♪
♪ FROM THE DISTANCE ♪
[COYOTES HOWLING]
♪ COMES A DRIFTIN' ♪
♪ ON THE EVENING BREEZE ♪
♪ MOVE ALONG ♪
♪ BLUE SHADOWS ♪
♪ SOON THE DAWN WILL COME ♪
♪ AND YOU'LL BE ON YOUR WAY ♪
♪ BUT UNTIL THE DARKNESS ♪
♪ SHEDS ITS VEIL ♪
♪ THERE'LL BE BLUE SHADOWS ♪
♪ ON THE TRAIL ♪
♪ MOVE ALONG ♪
♪ MOVE ALONG, BLUE SHADOWS ♪
♪ MOVE ALONG, MOVE ALONG,
MOVE ALONG ♪
♪ SOON THE DAWN WILL COME ♪
♪ AND YOU'LL BE ON YOUR WAY ♪
♪ ON YOUR WAY ♪
♪ BUT UNTIL THE DARKNESS ♪
♪ SHEDS ITS VEIL ♪
♪ THERE'LL BE BLUE SHADOWS ♪
♪ ON THE TRAIL ♪
♪ SHADOWS ON THE TRAIL ♪
[HOWLING]
- UNCLE ROY?
- YES, HONEY.
WHAT MAKES THE WOLVES
HOWL LIKE THAT?
WOLVES? THOSE ARE COYOTES,
AREN'T THEY?
YEP, THEY'RE COYOTES.
BOBBY'S RIGHT.
THEY ALWAYS HOWL
WHEN THE MOON'S BRIGHT.
WHY?
THAT'S QUITE A STORY.
- COWBOYS IN IT?
- YES, SIREE.
INDIANS TOO?
I COULD THROW IN
MAYBE TWO OR THREE,
BUT MOSTLY THIS STORY'S
ABOUT PECOS BILL.
PECOS BILL?
- WHO'S HE?
- [GUITAR STOPS]
WHAT? NEVER HEARD
OF PECOS BILL?
IMAGINE THAT!
I THOUGHT EVERYBODY
KNOWED PECOS.
BOBBY, I'M SURPRISED AT YOU.
BILL WAS THE WORLD'S
GREATEST BUCKAROO.
♪ HE WAS THE ROUGHEST,
TOUGHEST CRITTER ♪
♪ NEVER KNOWN TO BE A QUITTER ♪
♪ 'CAUSE HE NEVER HAD
NO FEAR FOR MAN OR BEAST ♪
YEP, THAT THERE
PECOS BILL WAS...
- [NEIGHING]
- EASY, TRIGGER.
I'M NOT FORGETTING
BILL'S HORSE.
SHUCKS, I COULDN'T
FORGET WIDOW MAKER.
WIDOW MAKER?
THAT'S A FUNNY NAME.
THAT HORSE EARNED IT,
JUST THE SAME.
HE WAS A KILLER.
DYNAMITE ON THE HOOF.
WIDOW MAKER
WAS BILL'S BEST PAL.
UNTIL ALONG CAME THAT
BEAUTIFUL PRAIRIE GAL.
[WHINNYING]
SHUCKS, A WOMAN
IN THE STORY.
BUT WHAT A WOMAN!
♪ SHE WAS FRESH AS THE DEW ♪
♪ ON A PRAIRIE ROSE ♪
♪ A TRUE THOROUGHBRED ♪
♪ FROM HER HEAD TO HER TOES ♪
♪ THAT THERE WAS
SLUE FOOT SUE ♪
♪ SWEET SUE ♪
SLUE FOOT SUE, HUH!
I'D RATHER HEAR
ABOUT THE COYOTES.
UNCLE ROY,
YOU STARTED TO SAY...
WHY THE COYOTES HOWL
AT THE MOON THAT WAY?
YOU'RE RIGHT, HONEY,
BUT IT ALL FITS TOGETHER.
CAN'T TELL ONE
WITHOUT THE OTHER.
BECAUSE THE STORY OF BILL
AND THAT SLUE FOOT GAL
IS A STORY OF COYOTES
AND WHY THEY HOWL.
I'M GETTING DOWN TO
THE DETAILS RIGHT NOW.
[ROY] NOW, HERE ON THE MAP
OF THE OLD U.S.,
COMPLETELY SURROUNDED
BY WILDERNESS, LIES TEXAS.
[COWBOY] AMEN.
[ROY] THERE'S SOME OTHER
STATES SCATTERED AROUND.
- [COWBOY] LIKE WYOMING.
- MILWAUKEE.
- AND LONG ISLAND SOUND.
- RIGHT!
[ROY] DOWN TEXAS WAY,
A RIVER FLOWS.
WHERE IT COMES FROM,
NOBODY KNOWS.
WHERE IT'S GOING,
DON'T NO ONE CARE.
JUST DOGGONE GLAD
IT'S A-LEAVIN' THERE.
[COWBOY] THAT THERE IS
THE PECOS RIVER.
- SHE WAS PURE ALKALI.
- JUST NATURALLY MEAN WATER.
WHY, THE BUZZARDS
WON'T EVEN TOUCH IT.
[WHISTLING]
INTO THIS FERTILE GARDEN SPOT,
ONCE THERE COME A PRAIRIE CART.
THERE WAS MA AND PA
AND 16 BRATS.
- FOUR HOUND DOGS.
- AND A COUPLE OF CATS.
ALL GOING WEST,
LOOKING FOR ELBOW ROOM.
SURE COULD USE
SOME OF THE SAME.
CROSSING THE PECOS RIVERBED,
SOMETHING FELL OUT
AND LIT ON HIS HEAD.
FOLKS DIDN'T EVEN KNOW
HE WAS GONE.
OL' WAGON JUST KEPT
ROLLING ALONG.
- YEP, IT WAS BILL.
- POOR LITTLE CRITTER.
HOMELESS AS A POKER CHIP.
♪ ALONG CAME NIGHT
AND A PRAIRIE MOON ♪
♪ OL' MA COYOTE
HURRYIN' HOME ♪
♪ SHE WAS DUE FOR A SHOCK
AT HER JOURNEY'S END ♪
♪ FOR THE STORK HAD
DELIVERED A DIVIDEND ♪
- PLUM UNUSUAL!
- YEP!
IT NEVER HAPPENED BEFORE.
PROBABLY ONE OF THEM
NEWFANGLED MODELS.
♪ BILL LOOKED UP
AND THEN HE GRINNED ♪
SHUCKS.
♪ MA'S OL' HEART JUST
PLUM CAVED IN ♪
♪ BILL SEEN RIGHT OFF
THAT HE NEEDN'T FEAR ♪
♪ HE'D STAKED HIMSELF
A CLAIM RIGHT HERE ♪
HEADED STRAIGHT FOR
THAT OL' CHUCKWAGON.
YEP, OL' BILL WAS HUNGRIER
THAN A WOODPECKER
WITH A HEADACHE.
SO, WHAT FOLLOWED
AS A NATURAL FACT,
THAT BILL GROWED UP
WITH THAT COYOTE PACK.
HE SOON BECOME
THE MAIN TOP HAND.
IN A WAY THEY ALL
COULD UNDERSTAND.
BUT LITTLE BILL,
HE COULDN'T REST,
TILL HE PROVED HIMSELF
THE A-1 BEST.
SO, HE STUDIED
THE OTHER VARMINTS TOO.
THEN, SHOWED 'EM ALL
A TRICK OR TWO.
OUTLOPED THE ANTELOPE.
OUTJUMPED THE JACK RABBIT.
YEAH, BILL EVEN
OUTHISSED THE RATTLESNAKE.
♪ THEN ONE DAY ♪
♪ CROSS THE BURNIN' SAND ♪
♪ A STRANGER COME ♪
♪ TO THE PECOS LAND ♪
♪ THE USUAL COMMITTEE
WAS THERE TODAY ♪
♪ TO WELCOME THEIR GUEST ♪
♪ IN THE USUAL WAY ♪
NOW, 50 TO 1 WEREN'T
NO FAIR FIGHT.
BUT 1 PLUS BILL
MADE IT JUST ABOUT RIGHT.
WELL, IT WAS THE BEGINNING
OF A BEAUTIFUL FRIENDSHIP.
FROM THAT TIME ON,
THEM TWO STUCK TOGETHER.
LIKE WARTS ON A TOAD,
LIKE BIRDS OF A FEATHER.
WHEN BILL GROWED UP,
IT WAS NATURAL OF COURSE,
HE'D CHOOSE A CAREER TO
SUIT HIM AND HIS HORSE.
YEP, BILL BECOME
A ROOTIN', TOOTIN' COWBOY!
♪ PECOS BILL WAS
QUITE A COWBOY ♪
♪ DOWN IN TEXAS ♪
♪ AND THE WESTERN SUPERMAN
TO SAY THE LEAST ♪
♪ HE WAS THE ROUGHEST,
TOUGHEST CRITTER ♪
♪ NEVER KNOWN TO BE A QUITTER ♪
♪ 'CAUSE HE NEVER HAD
NO FEAR OF MAN OR BEAST ♪
♪ SO, YIPPEE
YI-YAY YI-YAY ♪
♪ YIPPEE YI-YO ♪
♪ FOR THE TOUGHEST CRITTER
WEST OF THE ALAMO ♪
♪ ONCE HE ROPED A RAGING
CYCLONE
OUT OF NOWHERE ♪
♪ THEN HE STRADDLED IT AND
SETTLED DOWN WITH EASE ♪
♪ AND WHILE THAT CYCLONE
BUCKED AND FLITTED ♪
♪ PECOS ROLLED A SMOKE AND LIT IT ♪
♪ AND HE TAMED THAT
ORNERY WIND DOWN
TO A BREEZE ♪
♪ SO, YIPPEE YI-YAY ♪
♪ YIPPEE YI-YO ♪
[YODELING]
♪ ONCE THERE WAS A DROUGHT
THAT SPREAD ALL OVER TEXAS ♪
♪ SO, TO SUNNY CALIFORNY
HE DID GO ♪
♪ AND THOUGH THE GAG
IS KINDA CORNY ♪
♪ HE BROUGHT RAIN
FROM CALIFORNY ♪
♪ THAT'S THE WAY WE GOT
THE GULF OF MEXICO ♪
♪ SO, YIPPEE
YI-YAY YI-YAY ♪
♪ YIPPEE YI-YO ♪
♪ FOR THE TOUGHEST CRITTER
WEST OF THE ALAMO ♪
[MOOING]
♪ ONCE A BAND OF RUSTLERS
STOLE A HERD OF CATTLE ♪
♪ BUT THEY DIDN'T KNOW ♪
♪ THE HERD THEY STOLE
WAS BILL'S ♪
♪ AND WHEN HE CAUGHT
THEM CROOKED VILLAINS ♪
♪ PECOS KNOCKED OUT
ALL THEIR FILLINGS ♪
♪ THAT'S THE REASON WHY
THERE'S GOLD ♪
♪ IN THEM THAR HILLS ♪
♪ SO, YIPPEE
YI-YAY YI-YAY ♪
♪ YIPPEE YI-YO ♪
♪ FOR THE TOUGHEST CRITTER
WEST OF THE ALAMO ♪
♪ OHHH ♪
♪ PECOS LOST HIS WAY ♪
♪ WHILE TRAVELING
ON THE DESERT ♪
♪ WATER ♪
♪ IT WAS 90 MILES
ACROSS THE BURNIN' SAND ♪
♪ WATER ♪
♪ HE KNEW HE'D NEVER
REACH THE BORDER ♪
♪ WATER ♪
♪ IF HE DIDN'T
GET SOME WATER ♪
♪ WATER ♪
♪ SO, HE GOT A STICK
AND DUG THE RIO GRANDE ♪
[COWBOYS SINGING]
♪ WHILE A TRIBE
OF PAINTED INDIANS ♪
♪ DID A WAR DANCE ♪
♪ PECOS STARTED SHOOTIN' UP
THEIR LITTLE GAME ♪
♪ HE GAVE THEM REDSKINS
SUCH A SHAKEUP ♪
♪ THAT THEY JUMPED
OUT OF THEIR MAKE-UP ♪
♪ THAT'S THE WAY
THE PAINTED DESERT ♪
♪ GOT ITS NAME ♪
♪ SO, YIPPEE YI-YAY ♪
♪ FOR THE TOUGHEST CRITTER
WEST OF THE ALAMO ♪
♪ WHILE RECLININ' ON A CLOUD
HIGH OVER TEXAS ♪
♪ WITH HIS GUN HE MADE
THE STARS EVAPORATE ♪
♪ THEN PECOS SAW
THE STARS DECLININ' ♪
♪ SO HE LEFT ONE
BRIGHTLY SHININ' ♪
♪ AS THE EMBLEM OF
THE LONE STAR TEXAS STATE ♪
♪ SO, YIPPEE
YI-YAY YI-YAY ♪
♪ YIPPEE YI-YO ♪
YEP, THEM WAS HAPPY DAYS
FOR BILL AND THAT HORSE.
LOOKED LIKE NOTHING
COULD EVER COME BETWEEN 'EM.
THEN IT HAPPENED.
NOW BILL WAS HAPPY
THAT FATEFUL DAY.
KILLIN' SOME TIME
IN HIS CAREFREE WAY.
INVENTIN' A ONE-MAN RODEO.
A-BUTTIN' HEADS
WITH THE BUFFALO.
POOR BILL.
HAPPY AS A HOG
IN A TURNIP PATCH.
AND THEN...
OL' MAN FATE STARTED DEALIN'
FROM THE BOTTOM OF THE DECK.
FOR DOWN THE STREAM
COME SLUE FOOT SUE,
WITH ALL HER CHARMS
REVEALED TO VIEW.
LOOKED LIKE SOMETHING
FROM OUT IN A DREAM.
FIRST FEMALE WOMAN
BILL'S EVER SEEN.
[WOLF WHISTLE]
- SHE WAS STRANGE.
- UNUSUAL!
YEAH, BUT POWERFUL
STIMULATING.
LIKE A SLUG OF RYE
ON AN EMPTY STOMACH.
GAVE HIM A RIGHT
PECULIAR FEELING,
SET HIS SENSES
PLUM TO REELIN'.
WITH A POUNDING SOUND
INSIDE HIS EARS,
LIKE THE GALLOPING HOOVES
OF A THOUSAND STEERS.
INSIDE HIS CHEST WAS
A-SEETHIN' AND A-CHURNIN',
HIS BLOOD WAS BOILIN',
HIS BRAIN WAS BURNIN'.
BURNIN' WITH A FIRE
THAT COULD ONLY BE COOLED...
♪ IN THE BECKONING DEPTHS ♪
♪ OF TWO BLUE LIMPID POOLS ♪
YEP. L'AMOUR HAD COME
TO PECOS BILL.
[WHOOPING]
WIDOW MAKER WAS PLUM PUZZLED.
LOOKED LIKE TROUBLE TO HIM.
AND HE SURE WAS RIGHT.
BILL WAS BUSY INVENTING
COURTIN', WESTERN-STYLE.
♪ HE ARRANGED FOR THE MOON ♪
♪ TO RISE JUST RIGHT ♪
♪ AND FLOOD THE LAND ♪
♪ WITH A SILVERY LIGHT ♪
♪ ORDERED THE STARS
IN HEAVEN ABOVE ♪
♪ TO FORM A TOKEN
OF UNDYING LOVE ♪
♪ THEN CROSS THE SKY ♪
♪ IN WORDS OF FIRE ♪
♪ BILL TOLD SWEET SUE ♪
♪ OF HIS OWN HEART'S DESIRE ♪
♪ SWEET SUE ♪
♪ I LOVE YOU ♪
SO, SUE NAMED THE WEDDING DAY.
BUT THERE WAS A PRICE
BILL HAD TO PAY.
SUE WANTED A BUSTLE,
THE FINEST OF COURSE.
SHE AIMED TO BE WEDDED
RIDING BILL'S HORSE.
SUE GOT HER BUSTLE
AND IT SURE WAS CLASSY.
PUT THE FINISHING TOUCH
ON THAT SWEET GAL'S CHASSIS.
THAT THERE HAPPY
BLUSHING BRIDE
WAS BUSTING OUT
WITH GIRLISH PRIDE.
[WOLF WHISTLES]
BUT BILL HAD PROMISED SUE
A RIDE ON WIDOW MAKER TOO.
WOULD THAT HORSE BE WILLING
TO LET SUE RIDE?
HERE COMES THE ANSWER,
FIT TO BE TIED.
WIDOW MAKER WAS
PLUM IRRITATED.
BUT THAT DIDN'T
BOTHER SUE NONE.
SHE WALKED RIGHT UP
TO THAT CRITTER'S SIDE.
HER GENTLE HAND TOUCHED
HIS BRISTLIN' HIDE.
HER FOOT FOUND THE STIRRUP
WITH THE FLICK OF HER BUSTLE.
SUE WAS ABOARD,
AND SAT FOR THE TUSSLE.
THE PROCEEDINGS
BEGUN TO COMMENCE.
FORTHWITH.
NO DOUBT ABOUT IT,
THAT THERE SUE
WAS A REGULAR FEMALE BUCKAROO.
AND THEN, THAT BUSTLE.
UNDERNEATH THEM
FRILLS AND FLOUNCES,
SUE WAS DEVELOPIN'
PLENTY OF BOUNCES.
GOT TO BE MORE THAN
THAT GAL COULD HANDLE.
AND SUE TOOK OFF
LIKE A ROMAN CANDLE.
THAT DEVILISH CONTRAPTION
OF STEEL AND WIRE,
KEPT BOUNCING THAT POOR GAL
HIGHER AND HIGHER.
AND SOON IT WAS PLAIN
TO THE MULTITUDE
THAT SUE WAS
GAININ' ALTITUDE.
SURE LOOKED LIKE
SHE WAS A GONER.
BUT NO, HERE COME
A RAY OF HOPE.
LOOK, IT WERE BILL
AND HIS TRUSTY ROPE.
HE DONE SOON PUT
A STOP TO THIS.
SHUCKS, BILL WAS
NEVER KNOWED TO MISS.
BILL WAS CALM, CONFIDENT.
HE BUILT HIS LOOP
WITH CARELESS EASE.
HE JUDGED HIS DISTANCE,
TESTED THE BREEZE.
THEN A WHIRL AND A TWIRL
AND A TWIST OF THE WRIST.
HE LET HER GO.
BUT THE CHAMPION MISSED.
HOW IT COME TO HAPPEN,
NOBODY COULD EVER FIGURE OUT.
SHE WAS OFF AGAIN
ON HER HEAVENLY FLIGHT.
UP, UP SHE WENT
CLEAN OUT OF SIGHT.
TILL FAR INTO SPACE
THIS UNFORTUNATE MAID
FINALLY COME TO THE MOON.
AND THAT'S WHERE SHE STAYED.
IN THE STATE OF TEXAS, USA,
LIFE STILL GOES ON
IN THE SAME OLD WAY.
AND THE PECOS RIVER
STILL FLOWS ON,
BUT THE GREATEST COWBOY
ON EARTH IS GONE.
YEAH, BILL WENT BACK
TO THE COYOTES.
BUT HE NEVER FORGOT SUE.
AND EVERY NIGHT
WHEN THE MOON ROSE HIGH,
HE'D LIFT HIS VOICE
IN MOURNFUL CRY.
BEWAILING THE FATE
OF HIS LADY FAIR,
HIS LONG LOST LOVE
IN THE SKY UP THERE.
SO PAINFUL WAS
HIS GRIEF TO SEE,
THE VARMINTS JOINED IN
OUT OF SYMPATHY.
AND THAT'S HOW COME,
TO THIS VERY DAY,
COYOTES HOWL AT THE MOON
THAT WAY.
♪ MOVE ALONG ♪
♪ MOVE ALONG, BLUE SHADOWS ♪
♪ MOVE ALONG, MOVE ALONG,
MOVE ALONG ♪
♪ SOON THE DAWN WILL COME ♪
♪ AND YOU'LL BE ON YOUR WAY ♪
♪ ON YOUR WAY ♪
♪ BUT UNTIL THE DARKNESS ♪
♪ SHEDS ITS VEIL ♪
♪ THERE'LL BE BLUE SHADOWS ♪
♪ ON THE TRAIL ♪
♪ SHADOWS ON THE TRAIL ♪
[HOWLING]
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/76dc8
Help other users to choose the best subtitles