Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
We're under attack!
Light the signal!
- Light the fire now!
- Light the signal!
Now all of China
knows you're here.
Perfect.
Your Majesty, the Huns have
crossed our Northern border.
Impossible.
No one can get through the Great Wall.
Shan-Yu is leading them.
We'll set up defenses
around your palace immediately.
No. Send your troops
to protect my people. Chi Fu.
- Yes, Your Highness?
- Deliver conscription notices throughout all the provinces.
Call up reserves and
as many new recruits as possible.
Forgive me, Your Majesty,
but I believe my troops can stop him.
I won't take
any chances, General.
A single grain of rice
can tip the scale.
One man may be the difference
between victory and defeat.
"Quiet and demure.
Graceful. Polite.
Delicate.
Refined. Poised.
Punctual. "
Ai-yah!
Little Brother!
Little Brother. Lit-
Ah! There you are.
- Who's the smartest doggy in
the world? Come on, smart boy.
Can you help me with my chores today?
Honorable ancestors,
please help Mulan
impress the Matchmaker today.
Please.
Please help her.
Father, I brought your-
Whoa!
- Mulan.
- I brought a spare.
- Remember, the doctor said three cups of tea in the morning...
- Mulan.
- and three at night.
Mulan, you should already be in town.
We are counting on you-
To uphold the family honor.
Don't worry, Father.
I won't let you down.
- Wish me luck.
- Hurry!
I'm going to...
pray some more.
Fa Li, is your daughter
here yet?
The Matchmaker
is not a patient woman.
Of all days to be late-I should have
prayed to the ancestors for luck.
How lucky can they be?
They're dead.
- Besides, I've got
all the luck we'll need.
This is your chance
to prove yourself.
Grandma, no!
Yep, this cricket's
a lucky one!
I'm here.
What? But Mama,
I had to-
None of your excuses.
Now, let's get you cleaned up.
This is what you give me
to work with
Well, honey
I've seen worse
We're gonna turn this sow's ear
- into a silk purse
- It's freezing.
It would have been warm
if you were here on time.
We'll have you
washed and dried
Primped and polished
till you glow with pride
Trust my recipe
for instant bride
You'll bring honor
to us all
- Mulan, what's this?
- Uh, notes,
in case
I forget something.
Hold this.
We'll need more luck than I thought.
Wait and see
when we're through
Boys will gladly
go to war for you
- With good fortune
- And a great hairdo
You'll bring honor to us all
A girl can bring
her family
Great honor in one way
- By striking a good match
- Huh?
- And this could be the day
- Ha, ha, ha!
Men want girls
with good taste
- Calm. - Obedient.
- Who work fast-paced
- With good breeding
- And a tiny waist
You'll bring honor to us all
We all must serve
our Emperor
Who guards us
from the Huns
The men by bearing arms
A girl by bearing sons
When we're through you can't fail
Like a lotus blossom
soft and pale
How could any fellow
say no sale
You'll bring honor
to us all
There.
You're ready.
Not yet.
An apple for serenity.
A pendant for balance.
Beads of jade
For beauty
You must proudly
Show it
Now add a cricket
Just for luck
And even you
can't blow it
Ancestors
Hear my plea
Help me not to make
a fool of me
And to not uproot
my family tree
Keep my father
standing tall
Scarier than
the undertaker
We are meeting
our Matchmaker
Destiny Guard our girls
And our future
as it fast unfurls
Please look kindly
on these cultured pearls
Each a perfect
porcelain doll
- Please bring honor to us
Please bring honor
to us all
"Fa Mulan. "
- Present.
- Speaking without permission.
- Oops.
- Who spit in her bean curd?
Huh. Hmm.
Mmm. Too skinny.
Hmph! Not good
for bearing sons.
Recite the
final admonition.
Mm-hmm.
Well?
Fulfill your duties
calmly and... respectfully.
Um, reflect before you snack-
Act! This shall bring you
honor and glory.
Hmm. This way.
Now, pour the tea.
To please
your future in-laws,
you must demonstrate
a sense of dignity...
and refinement.
You must also be poised.
- Um, pardon me.
- And silent!
Ahhh.
Could I just take that back?
One moment.
Why, you clumsy-
Whoo! Whoo! Aaah! Whoo! Aaah!
I think it's going well, don't you?
Put it out! Put it out!
Put it out!
You are a disgrace!
You may look like a bride,
but you will never
bring your family honor!
Look at me
I will never pass
For a perfect bride
Or a perfect daughter
Can it be
I'm not meant
to play this part
Now I see
That if I were truly
to be myself
I would break
my family's heart
Who is that girl I see
Staring straight
Back at me
Why is my reflection
Someone I don't know
Somehow I cannot hide
Who I am
Though I've tried
When will
my reflection show
Who I am inside
When will
my reflection show
Who I am
Inside
My, my.
What beautiful blossoms
we have this year.
But, look,
this one's late.
But I'll bet that
when it blooms,
it will be
the most beautiful of all.
What is it?
Mulan.
Stay inside.
Citizens, I bring
a proclamation...
from the Imperial City.
The Huns have invaded China.
By order of the Emperor,
one man from every family
must serve in the Imperial Army.
The Hsiao family.
The Yi family.
I will serve the Emperor
in my father's place.
- The Fa family.
- No!
I am ready to serve
the Emperor.
- Father, you can't go.
- Mulan!
- Please, sir, my father has
already fought bravely- - Silence!
You would do well to teach your daughter
to hold her tongue in a man's presence.
Mulan, you dishonor me.
Report tomorrow
to the Wu Zhong camp.
Yes, sir.
The Chu family!
The Wen family!
The Chang family!
- You shouldn't have to go!
- Mulan-
There are plenty of young men
to fight for China.
It is an honor to protect
my country and my family.
So, you'll die for honor.
I will die
doing what's right.
- But if you- - I know my place!
It is time you learned yours.
Mulan is gone!
What?
It can't be.
Mulan!
No.
You must go after her.
She could be killed.
If I reveal her,
she will be.
Ancestors, hear our prayer.
Watch over Mulan.
Mushu, awaken.
I live!
So tell me what mortal needs
my protection, Great Ancestor.
- You just say the word and I'm there.
- Mushu-
And let me say somethin'. Anybody's who's
foolish enough to threaten our family,
vengeance will be mine!
Mushu!
These are
the family guardians.
- They-
- Protect the family.
And you, O Demoted One?
I... ring the gong.
That's right.
Now, wake up the ancestors.
One family reunion comin' right up.
Okay, people, people, look alive.
Let's go. Come on. Get up.
Let's move it. Rise and shine. Y'all way
past the beauty sleep thing, trust me.
I knew it. I knew it. That Mulan
was a troublemaker from the start!
Don't look at me. She gets it
from your side of the family.
She's just trying
to help her father.
But if she's discovered,
Fa Zhou will be forever shamed.
Dishonor will come to the family.
Traditional values will disintegrate.
Not to mention,
they'll lose the farm.
My children never caused such trouble.
They all became acupuncturists.
- Well, we can't all be acupuncturists.
- No!
Your great-granddaughter
had to be a cross-dresser!
- Let a guardian bring her back.
- Yes, awaken the most cunning.
No. The swiftest.
- No. Send the wisest.
- Silence!
We must send
the most powerful of all.
Okay, okay,
I get the drift. I'll go.
Oh, y'all don't think I can do it.
Watch this here.
Aha! Jump back.
I'm pretty hot, huh?
Don't make me have to singe
nobody to prove no point.
You had your chance
to protect the Fa family.
Your misguidance led
Fa Deng to disaster.
- Yeah, thanks a lot.
- And your point is?
The point is we will be sending
a real dragon to retrieve Mulan.
What-What-
I'm a real dragon!
You are not worthy of this spot.
Now, awaken the Great Stone Dragon.
So you'll get back to me
on the job thing?
Just one chance,
is that too much to ask?
I mean, it's not like
it'd kill ya.
Yo, Rocky, wake up!
Ya gotta go fetch Mulan!
Come on, boy!
Go get her! Go on!
Come on.
Hello?
Hel-lo!
Hello!
Uh-oh.
Uh, Stony?
Stony? Oh, man,
they're gonna kill me.
Great Stone Dragon,
have you awakened?
Uh, uh, uh, uh-
Yes, I just woke up.
I'm-I'm the Great
Stone Dragon. Good morning.
I will go forth
and fetch Mulan.
Did-Did I mention that
I was the Great Stone Dragon?
Go! The fate
of the Fa family...
rests in your claws.
Don't even worry about it.
I will not lose face.
My elbow!
I know I twisted somethin'.
That's just great.
Now what?
I'm doomed, and all 'cause Miss Man decides
to take her little drag show on the road.
Go get her? What's the matter
with you? After this Great Stone,
Humpty Dumpty mess, I'd have to bring her
home with a medal to get back in the temple.
Wait a minute. That's it!
I make Mulan a war hero, and they'll be
begging me to come back to work.
That's the master plan.
Ah, you done it now, man.
- Hey, what makes you
think you're comin'?
You're lucky?
Do I look like a sucker to you?
What you mean, a loser? How 'bout I pop one
of your antennas off, throw it across the yard?
Then who's the loser, me or you?
Imperial scouts.
Shan-Yu.
Nice work, gentlemen.
You found the Hun Army.
The Emperor
will stop you.
Stop me?
He invited me.
- By building his wall,
he challenged my strength.
Well, I'm here
to play his game.
Go! Tell your Emperor
to send his strongest armies.
I'm ready.
How many men does it take
to deliver a message?
One.
Okay, okay,
how about this?
Excuse me.
Where do I sign in?
Ha, I see you have a sword.
I have one too.
They're very manly
and... tough.
I'm working on it!
Oh, who am I fooling?
It's going to take a miracle
to get me into the army.
Did I hear someone ask
for a miracle?
- Let me hear you say "aaah"!
- Aaah!
- That's close enough.
- A ghost.
Get ready, Mulan.
Your serpentine salvation is at hand!
For I have been sent
by your ancestors...
to guide you through
your masquerade.
Come on. If you're gonna stay,
you're gonna work.
So heed my word! 'Cause if
the army finds out you're a girl,
the penalty is death!
- Who are you?
- Who am I? Who am I?
I am the guardian
of lost souls.
I am the powerful,
the pleasurable,
the indestructible Mushu.
Oh. Ha, ha.
Pretty hot, huh?
Uh, my ancestors sent
a little lizard to help me?
Hey, dragon, dragon,
not lizard.
I don't do that tongue thing.
You're, um-
Intimidating?
Awe inspiring?
- Tiny.
- Of course. I'm travel size for your convenience.
If I was my real size,
your cow here would die of fright.
Down, Bessie. My powers are
beyond your mortal imagination.
For instance, my eyes can see
straight through your armor. Oooh!
All right, that's it! Dishonor!
Dishonor on your whole family.
Make a note of this. Dishonor on you,
dishonor on your cow, dis-
Stop. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm just nervous.
I've never done this before.
Then you're gonna have to trust me.
And don't you slap me no more.
We clear on that?
All right.
Okeydokey. Let's get this show
on the road! Cri-Kee, get the bags.
Let's move it, heifer.
Okay, this is it.
Time to show 'em your man walk.
Shoulders back, chest high,
feet apart, head up and strut.
Two, three-Break it down.
Hup, two, three. And work it!
- Beautiful, isn't he?
- They're disgusting.
No, they're men. Now, you gonna have to
act just like them, so pay attention.
Look. This tattoo
will protect me from harm.
Hmm.
- I hope you can
get your money back.
I don't think
I can do this.
It's all attitude.
Be tough, like this guy here.
What are you lookin' at?
Punch him.
It's how men say hello.
Oh, Yao,
you've made a friend.
Good. Now slap him on the behind.
They like that.
Whoa-ho-ho!
I'm gonna hit you so hard,
it'll make your ancestors dizzy.
Yao, relax and chant with me.
Feel better?
Yeah. Ahh, you ain't
worth my time.
- Chicken boy.
- Chicken boy?
Say that to my face,
ya limp noodle!
Oh. Sorry, Ling.
Hey!
Whoa! You're dead!
Oh, there he goes!
Hey, guys.
The Huns have struck here,
here and here.
I will take the main troops
up to the Tung Shao Pass...
and stop Shan-Yu
before he destroys this village.
Excellent strategy, sir.
I do love surprises.
You will stay and train
the new recruits.
When Chi Fu believes
you're ready,
you will join us, Captain.
Captain?
This is an enormous
responsibility, General.
Perhaps a soldier
with more experience.
Number one in his class, extensive
knowledge of training techniques,
and impressive
military lineage.
I believe Li Shang will do
an excellent job.
Oh, I will. I won't let you down.
This is-I mean-
- Yes, sir.
- Very good then.
We'll toast China's victory
at the Imperial City.
I'll expect a full report
in three weeks.
And I won't leave
anything out.
Captain Li Shang.
Hmm.
Leader of China's
finest troops.
No. The greatest troops of all time.
Most impressive.
Good luck, Captain. Hyah!
Good luck, Father.
Day one.
Soldiers!
He started it!
I don't need anyone
causing trouble in my camp.
Sorry. Uh-
I mean, uh, sorry you had to see that.
But you know how it is when you get those
manly urges and you just gotta kill somethin',
fix things, cook outdoors-
What's your name?
Your commanding officer
just asked you a question.
Uh, I've got a name.
Ha! And it's a boy's name too.
- Ling. How 'bout Ling?
- His name is Ling.
I didn't ask for his name.
I asked for yours!
- Try, uh, uh, ah, Chu.
- Ah Chu.
- Ah Chu?
- Gesundheit. Ha, ha. I kill myself.
- Mushu.
- Mushu?
- No.
- Then what is it?
- Ping was my best friend growin' up.
- It's Ping.
- Ping?
- Of course, Ping did steal my-
Yes, my name is Ping.
Let me see your
conscription notice.
- Fa Zhou? The Fa Zhou?
- I didn't know Fa Zhou had a son.
Um, he doesn't talk about me much.
I can see why.
That boy's an absolute lunatic.
Okay, gentlemen,
thanks to your new friend, Ping,
you'll spend tonight picking up
every single grain of rice.
And tomorrow, the real work begins.
You know, we have to work
on your people skills.
- All right! Rise and shine,
Sleeping Beauty.
Come on. Hup, hup, hup.
- Get your clothes on. Get ready.
Got breakfast for ya.
Look, you get porridge,
and it's happy to see you.
Hey, get outta there!
You gonna make people sick.
- Am I late?
- No time to talk. Now remember, it's your first day of training,
so listen to your teacher and no
fightin', play nice with the other kids,
unless one of the other kids wanna fight,
then you have to kick the other kid's butt.
- But I don't wanna kick the other kid's butt.
- Don't talk with your mouth full.
Now let's see your war face.
Oh, I think my bunny slippers just ran
for cover. Come on! Scare me, girl.
Yeah, that's my tough lookin' warrior.
That's what I'm talkin' about.
Now, get out there and make me proud.
- What do you mean, the troops just left?
- They what?
Wait!
You forgot your sword.
My little baby,
off to destroy people.
Order. People, order.
- I'd like a pan-fried noodle.
- Oh, oh! Sweet and pungent shrimp.
- Moo goo gai pan.
- That's not funny.
Looks like our new friend
slept in this morning.
Hello, Ping.
Are ya hungry?
Yeah, 'cause I owe you
a knuckle sandwich.
Soldiers!
You will assemble swiftly
and silently every morning.
Anyone who acts otherwise...
will answer to me.
Eeew. Tough guy.
Yao.
Thank you for volunteering.
Retrieve the arrow.
I'll get that arrow,
pretty boy,
and I'll do it
with my shirt on.
One moment. You seem
to be missing something.
This represents discipline,
and this
represents strength.
You need both
to reach the arrow.
We've got a long way to go.
Let's get down to business
To defeat the Huns
- Hoo-ah!
- Did they send me daughters
When I asked for sons
You're the saddest bunch
I ever met
But you can bet
before we're through
Mister, I'll make a man
Out of you
Tranquil as a forest
But on fire within
Once you find your center
You are sure to win
You're a spineless, pale
pathetic lot
And you haven't got a clue
Somehow I'll
make a man
Out of you
I'm never gonna
catch my breath
Say good-bye
to those who knew me
Boy, was I a fool
in school for cutting gym
This guy's got 'em scared to death
Hope he doesn't see right through me
Now I really wish
that I knew how to swim
- Be a man
- We must be swift as a coursing river
- With all the force of a great typhoon
- Be a man
- With all the strength of a raging fire
Mysterious as the dark side
of the moon
Time is racing toward us
Till the Huns arrive
Heed my every order
And you might survive
You're unsuited for
the rage of war
So pack up, go home
You're through
How could I
make a man
Out of you
- Be a man
- We must be swift as a coursing river
- With all the force of a great typhoon
- Be a man
- With all the strength of a raging fire
Mysterious as the dark side
Of the moon
- Be a man
- We must be swift as a coursing river
- With all the force of a great typhoon
- Be a man With all the
strength of a raging fire
Mysterious as the dark side
Of the moon
Hoo-ah!
What do you see?
Black pine,
from the high mountains.
White horse hair.
Imperial stallions.
Sulphur, from cannons.
This doll came from a village
in the Tung Shao Pass...
where the Imperial Army
is waiting for us.
We can avoid them easily.
No.
The quickest way to the Emperor
is through that pass.
And besides, the little girl
will be missing her doll.
We should return it to her.
No, this is not a good
idea. What if somebody sees you?
Just because I look like a man
doesn't mean I have to smell like one.
So a couple of guys don't rinse
out their socks. Picky, picky, picky.
Well, myself, I kind of
like that corn chip smell.
Ahhh.
Okay, all right. That's enough. Get
out before you get all pruny and stuff.
Mushu, if you're so worried,
go stand watch.
Yeah, yeah. "Stand watch, Mushu,
while I blow our secret
with my stupid girlie habits. "
Pfft! Hygiene!
Me first! Me first!
We're doomed! There are a couple of
things I know they're bound to notice!
Whooo-ooo!
Hey, Ping!
Oh, hi, guys.
I didn't know you were here.
I was just washing. So now I'm clean,
and I'm gonna go. Bye-bye.
Come back here.
I know we were jerks to you before,
so let's start over.
Hi. I'm Ling.
- And I'm Chien-Po.
- Hello, Chien-Po.
And I am Yao!
King of the rock!
And there's nothin'
you girls can do about it.
Oh, yeah?
Well, I think Ping and I can take you.
- I really don't wanna take him anywhere.
- Ping, we have to fight!
No, we don't. Uh, we, uh, could just
close our eyes and swim around.
Come on. Don't be
such a gir-
Ouch! Something bit me!
What a nasty flavor.
Snake!
Oooh, snake! Snake!
Snake! Snake!
Some king of the rock.
Aaah!
Boy, that was close.
No. That was vile.
You owe me big.
I never want to see
a naked man again.
- Hey, don't look at me.
I ain't bitin' no more butts.
You think your troops
are ready to fight?
Ha! They would not last a minute
against the Huns!
- They completed their training.
- Those boys...
are no more fit to be soldiers
than you are to be captain.
Once the General
reads my report,
your troops
will never see battle.
Oh, no, you don't! I've worked
too hard to get Mulan into this war.
This guy's messin'
with my plan.
We're not finished!
Be careful, Captain.
The General may be your father,
but I am
the Emperor's counsel.
And, oh, by the way, I got that job on my own.
You're dismissed.
Hey. I'll hold him
and you punch.
Or not.
For what it's worth,
I think you're a great captain.
- I saw that.
- What?
You like him, don't you?
- No!
- Yeah, all right. Yeah, sure. Go to your tent!
I think it's time we took
this war into our own hands.
Let me see what you got. "From General Li.
Dear Son, we're waiting for Huns at the Pass.
It would mean a lot
if you'd come and back us up. "
That's great, except you forgot,
"And since we're out of potpourri,
perhaps you wouldn't mind
bringing up some. "
Hello! This is the army! Make it sound
more urgent! Know what I'm talkin' about?
That's better.
Much better. Let's go.
Khanny, baby.
Hey, we need a ride.
Insubordinate ruffians!
You men owe me a new pair of slippers!
And I do not squeal like a girl.
Urgent news
from the General.
What's the matter? You've never seen
a black and white before?
Who are you?
Excuse me? I think
the question is, who are you?
We're in a war, man!
There's no time for stupid questions!
I should have your hat for that.
Snatch it right off your head.
But I'm feeling gracious today,
so carry on before I report you.
Captain, urgent news from the General!
We're needed at the front.
- Pack your bags, Cri-Kee.
We're movin' out.
For a long time we've been marching
off to battle
- In our thundering herd
we feel a lot like cattle
Like a pounding beat
our aching feet
Aren't easy to ignore
Hey!
Think of instead
A girl
worth fighting for
- Huh?
- That's what I said.
A girl
worth fighting for
I want her paler
than the moon
With eyes that shine
like stars
My girl will marvel at my strength
Adore my battle scars
I couldn't care less what she'll wear
or what she looks like
It all depends on
what she cooks like
Beef, pork, chicken
Mmm
Bet the local girls thought you
were quite the charmer
And I'll bet the ladies
love a man in armor
You can guess what
we have missed the most
Since we went off to war
- What do we want
- A girl worth fighting for
My girl will think
I have no faults
That I'm a major find
Uh, how 'bout a girl
who's got a brain
- Who always speaks her mind
- Nah!
My manly ways
and turn of phrase
Are sure to thrill her
He thinks he's
such a lady killer
I've a girl back home
who's unlike any other
Yeah, the only girl
who'd love him is his mother
But when we come home in victory
They'll line up
at the door
- What do we want
- A girl worth fighting for
- Wish that I had
A girl worth fighting
Search for survivors.
I don't understand.
My father should've been here.
Captain!
The General.
I'm sorry.
The Huns are moving quickly.
We'll make better time to the Imperial
City through the Tung Shao Pass.
We're the only hope
for the Emperor now.
Move out!
What happened?
- Um- - You just gave away
our position! Now we're-
Get out of range!
Aah!
Save the cannons!
Come on! Empty it! Empty it!
Hey!
Oh, sure.
Save the horse.
Fire!
Hold the last cannon.
Prepare to fight.
If we die, we die with honor.
Yao, aim the cannon
at Shan-Yu.
- Hey!
- Ping! Come back!
Ping!
Stop!
All right. You might want to
light that right about now.
Quickly. Quickly!
Come on!
We gotta help!
- You missed!
How could you miss?
It was three feet
in front of you!
Whoa-ho-ho!
Mulan!
Mulan?
No.
Mulan!
Man, you are
one lucky bug.
Shang!
- Do you see them?
- Yes.
Perfect.
Now we'll pull them to safe-ty.
Hey, Mulan!
I found the lucky cricket!
We need help.
Ooh, nice. Very nice.
You can sit by me.
- Aah!
- We're gonna die!
We're gonna die!
We are definitely gonna die.
No way we survive this.
Death is coming!
I let them slip through my fingers.
Aah!
Pull!
Whoa!
Huh?
I knew we could do it.
You the man!
Well, sort of.
Step back, guys.
Give him some air.
Ping?
You are the craziest man I've ever met.
And for that,
I owe you my life.
From now on,
you have my trust.
Let's hear it for Ping!
The bravest of us all!
- You're king of the mountain!
- Yes, yes, yes!
Ping! What's wrong?
He's wounded!
Get help!
Ping, hold on.
Hold on.
I can explain.
So it's true!
Shang!
I knew there was
something wrong with you.
A woman!
Treacherous snake!
My name is Mulan.
I did it
to save my father.
- High treason!
- I didn't mean for it to go this far.
Ultimate dishonor!
It was the only way.
Please believe me.
Captain?
Restrain him!
- No!
- You know the law.
A life for a life.
My debt is repaid.
- Move out!
- But you can't just-
I said, "Move out. "
I was this close.
This close
to impressin' the ancestors,
gettin' the top shelf,
an entourage.
Man. All my fine work.
Pfft.
Hi.
I should never have left home.
Hey, come on.
You went to save your father's life.
Who knew you'd end up shamin' him
and disgracing your ancestors...
and losin' all your friends?
You know, you just gotta-
You gotta learn to let these things go.
Maybe I didn't go
for my father.
Maybe what I really wanted was to prove
I could do things right...
so when I looked in the mirror,
I'd see someone worthwhile.
But I was wrong.
I see nothing.
Now, that's just 'cause
this needs a little spit, that's all.
Let me shine this up for ya.
I can see you. Look at you.
You look so pretty.
The truth is,
we're both frauds.
Your ancestors never sent me.
They don't even like me.
I mean, you risked your life
to help people you love.
I risked your life
to help myself.
At least
you had good intentions.
What? What do you mean,
"You're not lucky"?
You lied to me?
And what are you, a sheep?
I'll have to face my father
sooner or later.
Let's go home.
Yeah. This ain't
gonna be pretty.
But don't you worry, okay?
Things will work out.
We started this thing together,
and that's how we'll finish it.
I promise.
Uh, home is that way.
- I have to do something.
- Did you see those Huns?
They popped out of the snow...
like daisies!
Are we in this together
or not?
Well, let's go kick
some Hunny buns!
Yee-haw!
Make way for the heroes
of China.
- Shang!
- Mulan?
The Huns are alive!
They're in the city!
You don't belong here,
Mulan. Go home.
Shang, I saw them in the mountains.
You have to believe me.
Why should I?
Why else would I come back?
You said you'd trust Ping.
Why is Mulan any different?
Keep your eyes open.
I know they're here. Yah!
Now, where are you going?
To find someone
who will believe me.
My children,
heaven smiles down...
upon the Middle Kingdom.
China will sleep
safely tonight...
thanks to
our brave warriors.
Sir, the Emperor's in danger.
But the Huns are here.
Please, you have to help.
- No one will listen.
- Huh? Oh, I'm sorry. Did you say something?
- Mushu.
- Hey, you're a girl again, remember?
Your Majesty, I present to you
the sword of Shan-Yu.
I know what this means
to you, Captain Li.
Your father would have been
very proud.
- No!
- Come on!
They'll never reach
the Emperor in time.
Hey, guys!
I've got an idea.
Be a man
- We must be swift as a coursing river
- Be a man
- With all the force of a great typhoon
With all the strength
of a raging fire
Mysterious as the dark side
of the moon
Boo.
Guard the door.
Your walls and armies have fallen,
and now it's your turn.
Bow to me.
Okay. Any questions?
Does this dress
make me look fat?
Ow!
Who's there?
- Concubines.
- Ugly concubines.
Oh, he's so cute!
Ohh.
- Now, that's what I call
Mongolian barbecue.
Shang, go!
I tire of your arrogance,
old man. Bow to me!
No matter how the wind howls,
the mountain cannot bow to it.
Then you will kneel
in pieces!
Chien-Po, get the Emperor!
Sorry, Your Majesty.
No!
Come on!
No.
You!
- You took away my victory!
- No!
I did.
The soldier
from the mountains.
So what's the plan?
- Um-
- You don't have a plan?
Hey, I'm making this up
as I... go.
- Mushu!
- Way ahead of you, sister.
Come on, Cri-Kee.
- Citizens, I need firepower.
- Who are you?
Your worst nightmare.
- On the roof!
- Look!
It looks like
you're out of ideas.
Not quite.
Ready, Mushu?
I am ready, baby!
Light me.
Huh?
Get off the roof, get off the roof,
get off the roof.
You are a lucky bug.
That was a deliberate attempt
on my life!
Where is she?
Now she's done it.
What a mess!
Stand aside!
That creature's
not worth protecting.
- She's a hero.
- 'Tis a woman.
- She'll never be worth anything.
- Listen, you pompous-
That is enough.
Your Majesty,
I can explain.
I've heard a great deal
about you, Fa Mulan.
You stole your father's armor,
ran away from home,
impersonated a soldier,
deceived
your commanding officer,
dishonored the Chinese Army,
destroyed my palace...
and...
you have saved us all.
Ah! Ooh!
My little baby is all grown up and-
and savin' China.
You have a tissue?
Chi Fu?
- Your Excellency?
- See to it that this woman is made a member of my council.
Member? What?
But... there are
no council positions open,
Your Majesty.
Very well.
You can have his job.
What? I-Oh.
With all due respect,
Your Excellency,
I think I've been away
from home long enough.
Then... take this,
so your family will know
what you have done for me.
And this,
so the world will know
what you have done for China.
Is she allowed
to do that?
Um... you-
you fight good.
Ohh. Thank you.
Khan, let's go home.
The flower that blooms
in adversity...
is the most rare
and beautiful of all.
- Sir?
- You don't meet a girl like that every dynasty.
Mulan!
Father, I brought you
the sword of Shan-Yu.
And the crest
of the Emperor.
They're gifts
to honor the Fa family.
The greatest gift and honor
is having you for a daughter.
I've missed you so.
I've missed you too, Baba.
Great.
She brings home a sword. If you ask me,
she should've brought home a man.
Excuse me.
Does Fa Mulan live here?
Thank you.
Whoo! Sign me up
for the next war.
Honorable Fa Zhou, I-
Mulan!
Uh... you forgot
your helmet.
W- Well, actually,
it's your helmet, isn't it?
- I mean-
- Would you like to stay for dinner?
Would you like
to stay forever?
Dinner would be great.
Come on.
Who did a good job?
Come on. Tell me.
Oh, all right!
You can be a guardian again.
Aah-ha!
Hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Take it, Cri-Kee!
You know, she gets it
from my side of the family.
Call out for egg rolls!
Guardians.
- Oh.
- Thanks, Mushu.
Mushu!
Whenever you feel your world
is crashin' down on you
Whenever you don't know
where to turn or what to do
Don't look too far
You've got the guide
To find your way
Let your heart decide
Be true to your heart
You must be true to your heart
. That's when
the heavens will part
. And show the world
what you believe in
. Open your eyes
Your heart can tell you no lies
. And when you're true
to your heart
. Then you've got all you need
to make it through
. Be true to your heart
. Ah, someone you know
is on your side
. Can set you free
. I can do that for you
if you believe in me
. Why second guess
. What feels so right
. Just trust your heart
. And you'll see the light
. Be true to your heart
You must be true to your heart
. That's when
the heavens will part
. And show the world
what you believe in
. Open your eyes
Your heart can tell you no lies
And when you're true
to your heart
Then you've got all you need
to make it through
You know it's true
It'll see you through
Yeah, yeah, yeah
- You've got to be true
- Baby
Be true to your heart
You must be true to your heart
That's when
the heavens will part
And show the world
what you believe in
Open your eyes
Your heart will tell you no lies
And when you're true
to your heart
Then you've got all you need
to make it through
Be true
To your heart
Sing the chorus, boys.
When things
are gettin' crazy
And you don't know
where to start
Keep on believin', baby
Just be true
to your heart
- When all the world around you
- Yeah
It seems to fall apart
Keep on believin', baby
- Just be true to your heart
- True to your heart
Just be true
To your heart
Got to be true
Be true
True, true, true, true
To your heart
Look at me
You may think you see
who I really am
But you'll never know me
Every day
It's as if
I play a part
Now I see
If I wear a mask
I can fool the world
But I cannot fool my heart
Who is that girl I see
Staring straight
back at me
When will my reflection show
Who I am inside
I am now
In a world where
I have to hide my heart
And what I believe in
But somehow
I will show the world
What's inside my heart
And be loved for who I am
Who is that girl I see
Staring straight back at me
Why is my reflection
Someone I don't know
Must I pretend that I'm
Someone else for all time
When will my reflection show
Who I am
Inside, there's a heart
That must be free
To fly
And I burn
With a need to know
The reason why
Why must we all conceal
What we think
How we feel
Must there be a secret me
I'm forced to hide
I won't pretend that I'm
Someone else for all time
When will my reflection show
Who I am inside
Oh, hey, yeah
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today