Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
When you wish upon a star
Makes no difference
who you are
Anything your heart desires
Will come to you
If your heart
is in your dream
No request is too extreme
When you wish upon a star
As dreamers do
Fate is kind
She brings to those who love
The sweet fulfilment of
Their secret longing
Like a bolt out of the blue
Fate steps in
And sees you through
When you wish
Upon a star
Your dreams
Come true
Pretty, huh?
I'll bet a lot of you folks
don't believe that.
About a wish coming true,
do you?
Well, I didn't either.
Of course, I'm just
a cricket singing my way
from hearth to hearth...
but... let me tell you
what made me change my mind.
One night, a long time--
Pardon me. Wait 'til I, I fix
this thing here. There.
One night, a long time ago,
my travels took me to
a quaint little village.
It was a beautiful night.
The stars were shining
like diamonds...
high above the roofs
of that sleepy old town.
Pretty as a picture.
As I wandered along
the crooked streets,
there wasn't a soul to be seen.
The only sign of life
was a lighted window...
in the shop of a wood-carver
named, uh, Geppetto.
So, I hopped over.
And looked in.
It was a shame to see a nice
cheerful fire like that
going to waste.
So what do I do?
I go in.
I looked around.
Of course, being in
a strange place like that,
I didn't know what to expect.
A cricket can't be
too careful, you know.
Soon as I saw there was no one
about, I made myself at home.
As I stood there warming my...
myself, I took a look around.
Well, sir, you never saw
such a place.
The most fantastic clocks
you ever laid your eyes on.
And all carved out of wood.
And cute little music boxes,
each one a work of art.
Shelf after shelf of toys and--
And then something else
caught my eye.
A puppet!
You know, one of those
marionette things,
all strings and joints.
Cute little fella.
Ding, ding! Going up?
Good piece of wood too.
Well, now.
It won't take much longer.
Just a little more paint
and he's all finished.
I think he'll be all right.
Don't you, Figaro?
Um, huh, uh, beg pardon.
See? That makes
a big difference.
Very good.
Very, very goo--
Well, you can't
please everybody.
Now, I have just
the name for you.
Pinocchio!
Do you like it, Figaro?
No? You do, don't you, Cleo?
Well, we'll leave it
to little Woodenhead.
Do you like it?
That settles it!
Pinocchio it is!
Come on, now,
we'll try you out.
Music, Professor!
Hey! Ow, ow, ow, ouch!
Ta-Ta-Take it easy there!
Oh, break it up, will you?
Lot of downbeats in there.
Little Woodenhead
Go play your part
Bring a littlejoy
to every heart
Little do you know
and yet it's true
That I'm mighty proud of you
Little wooden feet
and best of all
Little wooden seat
in case you fall
Oh-ho! How graceful!
My little Woodenhead
Cleo, meet Pinocchio.
Say, "How do you do?"
Say hello to Figaro.
Oops! Oh-ho-ho!
Up to mischief already.
You see what happens?
Boo!
Up we go! Ahh.
You're a cute little fellow.
And that smile?
You know, I--
You rascal.Jealous, huh?
You know, Pinocchio, I think
Figaro is jealous of you.
Oh-ho, don't worry, Figaro.
I sti-- Uh-oh.
I wonder what time it is.
It's getting late.
Come, now. We go to bed.
Good night, Pinocchio.
Little funny face.
Good night, Cleo,
my little water baby.
Figaro.
You say good night too.
Go on.
Now go to sleep,
my little mermaid.
Good night.
This is my idea of comfort.
Solid comfort.
Look at him, Figaro.
He almost looks alive.
Wouldn't it be nice
if he was a real boy?
Oh, well.
Come on. We go to sleep.
Ah, Figaro.
I forgot to open the window.
Oh, Figaro! Look, look!
The wishing star!
Star light, star bright,
first star I see tonight;
I wish I may, I wish I might...
have the wish I make tonight.
Figaro, you know what
I wish?
I wish that
my little Pinocchio...
might be a real boy.
Wouldn't that be nice?
Just think!
A real boy!
A very lovely thought.
But not at all practical.
A real...
boy.
Quiet!
After all, enough's enough.
Now what's up?
Hey, what's going on here?
As I live and breathe, a fairy!
Mm-mmm.
Good Geppetto, you have given
so much happiness to others.
You deserve to have
your wish come true.
Little puppet made of pine,
wake.
The gift of life is thine.
Whew! What they can't do
these days!
I can move!
I can talk!
I can walk!
- Yes, Pinocchio,
I've given you life.
- Why?
Because tonight, Geppetto
wished for a real boy.
- Am I a real boy?
- No, Pinocchio.
To make Geppetto's wish come
true will be entirely up to you.
- Up to me?
- Prove yourself brave,
truthful and unselfish,
- and someday you
will be a real boy.
- A real boy!
That won't be easy.
You must learn to choose
between right and wrong.
Right and wrong?
But how will I know?
- How will he know.
- Your conscience will tell you.
- What are conscience?
- What are conscience!
I'll tell ya!
A conscience is that
still small voice that
people won't listen to.
- That's just the trouble
with the world today, you see?
- Are you my conscience?
Who, me?
Would you like to be
Pinocchio's conscience?
Well, w-- uh, I--
I-- uh-- Ohh. Uh-huh.
Very well. What is your name?
Uh, oh, uh, Cricket's the name.
Jiminy Cricket.
- Kneel, Mr Cricket.
- Huh?
No tricks now.
I dub you
Pinocchio's conscience,
lord high keeper of the
knowledge of right and wrong,
counsellor in moments
of temptation...
and guide along the straight
and narrow path.
Arise, Sir Jiminy Cricket.
Well! Oh-ho-ho!
My, my!
Mmm. Say, that's pretty swell.
Gee... thanks.
But, uh, don't I get
a badge or something?
- Well, we'll see.
- You mean maybe I will?
- I shouldn't wonder.
- Make it a gold one?
Maybe.
Now, remember, Pinocchio,
be a good boy.
And always let your conscience
be your guide.
Goodbye, milady.
Goodbye!
Not bad, says I.
Oh, yeah. Ho-ho-ho.
Almost forgot about you.
Well, Pinoke.
-Maybe you and I had better have
a little heart-to-heart talk.
-Why?
- Well, you want to be
a real boy, don't you?
- Uh-huh!
All right. Sit down, son.
- Now, you see, the world
is full of temptations.
- Temptations?
Yep. Temptations.
They're the wrong things
that seem right at the time.
But, uh, even though the right
things may seem wrong sometimes,
uh, sometimes the,
the wrong things may be
right at the wrong time.
Or, uh, visa versa.
- Understand?
- Uh-uh.
But I'm gonna do right!
Atta boy, Pinoke.
And I'm gonna help you.
And anytime you need me,
you know, just whistle...
like this.
Like this?
No, no. Try it again, Pinoke.
No, son. Now, listen.
That's it! Come on, now,
let's sing it!
When you get in trouble and
you don't know right from wrong
Give a little whistle
When you meet temptation
and the urge is very strong
Give a little whistle
Not just a little squeak
Pucker up and blow
-And if your whistle's
weak, yell
-Jiminy Cricket?
Right!
Take the straight and narrow
path and if you start to slide
Give a little whistle
And always let your
conscience be your guide
Take the straight and narrow
path and if you start to slide
Give a little whistle
Yoo-hoo!
Whoo-hoo!
And always let your
conscience be your guide
Look out, Pinoke!
- Who is there?
- It's me!
Oh, it's me.
Shh, Figaro.
There's somebody in here.
Shh!
Be careful now, Figaro.
He might spring out
on us at any time.
He's in here somewhere.
Here I am!
Oh... Pinocchio.
How did you get down here?
- I fell down.
- Oh, you did.
- Ohh! You're talking!
- Uh-huh.
- N-N-N-No!
- Yes, and I can move too!
No, n-no, you, you can't--
I-I'm dreaming in my sleep.
W-W-Wake me up. Wake me up!
Now we see who is dreaming.
Go on. Say something.
Gee, you're funny.
Do it again!
- You do talk!
- Yes, the Blue Fairy came--
- The Blue Fairy?
- Uh-huh.
- And I got a conscience.
- A conscience!
And someday I'm gonna
be a real boy!
A real boy! It is my wish.
It's come true!
Figaro, look!
He-- He's alive. He can talk!
- Let's say hello to Figaro.
- Hello to Figaro.
Ohh. Oh, Cleo, I almost forgot.
Look! It's Pinocchio!
She's my little water baby.
Isn't she cute?
Yeah, cute.
This calls for a celebration.
Music!
You start one, Pinocchio.
Oh, boy. A party!
Mind if I cut in?
How about sitting out
the next one, babe, huh?
Whoop! Hey, whoa, let me out!
Let me out!
Come, Cleo, join the party.
Dance!
Ooh, nice.
Gathering toys
For my little boy
- Look! Pretty!
- Oh!
Help!
Wh-Wh-Wh-Where's the bucket?
Help! Water! Where's the water?
Here it is! I got it!
Here's water! Here's some water!
Help! Where's water?
That was close.
Maybe we'd better go to bed...
before something else happens.
Little man, you've had
a busy night.
Now, close your eyes
and go to sleep.
Why?
Oh, everybody has to sleep.
Figaro goes to sleep...
and Cleo...
and, and besides, tomorrow
you've got to go to school.
Why?
Oh, to learn things and--
and get smart.
Why?
- Because.
- Oh.
- Oh, look, Father! Look!
- Now, wait. Stand still now.
- What are those?
- Huh? Oh, those.
They are your schoolmates.
Girls and boys.
Uh, no-now, get in--
- Real boys?
- Yes.
But hurry now.
Oh, oh, wai-wai-wait! Wait. Eh--
Here's an apple for your
teacher. Now turn around...
and let me look you over.
Huh? Oh, yeah, yeah.
Here. Run along now.
Fig, wait!
Come back here, Figaro.
School is not for you.
- Goodbye, Father.
- Goodbye, son. Hurry back.
Ah, Gideon, listen.
The merry laughter...
of little innocent children
wending their way to school.
Thirsty little minds rushing
to the fountain of knowledge.
School, a noble institution.
What would this stupid
world be without--
Well, well, well!
Stromboli! So that old rascal's
back in town, eh?
Remember, Gideon, the time
I tied strings on you...
and passed you off
as a puppet?
We nearly put one over on
that old gypsy that time.
A little wooden boy.
Now, who'd have-- A wooden boy!
Look, Giddy, look! It's amazing.
A live puppet without strings.
A thing like that ought to be
worth a fortune to someone.
Now let me see.
That's it! Stromboli!
Why, that fat old faker
would give his-- Listen.
If we play our cards right,
we'll be on Easy Street,
or my name isn't Honest John.
Quick, we'll head him off.
Shh! Now's our--
No, no, stupid.
Don't be crude.
Let me handle this.
Here he comes.
Ah, yes, Skinny, as I was saying
to the Duchess only yesterday--
Oh! Oh, how clumsy of me.
Oh, my, my, my, my.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
Oh, I do hope
you're not injured.
- I'm all right.
- Oh, splendid.
Well, well, hmm.
Quite a scholar, I see.
Look, Giddy, a man of letters.
- Here's your book.
- I'm going to school.
School. Ah, yes.
Then you haven't heard of
the easy road to success.
- Uh-uh.
- No?
I'm speaking, my boy,
of the theatre.
Here's your apple.
Bright lights, music,
applause, fame!
- Fame?
- Yes!
And with that personality,
that profile, that physique,
why, he's a natural born
actor, eh, Giddy?
- But I'm going--
- Straight to the top.
Why, I can see your name
in lights, lights six feet high.
- Uh-- What is your name?
- Pinocchio.
Pinocchio! P-I-N-- Eh, uh--
U-O-- Eh, P-I-- Eh--
We're wasting precious time.
Come, on to the theatre.
Hi diddle dee dee
An actor's life for me
A high silk hat
and a silver cane
A watch of gold
with a diamond chain
Hi diddle dee day
An actor's life is gay
It's great to be a celebrity
An actor's life for me
Hi diddle dee dum
An actor's life is fun
Whew! Fine conscience
I turned out to be.
Late the first day. Oh, well,
he can't get in much trouble...
between here and school.
- Oh, boy, a parade!
- An actor's life for me
Hi diddle dee dee
An actor's life for me
- Huh?
- A waxed mustache
and a beaver coat
- A pony cart and a billy goat
Hi diddle dee dum
- Why, it's-- it's Pinoke. Hey!
- An actor's life is fun
- Where you goin'?
You wear your hair
in a pompadour
- You ride around in
a coach and four
- Wait!
- You stop and buy out
a candy store
- Halt!
- An actor's life for me
- Hold on there! Pinoke!
Hi diddle dee dee
An actor's life for me
- With clothes that come
from the finest shops
- Hey, Pinoke.
- And lots of peanuts
and soda pop, Hi--
- Hey!
- What was that?
- Oh, it's Jiminy!
- Whatcha doin' up there?
- Huh? Who?
Wha-Wha-Wha-What? Wha--
Who? Jiminy? Up where?
Shh!
Why, my boy, huh, you
must be seeing things.
Oh, no, that's
my conscience. He--
Now, now, now.Just calm down.
Why, there's nothing
up there to be afraid of.
Oh!
Psst! Pinoke!
Psst! Pinoke! Over here.
- Over here.
- Oh,Jiminy!
- I'm going to be an actor.
- All right, son,
take it easy now.
Remember what I said
about temptation?
- Uh-huh.
- Well, that's him.
Oh, no,Jiminy,
that's Mr Honest John.
Honest John?
Get this thing off.
Get me outta here!
Get me out of here!
Oh!
All right then, here's
what we'll tell 'em:
You can't go to the theatre,
say "Thank you just the same,"
you're sorry but you've
got to go to school.
- Mm-hmm.
- Pinocchio!
Oh, Pinocchio! Whoo-hoo!
Here they come, Pinoke.
Now, you tell 'em.
Whoo-hoo! Oh, little boy!
Ah, there you are!
Now, where were we? Ah,
yes, on to the theatre!
Goodbye,Jiminy! Goodbye!
- Hi diddle dee dee
An actor's life for me
- Goodbye? Huh? Goodbye?
- Hey, Pinoke, you can't--
- A high silk hat
and a silver cane
- A watch of gold
with a diamond chain
- There he goes.
- Oh, what'll I do? I'll
run and tell his father.
- Hi diddle dee day
- An actor's life is gay
- No, that'd be snitching.
I'll go after him myself.
Ladies and gentlemen,
to conclude the performance
of this great show,
Stromboli the Master Showman--
that's a-me--
and by special permission
of the management--
that's a-me too--
is presenting to you
something...
you will absolutely
refuse to believe.
Well, looks like a sell-out.
Introducing
the only marionette...
who can sing and dance...
absolutely without
the aids of strings.
I hope so.
The one and only Pinocchio!
Hmph! What a build-up.
I got no strings
to hold me dow--
Go ahead, make a fool
of yourself.
Then maybe you'll listen
to your conscience.
Cute kid.
I got no strings
to hold me down
To make me fret
or make me frown
I had strings
but now I'm free
There are no strings on me
Heigh-ho the merry-o
That's the only way to be
I want the world to know
Nothing ever worries me
I got no strings
so I can have fun
- What I told you, huh?
- I'm not tied up with anyone
They got strings
but you can see
There are no strings on me
You have no strings
Your arms is free
To love me by the Zuider Zee
Ja, ja, ja
If you would woo
I'd bust my strings for you
You got no strings
Comme ci, comme ca
Your savoir faire
is ooo-la-la
I've got strings
but entre nous
I'd cut my strings for you
Down where the Volga flows
There's a Russian rendezvous
Where me and Ivan go
But I'd rather go with you, hey
Hey!
- Hey!
There are no strings on me
Hmm, they like him.
He's a success.
Gosh, maybe I was wrong.
Well, guess he won't
need me any more.
What does an actor want
with a conscience anyway?
What could have happened to him?
Where could he be at this hour?
I'd better go out again
and look for him.
And remember, nobody eats
a bite until I find him.
I got-a no strings
but I got-a the brain
I buy a new suit
and I swing-a the chain
I eat-a the best
and I drink-a champagne
I got-a no strings on me
- Bravo, Pinocchio!
- They like me.
Hmm, two hundred.
- You are sensational!
- Ya mean I'm good?
Ahh, three hundred.
You are colossal!
Does that mean I'm an actor?
Sure. I will push you
in the public's eye.
Your face, she will be
on everybody's tongue.
- Will she?
- Ye-- Uh, huh?
What's this?
Ahhh!
For you, my little Pinocchio.
For me? Gee, thanks!
I'll run right home
and tell my father.
Home?
Oh, sure. Going home
to your father.
Oh, that is very comical!
- Ya mean it's funny?
- Oh, sure! Yes.
- I'll be back in the morning.
- Be back in the morning.
Going home.
There, this will be your home,
where I can find you always.
- No, no, no!
- Yes, yes, yes!
To me you are belonging.
We will tour the world.
Paris. London.
Monte Carlo.
"Constantinopolee."
- No, no!
- Yes!
We start tonight!
Hmm.
You will make lots of money...
for me!
And when you are
growing too old,
you will make good... firewood!
Let me outta here! I gotta
get out! You can't keep me!
Quiet! Shut-a up...
before I knock-a you silly!
Good night,
my little wooden gold mine.
No! No, wait! Let me out!
I'll tell my father!
Giddyap! Get along there.
Jiminy! Oh,Jiminy!
Oh,Jiminy, where are ya?
Jiminy Cricket!
Well, there he goes,
sitting in the lap of luxury,
the world at his feet.
Oh, well, I can always
say I knew him when.
I'll just go out
of his life quietly.
I would like to
wish him luck though.
Sure! Why not?
Pinocchio.
Pinocchio. It's me, your
old friend Jiminy, remember?
Jiminy! Gee, I'm glad to see ya!
Pinocchio! What's happened?
- What did he do to ya?
- Oh, he was mad.
He said he was gonna push
my face in everybody's eye.
- Yeah?
- A-A-And just 'cause
I'm a gold brick,
he-he's gonna chop me
into firewood!
Oh, is that so?
Now, don't you worry, son.
I'll have you out of here
in no time at all.
Why, this is-- eh, just as
easy as... rollin' off a--
Kind of rusty.
- Needs a little oil!
- Needs a little oil, needs
a little oil, a little oil.
That's what I said.
Must be one of the old models.
You mean, you can't open it?
Yeah.
Looks pretty hopeless.
It'll take a miracle
to get us out of here.
Gee.
Pinocchio!
Giddyap!
Pinocch--
A fine conscience
I turned out to be.
I should've listened
to you,Jiminy.
No, it was my fault. I shouldn't
have walked out on you.
Guess I'll never see
my father again.
Oh, buck up, son.
It could be worse.
Be cheerful, like me.
Aw, take it easy, son.
Come on, blow.
Thatta boy.
Oh, well, it stopped
raining anyway.
Hey, that star again!
Uh, the lady, the-- Ooh!
- The fairy!
- What'll she say?
- What'll I tell her?
- You might tell her the truth.
- Why, Pinocchio.
- Uh, eh, hello!
Sir Jiminy!
Well! Uh, this is a--
a pleasant surprise. Ha-ha.
Pinocchio, why didn't
you go to school?
- School? Well, I-- um--
- Uh-- Go ahead, tell her.
I was going to school
'til I met somebody.
- Met somebody?
- Yeah. Uh, two big monsters...
with big green eyes!
- Why, I-- I--
- Monsters?
- Weren't you afraid?
- No, ma'am. But they
tied me in a big sack.
You don't say!
And where was Sir Jiminy?
Eh, huh? Oh,Jiminy?
Hey, psst! Leave me outta this.
They put him in a little sack.
- No!
- Yeah!
- How did you escape?
- I didn't.
They chopped me into firewood.
Oh! Oh, look!
My nose! What's happened?
Perhaps you haven't been
telling the truth, Pinocchio.
- "Perhaps"?
- Oh, but I have,
every single word.
Oh, please help me!
I'm awful sorry.
You see, Pinocchio, a lie
keeps growing and growing...
until it's as plain as
the nose on your face.
She's right, Pinoke.
You better come clean.
I'll never lie again.
Honest, I won't.
Please, Your Honor--
Uh, uh, I mean, Miss Fairy.
Give him another chance,
for my sake.
Will ya, huh?
I'll forgive you this once.
But remember,
a boy who won't be good might
just as well be made of wood.
- We'll be good, won't we?
Very well. But this is
the last time I can help you.
Gee, look,Jiminy, my nose!
Hey, we're free!
Come on, Pinoke!
I buy a new suit
and I swing-a the cane
I eat-a the fish
and I drink-a champagne
I got no strings on me
- Toodle-ooo, Stromboli.
- Goodbye, Mr Strombo--
Shh! Quiet! Let's get outta here
before something else happens.
Hi diddle dee dee
An actor's life for me
A high silk hat
and a silver cane
A watch of gold
with a diamond chain
Hi diddle dee day
An actor's life is gay
It's great to be a celebrity
An actor's life for me
And the dummy fell for it...
hook, line and sinker!
And he still thinks
we're his friends.
And did Stromboli pay...
plenty!
That shows you how low
Honest John will stoop,
eh, Giddy?
Now, uh, coachman,
what's your proposition?
Well,
how would you blokes like
to make some real money?
Well! And who do we
have to, eh--
No, no! Nothing like that.
You see--
I'm collecting
stupid little boys.
- Stupid little boys?
- You know,
the disobedient ones what
play hookey from school.
- Oh!
- And you see...
Yes.
Oh!
And I takes 'em
to Pleasure Island!
Ah, Pleasure Island.
Pleasure Island?
But the law, suppose they--
No, no. There is no risk.
They never come back...
as boys!
Now, I've got a coach load
leaving at midnight.
We'll meet at the crossroads,
and no double-crossing!
- No, sir.
- Scout around,
and any good prospects
you find, bring 'em to me.
- Yes, Chief.
- I'll pay you well.
- I got plenty of gold.
- Yes, yes.
No, sir, nothing can stop me
now. I'll make good this time.
- You'd better.
- I will. I'm going to school.
- That's the stuff, Pinoke.
- I'd rather be smart
than be an actor.
Now you're talkin'! Come on,
slowpoke, I'll race ya home.
Well, well, Pinocchio.
What's your rush?
I gotta beat Jiminy home.
Oh, hello.
Well, how is the great actor?
I don't wanna be an actor.
Stromboli was terrible.
- He was?
- Yeah, he locked me
in a bird cage--
- He did?
- Uh-huh, but I
learned my lesson.
- I'm going--
- Oh, you poor, poor boy.
You must be a nervous wreck.
That's it, you are
a nervous wreck!
We must diagnose
this case at once.
Quick, Doctor, your notebook.
Bless my soul.
Hmmm, mm-hmm.
My, my.Just as I thought.
A slight touch of
monetary complications...
with bucolic
semi-lunar contraptions
of the flying trapezes.
Mm-hmm. Say "hippopotamus."
- Hi-ho-hotamus.
- I knew it!
Compound transmission of the
pandemonium with percussion...
and spasmodic
frantic disintegration.
- Close your eyes.
What do you see?
- Nothing.
-Open them. Now what do you see?
-Spots.
Aha! Now that heart.
Ooh, my goodness!
A palpitating syncopation
of the killer diller...
with the wicky wacky
stomping of the floy joy.
Quick, Doctor, that report.
Ooh, this makes it
perfectly clear!
My boy, you are allergic.
- Allergic?
- Yes, and there is
only one cure.
- A vacation on Pleasure Island!
- Pleasure Island?
Yes, that happy land
of carefree boys...
where every day is a holiday!
- But I can't go. I--
- Why, of course you can go.
I'm giving you my ticket.
- Here.
- Thanks! But I'm--
Oh, tut-tut-tut-tut, I insist.
Your health comes first.
Come, the coach
departs at midnight.
Hi diddle dee dee
It's Pleasure Isle for me
Where every day is a holiday
And kids have nothing
to do but play
- Pinoke!
- Hi diddle dee dee
Oh, Pinoke? Now where
do you suppose he-- Huh?
Pinocchio! Hey! Come back!
Giddyap!
Well,
here we go again.
My name's Lampwick.
What's yours?
Pinocchio.
- Ever been to Pleasure Island?
- Uh-uh, but Mr Honest John
gave me--
Me neither, but they say it's a
swell joint. No school, no cops.
You can tear the joint apart,
and nobody says a word.
- Honest John gave me--
- Loaf around, plenty to eat,
plenty to drink.
- And it's all free!
- Honest John--
Boy, that's the place.
I can hardly wait!
Right here, boys!
Right here!
Get your cake, pie,
dill pickles and ice cream.
Eat all you can. Be a glutton.
Stuff yourselves.
It's all free, boys.
It's all free. Hurry,
hurry, hurry, hurry!
The Rough House.
It's the roughest, toughest
joint ya ever seen.
-Come in and pick a fight, boys.
-Oh, boy, a scrap!
Come on, let's go in and
poke somebody in the nose.
- Why?
- Ah, just for the fun of it.
Okay, Lampy.
Tobacco Road. Tobacco Road.
Get your cigars, cigarettes
and chewin' tobacco.
Come in and smoke
your heads off. There's
nobody here to stop you.
Pinocchio!
Pinocchio! There's somethin'...
phoney about all this.
I gotta get him outta here.
Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry,
hurry! See the model home.
It's open for destruction,
and it's all yours, boys!
It's all yours!
What'd I tell ya?
Ain't this a swell joint?
Yeah! Bein' bad's
a lot of fun, ain't it?
Yeah, uh-huh. Get a load of
that stained-glass window.
All right now,
hop to it, you blokes.
Come on, come on! Shut the doors
and lock 'em tight.
Now get below and get
them crates ready.
Give a bad boy enough rope
and he'll soon make
a jackass of himself.
Pinocchio!
Pinocchio?
Where is everybody?
The place is like a graveyard.
I don't like the looks of this.
Pinocchio!
Hey, where are you?
Where d'you suppose all
the kids went to, Lampwick?
Ah, they're around here
somewheres. What do you care?
- You're having
a good time, ain't ya?
- Uh-huh, I sure am.
Oh, boy! This is the life,
huh, Pinoky?
Yeah!
It sure is!
Ah, you smoke
like me grandmother!
Come on, take
a big drag like this.
Okay, Lampy.
Some fun, huh, kid?
Okay, Slats, your shot.
What's the matter, Slats?
Losin' your grip?
Pinocchio! So this is
where I find you.
How do you ever expect
to be a real boy?
Look at yourself. Smoking,
playing pool! Ow! You are coming
right home with me this minute!
Hey! Who's the beetle?
Let go! Put me down!
Let me out of here. Let me out!
He's my conscience. He tells me
what's right and wrong.
What? You mean to tell me you
take orders from a grasshopper?
Grasshopper? Look here,
you, you impudent young pup!
It wouldn't hurt you to take
orders from your grasshopp--
Uh, uh... your conscience,
if you have one.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, sure.
Screwball in the corner pocket.
Why-- Why-- Ya young hoodlum!
I'll-- I'll knock
your block off!
Why, I'll take you apart
and put you back together.
Oh, don't hurt him,Jiminy.
He's my best friend.
Why, I'll-- Your best friend?
And what am I?
Just your conscience.
Okay, that settles it.
- B-But,Jiminy--
- You buttered your bread,
now sleep in it.
Ha-ha-ha! Go on, laugh.
Make a jackass out of yourself.
I'm through! This is the end.
But,Jiminy, Lampwick says
a guy only lives once.
Lampwick. Hmph!
Come on, come on. Let him go.
Lampwick. Hmph, Lampwick!
Burns me up. After all
I tried to do for him.
Who's his conscience anyway? Me
or that, that hoodlum Lampwick?
I've had enough of this.
I'm taking the next boat
out of here.
Open up that door! Open up!
I wanna go home!
Come on, you blokes!
Keep 'em moving!
Lively there now.
We haven't got all night.
Where'd all the
donkeys come from?
Come on, come on.
Let's have another.
And what's your name?
Okay, you'll do! In you go!
You boys'll bring a nice price.
All right, next!
- And what might your name be?
- Alexander.
Hmm, so you can talk.
Ye-Yes, sir. I wanna
go home to my mama!
Take him back!
He can still talk!
Please, please! I don't
wanna be a donkey!
- Let me outta here!
- Quiet!
You boys have had your fun.
Now pay for it.
"Boys"? So that's what--
Pinocchio!
Ha! To hear that beetle talk,
you'd think somethin'
was going to happen to us.
Conscience. Nah, phooey!
Where does he get that stuff?
"How do you ever expect
to be a real boy?"
What's he think
I look like, a jackass?
You sure do!
Hey, you laugh like a donkey.
Did that come out of me?
Oh!
Huh?
What the-- What's goin' on?
I've been double-crossed!
Help! Help!
Somebody, help!
I've been framed! Help!
Please, you gotta help me.
Oh, be a pal.
Call that beetle! Call anybody!
Mama! Mama!
- Oh, what's happened?
- I hope I'm not too late.
What'll I do?
- Pinocchio!
-Jiminy! Oh,Jiminy, help!
Wait, Pinoke! The kids,
the boys, they're all donkeys!
Oh, you too!
Come on, quick!
Before you get any worse.
This way, Pinoke.
It's the only way out.
Hurry up... before they see us.
You gotta jump!
Jiminy.
Jiminy, y-you all right?
Sure. I thought
we'd never make it.
Certainly feels good
to be back on...
dry land.
Come on, let's get home.
Father! Father, I'm home!
- We're home, Mr Geppetto!
Home again!
- It's me, Pinocchio!
- I'm home to stay!
- Here he is, Mr Geppetto.
Home at last.
Hey, maybe he's asleep.
Father! Father, it's me!
Pinoke, come here.
Look. He ain't here.
He-- He's gone.
Yeah, and Figaro.
And Cleo too.
Maybe something awful
happened to him.
Don't worry, son,
he probably hasn't gone far.
Hey.
- It's a message.
- What's it say?
- It's about your father.
- Where is he?
Why, uh, uh,
it says here he, uh,
he went looking for you and, uh,
uh, he was swallowed by a whale.
- Swallowed by a whale?
- Yeah, uh-huh. A-- A whale?
- A whale named Monstro.
- Oh, he's--
Uh, but, but wait. He's alive.
- Alive? Where?
- Why, uh, uh,
inside the whale at the,
at the bottom of the sea.
- Bottom of the sea?
- Uh-huh. Uh-- Hey!
Where you going?
I'm going to find him.
But, Pinoke, are you crazy?
Don't you realize,
uh, he's in a whale?
I've gotta go to him.
Hey, Pinoke, wait!
Listen here, son.
But this Monstro,
I've heard of him.
He's a whale of a whale.
Why, he swallows
whole ships alive.
Tie it good and tight now.
And besides, it's dangerous.
- Why, I--
- Bye,Jiminy.
Goodbye? I may be live bait
down there, but I'm with ya.
Come on, let's go.
Look out below!
Gangway, down there.
Gee, what a big place.
- Come on,Jiminy.
- All right.
Soon as I take on some ballast.
One side, sister.
Well, so long.
Hmm, put it in the wrong end.
Hmph, no more privacy
than a goldfish.
Ooh, chilly.
Father!
Hey, Pinoke, wait for me!
Father! Huh, he ain't my father.
Uh, Mr Geppetto!
Hey, what the--
Hey, le-- let go!
Run along, ya little... squirt.
What's the matter? Can't
a fellow, uh-- I was only--
We were only looking
for Monstro.
That got 'em.
Father!
Oh, hello.
Oh! Uh...
can you tell me where
we can find Monstro?
Gee, they're scared.
Uh, pardon me, pearl,
are you acquainted
with Monstro the whale?
Whoa, hold it there.
- Hmph!
- Father!
One side there, son.
Come on, boys, break it up.
Break it up now.
Hey, what the--
Whoa, quit, quit,
quit shoving now.
Quit, whoa. Don't crowd.
Now take it easy.
Take it easy there.
Whoa-ho-ho there. Whoa!
Steady there, Nellie.
Go ahead, Pinoke, ask them.
Could any of you tell me
where to find Monstro?
Whoa! Whoa, boy!
Whoa, whoa! Hey!
Uh, sakes alive.
Father!
- Father!
- Mr Geppetto!
Not a bite for days.
We can't hold out much longer.
I never thought...
it would end this way, Figaro.
Starving to death...
in the belly of a whale.
My poor little Pinocchio.
He was such a good boy.
It's hopeless, Figaro.
There isn't a fish left.
If the monster doesn't
wake up soon, I--
I'm afraid we--
We are done for.
Here they come!
Tuna! Oh, tuna fish!
Food! We'll eat!
Here's a big one!
Keep them in there, Figaro!
Hey! Wait a minute!
Ha-Have you seen--
Monstro!
We got to get out of here!
Come on, Pinoke.
Don't wait for me.
Never saw so many!
Here's another one!
Enough for weeks!
Here's a big one.
Keep them in there, Figaro!
Hey, blubber mouth, open up!
I got to get in there!
Looks like the last of them.
Here's a big one.
Only a few left.
We got to work fast!
- Hey!
- Here's another one.
Hey, Father!
- Father!
- Don't bother me now,
Pinocchio!
- P-Pinocchio!
- Father!
Pinocchio, my son!
- Hey, Father, here I am!
- Huh?
Oh, oh, yes! Pinocchio, my boy!
- I-- I'm so happy to see you!
- Me too, Father!
- Oops!
- Figaro! Ah, Figaro.
Cleo! Oh, Cleo!
- You're here too.
- Yes!
We are all together again!
- Oh, you, you are soaking wet.
- Yes, Father.
You, you mustn't catch cold.
- But I came to save you!
- 'Cause you know, you, you
shouldn't have come down here.
- But, Father!
- But I'm awfully glad
to see you.
Let me take your hat. Oh!
Pinocchio!
Wh-- Wh-- What's the matter?
- Those ears!
- Huh? Ears?
Oh, these.
Hah. Oh, that's nothing.
I got a tail too.
Pinocchio!
What's happened to you?
Well, I-- I-- I--
Oh, never mind now.
Old Geppetto has his
little Woodenhead.
Nothing else matters.
I got to get in!
My pal's in there!
Come on, you big moose!
Open up, I tell ya--
Hey! Cut it out!
Oh, boy. Beat it, you buzzards!
Get out? Oh, no, no, son.
I've tried every way.
Why, I, I even built a raft.
- A raft? That's it!
- Huh?
We'll take the raft, and when
the whale opens its mouth--
No, no, no, no.
N-Now listen, son.
He only opens his mouth
when he's eating.
Then everything comes in.
Nothing goes out.
- Oh.
- It's hopeless, Pinocchio.
Come. We make a nice fire
and we cook some of the fish.
- A fire! That's it!
- Yes. And then we'll
all eat again.
A great big fire!
Lots of smoke.
Smoke? Oh, yeah, sure.
A smoked fish will taste good.
- Quick, some wood.
- Pinocchio, not the chair!
Hurry, Father. More wood!
Oh, what will we sit on if we--
We won't need it.
We're getting out!
Getting out? But how?
- We'll make him sneeze!
- Make him sneeze?
Ohh, that will make him mad.
Well, it's about time!
- It won't work!
- Hurry, Father! Climb aboard!
-We'll never get by those teeth!
-Yes, we will!
Hey, which way you going?
Wait for me!
Hang on! Here we go!
Gesundheit.
- We're going back!
- No, we'll make it!
Faster, faster!
It's no use! We're done for!
We made it!
Look! Now he is mad!
I told you he'd be furious!
- He's gone!
- Where did he go?
Look out!
Hang on!
He's coming back. Hurry!
He's trying to kill us!
Paddle, son!
Let's go back!
Look out!Jump!
Father! Father!
Oh, Father!
Pinocchio, swim for shore.
Swim for shore.
Hang on, Father!
Save... yourself.
Pinocchio,
save yourself.
Don't mind me, son.
Save yourself, Pinocchio.
Pinocchio?
Oh, Pinocchio!
Pinocchi--
My boy.
My brave little boy.
Prove yourself brave,
truthful and unselfish,
and someday you will
be a real boy.
Awake, Pinocchio.
Awake.
Father! Whatcha crying for?
'Cause... you are dead,
Pinocchio.
No! No, I'm not.
Yes, yes, you are.
Now, lie down.
But, Father, I'm alive. See?
And-- And I'm, uh--
I'm-- I'm real. I'm a real boy!
You're alive! And, and
you are a real boy!
- Yea! Whoopie!
- A real live boy!
This calls for a celebration!
Professor, lots of music!
Well! Huh. Th-This is
practically where I came in.
Thank you, milady.
He deserved to be a real boy.
And it sure was nice of you to--
Huh? Wha-- Uh-- Wh-- Wh--
W-- Well, I'll be!
My, my!
Solid gold too.
Oh, I think it's swell!
When your heart
is in your dream
No request
Is too extreme
When you wish
Upon a star
Your dreams
Come true
You'll find
your dreams come true
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/h49h
Help other users to choose the best subtitles