♪ Which pet's address
is the finest in Paris?
♪ Which pets possess
the longest pedigree?
♪ Which pets get to
sleep on velvet mats?
♪ Naturellament
♪ The Aristocats
♪ Which pets are blessed with
the fairest forms and faces?
♪ Which pets know best all
the gentle social graces?
♪ Which pets live on
cream and loving pats?
♪ Naturellament
♪ The Aristocats
♪ They show aristocratic bearing
♪ When they're seen upon an airing
♪ And aristocatic
flair in what they do
♪ And what they say
♪ Aristocats are never
found in alleyways
♪ Or hanging 'round
the garbage cans
♪ Where common kitties play
♪ Oh, no
Which pets are known
♪ To never show their claws?
♪ Which pets are prone
to hardly any flaws?
♪ To which pets do the
others tip their hats?
♪ Naturellament
♪ The Aristocats
-== [ www.OpenSubtitles.com ] ==-
Oh, ho!
Marie, my little one.
You're going to be as
beautiful as your mother.
Isn't she, Duchess?
Careful, Toulouse.
You're making it very
difficult for Edgar.
Whoa, Frou-Frou, whoa.
Steady, girl.
Thank you, Edgar.
Oh. Of course, Frou-Frou.
I almost forgot.
Madame... uh, may I take
your parcel, Madame?
It really is much too
heavy for you, Madame.
Now, tut-tut, Edgar.
Don't fuss over me.
Berlioz, come back here.
Haven't you forgotten
something, darling?
Thank you, Miss Frou-Frou,
for letting me ride on your back.
You're quite welcome, young man.
How was that, Mama?
Very good, darling.
That was very nice.
Come along, Duchess. Kittens.
Come along.
Oh, and Edgar,
I'm expecting my attorney,
Georges Hautecourt.
You'll remember him, of course.
Of course, Madame.
How could anyone forget him?
♪ Ta rah rah boom di aye
♪ Da da da dee dee dee
Dee dee dee
Oh!
♪ Dee do do do
♪ Ta rah rah boom di aye
♪ Ta rah rah boom di...
Whoops!
Oh, oh, oh. Not as spry as
I was when I was 80, eh?
♪ Ta rah rah boom di aye
Ah, good day, sir.
Madame is expecting you, sir.
Evening. Evening, Edgar.
♪ Ta rah rah boom di aye
- ♪ Ta rah rah boom di aye
- Another ringer, sir.
You never miss.
Come on, Edgar! The last one
up the stairs is a nincompoop!
Could we take the
elevator this time, sir?
Oh, that birdcage? Poppycock.
Elevators are for
old people. Whoops!
May I give you a hand, sir?
You haven't got an extra
foot, have you, Edgar?
That always makes me laugh, sir.
Every time.
- Whoo!
- Let go of my cane!
Careful, sir. Please.
Frightfully sorry, sir.
Don't panic, Edgar.
Upward and onward! Whee!
Am I going too fast for you, Edgar?
Please, sir, hold...
There now, Duchess. That's better.
We must both look our
best for Georges.
He's our oldest and
dearest friend, you know.
Come in.
Announcing...
Monsieur...
Georges...
Hautecourt.
Oh, my goodness, Edgar.
I know Georges.
Adelaide, my dear.
So good to see you, Georges.
Aaah!
Still the softest
hands in all Paris.
You're a shameless
flatterer, Georges.
Adelaide, that's music.
It's from Carmen, isn't it?
That's right. It was
my favourite role.
Yes, yes.
It was the night of your grand
premiere that we first met. Remember?
- Oh, indeed, I do.
- And how we celebrated your success.
Champagne, dancing
the night away...
Oh, Georges.
Oh, ho!
Thank goodness.
Just in time.
Ah, Georges.
We're just a pair of
sentimental old fools.
Now, Georges, do be serious.
I've asked you to come here on
a very important legal matter.
Oh? Oh!
Splendid, splendid.
Who do you want me to sue, eh?
Come now, Georges. I don't
wish you to sue anyone.
I simply want to make my will.
Will, eh? Will, will...
Now, then, who are
the beneficiaries?
Well, as you know, I have
no living relatives.
Naturally, I want my beloved cats
to be always well-cared for.
Certainly, no one can do this better
than my faithful servant, Edgar.
Edgar?
Adelaide, you mean to say you're
leaving your vast fortune to Edgar?
Everything you possess?
Stocks and bonds?
This mansion? Your country chateau?
Your treasures, jewels, and...?
Oh, no, no, Georges.
- To my cats.
- To your cats?
Cats?
Yes, Georges.
I simply wish to have
the cats inherit first.
Then, at the end of their lifespan,
my entire estate will revert to Edgar.
Cats inherit first?
And I come after the cats.
I, me, after...
It's... it's not fair.
Whoo! I mean, whoo.
Each cat will live about 12 years.
I can't wait... And each
cat has nine lives.
That's four times 12...
Multiply by nine times...
No, it's less than that. Anyway,
it's much longer than I'd ever live.
I'll be gone.
No.
Oh, no. They'll be gone.
I'll think of a way.
Oh... there are a million
reasons why I should.
All of 'em dollars.
Millions.
Those cats have got to go.
Wait for me, wait for me!
Me first, me first. Whoo.
Why should you be first?
Because I'm a lady, that's why.
Ha-ha. You're not a lady.
You're nothin' but a sister.
Oh!
I'll show you if I'm a lady or not.
- You're tickling.
- Get her, Berlioz, get her.
Fight fair, Marie.
Females never fight fair.
Ow! Now, that hurt.
Mama! Mama!
Marie, darling, Marie,
you must stop that.
This, this is really not ladylike.
And Berlioz?
Such behaviour is most unbecoming
to a lovely gentleman.
Well, she started it.
Ladies do not start fights,
but they can finish them.
Berlioz.
Now, don't be rude.
We were just practising
biting and clawing.
Aristocrats do not practise
biting and clawing
and things like that.
That's just horrible.
But someday we might
meet a tough alley cat.
That will do.
It's time we concerned ourself
with self-improvement.
You want to grow up to be lovely
charming ladies and gentlemens.
Now, Toulouse, you go and
start on with your painting.
Yes, Mama.
Mama, may we watch Toulouse paint
before we start our music lesson?
Please?
Well, yes, my love, but...
- Whoops.
- ...you must be very quiet.
Uh-Oh.
Mm-hm. Mm-mm-hm.
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
It's Edgar.
Yeah, old pickle-puss Edgar.
"Old pickle-puss"? Now, now.
Berlioz, that is not kind.
You know Edgar is so
fond of all of us
and takes very good care of us.
♪ Rock-a-bye, kitties
♪ Bye-bye you go
♪ La la la la
♪ And I'm in the dough
Oh, Edgar, you sly old fox.
Oops. Oh, dear.
Slip of the hand and
it's off to dreamland.
I say, that's not at all bad.
Slip of the hand... dreamland.
Let's leave Toulouse
to his painting.
Now, dear, you go to
the piano. Now, run along.
Both of you, go ahead.
Yes, Mama.
It's time to practise your
scales and your arpeggios.
Ouch!
I'm ready, maestro.
Ooh!
Mama, he did it again.
- Tattletale.
- Now, Berlioz.
Now, please, darling, settle down and
play me your pretty little song.
Yes, Mama.
♪ Do mi so do
Do so mi do
♪ Every truly cultured
♪ Music student knows
♪ You must learn your
scales and your arpeggios
♪ Bring the music
ringing from your chest
♪ And not your nose
♪ While you sing your
scales and your arpeggios
♪ If you're faithful to
your daily practising
♪ You will find your
progress is encouraging
♪ Do mi so mi
Do mi so mi
♪ Fa la so it goes
♪ When you do your scales
and your arpeggios
♪ Do mi so do...
♪ Do mi so do
Do so mi do
♪ Though at first it seems
as though it doesn't show
J“ Like a tree, ability
will bloom and grow
♪ If you're smart
you'll learn by heart
♪ What every artist knows
♪ You must sing your scales
♪ And your arpeggios ♪
Oh. Good evening, my little ones.
Your favourite dish,
prepared a very special way.
It's crème de la crème à la Edgar.
Sleep well... I mean,
eat well, of course.
Good evening, Duchess.
- Hello, kittens.
- Hello, Roquefort.
- Hi, Roquefort.
- Good evening, Monsieur Roquefort.
Mm. Something smells awfully good.
What is that appetising smell?
It's crème de la crème à la Edgar.
Won't you join us,
Monsieur Roquefort?
Well, yes. I mean...
I don't mean to interrupt.
But...
But it so happens that I
have a cracker with me.
Come on, Roquefort, have some.
Oh, thank you. Don't mind if I do.
Just a few dunks.
Mm. Oooh. Very good.
My compliments to the chef.
Mm. This is yummy.
Mm.
Delicious.
Double delicious.
This calls for another cracker.
I'll be right back.
So that's...
crème de la crème...
a la...
Edgar.
Ahhh!
Lafayette. Hey, Lafayette.
Lafayette!
- Well, I'm right here.
- Listen.
Wheels approaching.
Oh, Napoleon, we done
bit six tyres today.
Chased four motorcars and
a bicycle and a scooter.
Hush your mouth.
It's a motorcycle.
Two-cylinder, chain drive,
one squeaky wheel on
the front, it sounds like.
You go for the tyres, and I'll go
right for the seat of the problem.
How come you always grab the
tender part for yourself?
'Cause I outrank you, that's why.
Now, stop beating your
gums and sound the attack.
No, that's mess call.
Yeah, made a mess of it, huh?
You can be replaced, you know.
OK, let's charge. Oooh.
Wait a minute. I'm the leader.
I'm the one that says when we go.
Here we go.
Charge!
Whew.
Ahh! Oww!
Nice doggy, nice doggy.
Heel, roll over, play dead!
Yow!
This sure beats running, Napoleon.
Step on the gas, Napoleon.
I got 'er wide open.
Oww!
Oh!
Oh, where am I?
I'm not at home at all.
Children, where are you? Answer me.
Berlioz?
Toulouse, Marie, where are you?
Here I am, Mama.
Marie, darling. Well,
are you all right?
Uh, I guess I had a nightmare
and fell out of bed.
Now, Marie, darling,
don't be frightened.
Mama! Mama!
That's Berlioz.
Over here, darling.
Berlioz, here we are.
And don't worry. Everything's
going to be all right.
I'm coming, Mama.
Gee, I'm cold and I'm wet.
Mama?
Mama!
Darling.
That's only a little frog, my love.
He had a mouth like
a hippo-lotamus.
Oh, what's so funny?
Not now, darling. Darlings,
you just stay here.
I go and I look for Toulouse.
Toulouse?
Toulouse, where are you?
- Toulouse!
Toulouse!
Hey! What's all the
yelling about, huh?
Why didn't you answer?
Mama, he's been here all the time.
Oh, thank goodness.
Are you all right?
I was having a funny dream.
Edgar was in it.
And we were all riding
and bouncing along...
Frogs? Uh-oh. It wasn't a dream.
- Edgar did this to us.
- Edgar?
Oh, darling, why, that's...
Why, that's ridiculous.
Yeah, maybe you fell on
your head, Toulouse.
Mama, I'm afraid. I wanna go home.
Now, my darling, don't be
frightened. You'll see...
Oh, dear. Let's get into
the basket, all of us.
What's gonna happen to us?
Well, darlings, I just don't know.
It does look hopeless, doesn't it?
I wish we were home
with Madame right now.
Oh, poor Madame.
She will be so worried
when she finds us gone.
Duchess? Kittens?
Oh, my gracious.
I had the most horrible
dream about them.
Thank goodness it was only a dream.
Oh, dear, what a terrible night.
Now, now, my darlings.
Don't be frightened.
The storm will soon pass.
Oh, no! They're gone.
Duchess! Kittens!
Duchess! Where are you?
They're gone. They're gone!
Duchess? Kittens? Gone?
Why, that's terrible.
But where? Why?
Good heavens. Anything could
happen to them on a night like this.
Get washed down a storm
drain, struck by lightning...
Oh, they'll need help.
I've just got to find them.
Duchess! Kittens?
Duchess!
Kittens!
♪ I like a chee-chee-chee-rony
like they make at home
♪ Or a healthy fish
with a big backbone
♪ I'm Abraham de Lacy
♪ Giuseppe Casey
♪ Thomas O'Malley
♪ O'Malley the alley cat
♪ I've got that Wanderlust
♪ Gotta walk the scene
♪ Gotta kick up highway dust
♪ Feel the grass that's green
♪ Gotta strut them city streets
♪ Showin' off my éclat, yeah
♪ Tellin' my friends
of the social elite
♪ Or some cute cat I happen to meet
♪ That I'm
♪ Abraham de Lacy
♪ Giuseppe Casey
♪ Thomas O'Malley
♪ O'Malley the alley cat
Oh, my. Monsieur, your name
seems to cover all of Europe.
Of course. I'm the
only cat of my kind.
♪ I'm king of the highway
♪ Prince of the boulevard
♪ Duke of the avant-garde
♪ The world is my backyard
♪ So if you're goin' my way
♪ That's the road you wanna seek
♪ Calcutta to Rome
♪ Or home sweet home in Paris
♪ Magnifique, you all
Oh, boy, an alley cat.
Shh, shh. Listen.
♪ I only got myself
♪ And this big old world
♪ But I sip that cup of life
♪ With my fingers curled
♪ I don't worry what road to take
♪ I don't have to think Of that
♪ Whatever I take
is the road I make
♪ It's the road of life
Make no mistake
♪ For me
♪ Yeah, Abraham de Lacy
♪ Giuseppe Casey
♪ Thomas O'Malley
♪ O'Malley the alley cat ♪
That's right. And I'm
very proud of that.
Yeah.
Bravo.
Very good. You are a great talent.
Oh, thank you.
And what might your name be?
My name is Duchess.
Duchess.
Beautiful. Love it.
And those eyes.
Oooh.
Why, your eyes are like
sapphires sparkling so bright.
They make the morning
radiant and light.
- How romantic.
- Sissy stuff.
Very poetic.
But it is not quite Shakespeare.
Of course not. That's
pure O'Malley, baby.
Right off the cuff.
I got a million of them.
Oh, no more, please.
I am really in a great
deal of trouble.
Trouble?
Helping beautiful dames...
uh, uh, damsels in
distress is my specialty.
Now, what's the
hang-up, your ladyship?
Well, it is most important
that I get back to Paris.
So if you would be just so
kind and show me the way...
Show you the way?
Perish the thought.
We shall fly to Paris
on a magic carpet,
side by side, with the
stars as our guide.
Just we two.
Oh, that would be wonderful.
Three?
Four?
Five?
Oh, yes, Monsieur O'Malley.
- These are my children.
- Oh, how sweet.
Do you really have a magic carpet?
- Are we really gonna ride on it?
- Now, now, Marie.
Mama, do I have
sparkling sapphire eyes
- that dazzle, too?
- Did I say that?
Yes, right off your cuff.
And you said we're gonna
ride on your magic carpet.
Well, now, uh...
What I meant... You see, I...
No poetry to cover the
situation, Monsieur O'Malley?
What I had in mind was kind
of a sports model, baby.
- You know, one of those...
- Perhaps a magic carpet?
Built for two?
I wouldn't take up much room.
I understand perfectly,
Monsieur O'Malley.
Well, come along, darlings.
I'm a tough alley cat, too.
Hey, there.
You're coming on. I bet you're a
real tiger in your neighbourhood.
Yeah. That's 'cause
I practise all the time.
Now, now, Toulouse.
Toulouse, come along, dear.
Yes, Mama.
See you around, tiger.
Now, that's quite a family.
Come to think of it, O'Malley,
you're not a cat. You're a rat.
Right? Right.
- Hey, hey, hold up there.
- Yes, Monsieur O'Malley?
Now look, kids,
if I said magic carpet,
magic carpet it's gonna be.
And it's gonna stop
for passengers...
wright...
here.
Oh, boy, we're gonna fly after all.
Another flight into the
fantasy, Monsieur O'Malley?
No, no, no, baby.
You just hide over there,
and you leave the rest
to J. Thomas O'Malley.
Quick, Mom, get in here.
- But, children...
- Hurry up, Mama, hurry.
One magic carpet, coming up.
That's a magic carpet?
Sacré bleu!
Sapristi! Stupid cat.
Brainless lunatic.
All right, step lively.
All aboard for Paris.
Why, Mr. O'Malley, you
could have lost your life.
So I got a few to spare. Nothin'.
- How can we ever thank you?
- My pleasure entirely.
Aloha. Auf weidersehen.
Bonsoir. Sayonara.
And all those goodbye things, baby.
Sayonara, mister...
Mama!
Marie! Marie!
Oh, Marie, are you all right?
- Yes, Mama.
- Haven't we met before?
And I'm so very glad we did.
Thank you, Mr. O'Malley,
for saving my life.
No trouble at all, little princess.
And when we get to Paris, I'll
show you the time of your life.
Oh, I'm so sorry, but...
we just couldn't.
You see, my mistress will
be so worried about us.
Well, humans don't really worry
too much about their pets.
Oh, no. You just don't understand.
She loves us very much.
Poor Madame, in that
big mansion, all alone.
In all our days, in tender ways,
her love for us was shown.
And so you see,
we can't leave her alone.
She'd always say that we're the
greatest treasure she could own.
Because with us she
never felt alone.
Oh, Roquefort, I've been
so worried about you.
Did you have any luck at all?
Not a sign of them, Frou-Frou.
And I've searched all night.
I know. And poor Madame
didn't sleep a wink, either.
Oh, it's a sad day for all of us.
Morning, Frou-Frou,
my pretty steed.
Can you keep a secret, hmm?
Of course you can.
I have some news straight
from the horse's mouth,
if you'll pardon the
expression, of course.
Look, Frou-Frou.
I've made the headlines.
"Mysterious Catnapper
Abducts Family of Cats."
Aren't you proud of me?
So he's the catnapper.
The police said it was a
professional, masterful job.
The work of a genius.
Not bad, eh, Frou-Frou old girl?
Oh, they won't find a
clue to implicate me.
Not one single clue.
Why, I'll eat my hat if they...
My hat!
My umbrella!
Oh, oh, gracious.
I've got to get those
things back tonight.
But... oh, you...
Why, that...
sneaky, crooked, no-good butler!
- Anyone for breakfast?
- What breakfast?
- Where is it?
- Right under that magic carpet.
But now we have to
cook up a little spell.
You know. Ready?
All right. First, to make
the magic begin,
you wiggle your nose.
And tickle your chin.
Now you close your eyes.
And cross your heart.
Then presto, breakfast à la carte.
Hooray!
- We did it.
- Look, Mama, look!
Why, Mr. O'Malley, you are amazing.
True.
Sapristi!
Sacré bleu!
Thieves! Robbers!
Mangy tramps!
Take that and that!
Oh. Oh, what a horrible,
horrible human.
Well, some humans are like that,
Duchess. I've learned to live with it.
I'll show him.
Hey, cool it, you little tiger.
- That guy's dynamite.
- But he called us tramps.
Oh, I'll be so glad
when we get back home.
That's a long way off,
so we better get moving.
Gee whiz.
Look at that bridge.
Come on, let's play train.
Now, be careful, children.
Marie's the caboose. All aboard!
Choo choo choo, choo choo choo.
Choc choo choo choo...
Clickedy, clickedy,
clickedy, clickedy.
- Oh, no.
- Don't panic.
Down underneath here.
- Mama!
- Marie!
Oh, Marie!
Keep your head up,
Marie! Here I come!
Thomas! Thomas, up here.
Gee, Marie, why did you
have to fall off the bridge?
Thomas! Oh, Thomas! Take care!
I'm all right, honey, don't worry.
I'll see you downstream.
What beautiful
countryside, Abigail.
- So much like our own dear England.
- Indeed, yes.
Amelia, if I walk much
farther I'll get flat feet.
Abigail, we were
born with flat feet.
I say. Look over there.
Oh. Oh, how unusual.
Fancy that. A cat
learning how to swim.
He's going about it
all the wrong way.
Quite. We must correct him.
Sir. Sir?
You are most fortunate
we happened along.
Yes. We're here to help you.
No, no. Back off, girls.
I'm doing fine.
First, you must gain self-confidence
by striking out on your own.
Go away. I'm trying
to get to shore.
You will never learn to swim properly
with that willow branch in your mouth.
Indeed, not. Snip, snip.
Here we go.
Don't do that!
You're doing splendidly.
And don't worry about form.
It will come later.
Oh, he takes to water
like a fish, doesn't he?
A very enthusiastic pupil!
No, no. This is no time
for fun and games.
Gracious, Amelia.
- You don't suppose...
- Oh, yes. Yes, I do.
Bottoms up.
Deeper!
Look, Ma, there he is.
You really did quite
well for a beginner.
Oh, Thomas. Thank
goodness you're safe.
- Keep practising.
- And toodley-pip.
Can I help you, Mr. O'Malley, huh?
Help? I've had all
the help I can take.
Oh, mademoiselles, thank you so
much for helping Mr. O'Malley.
Of course, my dear.
But first, introductions.
Yes, we British like to
keep things proper.
Now, I am Amelia Gabble
and this is my sister...
- Miss Abigail Gabble.
- We're twin sisters.
You might say we're related.
How nice. I never
would have guessed.
Look, they got rubber feet.
Yeah.
- We're on holiday.
- For a walking tour of France.
- Swimming some of the way.
- On water, of course.
Thomas, this is Amelia
and Abigail Gabble.
Yeah, honey, get those two
web-footed lifeguards out of here.
Now, now, Thomas.
OK, OK, baby.
Hiya, chicks.
How awful.
We're not chickens. We're geese.
Nooo. I thought you were swans.
Oh! Oh, flatterer.
Your husband is very
charming and very handsome.
Well...
Uh, you see, I'm not
exactly her husband.
Exactly? You either
are or you're not.
All right. I'm not.
Oh?
Hm.
- It's scandalous.
- He's nothing but a cad.
Absolutely. Possibly a reprobate.
- A roué.
- His eyes are too close together.
- Shifty, too.
- Look at his crooked smile.
His chin is very weak, too.
Obviously, a philanderer who trifles
with unsuspecting women's hearts.
How romantic.
Please, please, let me explain.
Thomas is a dear friend of ours.
- He's just helping us to get to...
- Come on, Duchess.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Well, girls, see you around.
- We're on our way to Paris.
- Oh, how nice.
- We're going to Paris ourselves.
- Why don't you join us?
I think that's a splendid idea.
Oh, no.
Now, uh, you stand here, dear.
And, uh, let's see.
You take this position.
- Duchess, you'll do nicely here.
- Very good.
And, you dear, you take this place.
Now, that leaves Mr. O'Malley.
We can't leave him, can we?
Mr. O'Malley, I think you
should be the rear end.
Ready, everyone? Now, think goose.
Forward march.
Mama? Do we have to
waddle like they do?
Yes, dear. Think goose.
When we get to Paris,
you must meet Uncle Waldo.
Waldo?
Yes, he's our uncle.
We are to meet Uncle
Waldo at Le Petit Café.
Le Petit Café? Oh, that's
that famous restaurant.
C'est magnifique.
Sacré bleu!
Oh, he bit my finger!
Get out. Go! Go, get out. Scram!
Good riddance!
Why! Why, it's Uncle Waldo.
Uncle Waldo!
Abigail! Amelia!
My two favourite nooses.
Uncle Waldo, I do believe
you've been drinking.
Oh, dear. What happened to
your lovely tail feathers?
Girls, it's outrageous.
Why, you won't believe
what they tried to do
to your poor old Uncle Waldo.
Look. Look at this.
"Prime country goose
à la Provençale.
Stuffed with chestnuts"?
And "basted in... white wine".
Basted? He's been marinated in it.
Dreadful.
Being British, I would
have preferred sherry.
Sherry! Sherry.
Oh! Oh, Uncle Waldo.
- You're just too much.
- You mean he's had too much.
- Abigail, Abigail.
- Yes, dear?
We'd best get Uncle Waldo to bed.
I say, there...
what's all the
whispering about, huh?
- Shh!
- Oh! Whoo-hoo!
Now, now, now, girls.
Girls, don't shush
your old Uncle Waldo.
Why, you'll wake up the
whole neighbourhood.
- Sh. No!
- Neighbourhood!
Come along, Uncle Waldo.
Oh, jeez, I think
we'd better be going.
Oh. Right-o, girls.
Birds of a feather must...
together.
That's "stick together".
Oh, stick.
Shush.
You know something?
I like Uncle Waldo.
Especially when he's marinated.
Frou-Frou, here comes Edgar.
Hurry, Roquefort, hop
aboard the motorcycle.
And for goodness sakes,
do be careful.
Frou-Frou, tonight Operation
Catnapper will be completed.
Wish me luck. Fisherman's luck.
Bye, Frou-Frou. Oooh!
I... Whoa!
Lafayette. Lafayette.
Listen.
Oh, shucks, Napoleon, that ain't
nothin' but a little old cricket bug.
It's squeaky shoes approaching.
Oh, cricket bugs don't wear shoes.
Hush your mouth.
Let's see.
They're Oxford shoes.
Size nine and a half.
Hole in the left sole,
it sounds like.
- What colour are they?
- They're black...
Now, how would I know that?
Hey! Now the squeaking has stopped.
I still say it was a
little old cricket bug.
I'm the leader.
I'll decide what it was.
It was a little old cricket bug.
I'll see ya in the
morning, Napoleon.
That's my hat. I'm the leader.
Well, shoot fire.
Don't get sore at me.
I ain't done nothin'.
Ooh. Oh.
Ooh.
Mm, mm. That feels good, Lafayette.
That's all right.
Mm. Mm.
Mm-mmm.
Oooh.
A little lower and faster there.
I'm scratching as fast as I can.
Oooh. Right there. That's good.
Oooh.
It's so warm... and cosy.
- Oooh.
- Aaah!
Oooh.
What's going on? Lafayette, what
in tarnation you trying to do?
Aw, I get blamed for everything.
Wait a minute. Where's my hat?
What? And somebody
stole my bumbershoot.
Where's my beddy-bye basket?
Whoever it is, is gonna
get it and get it good.
This time I get the tender part.
Hush your mouth. Now, come on.
Hey, Napoleon,
it's them shoes again.
Yeah, yeah, I hear 'em.
Napoleon, I'm plumb
goose-pimply scared.
Now, this is no time
to turn chicken.
I got a feelin' this case
is gonna bust wide open.
Whoo-hoo!
Did you see him?
No, no, he sneaked up
behind me and tailgated me.
Well, he didn't hurt me.
He hit me on the head.
Shh. Listen.
Sounds like a one-wheel...
- A one-wheel what?
- You're not gonna believe this.
But it's a one-wheeled haystack.
Hey, there it go. Come on.
After it!
I got him, I got him, I got him!
Ow! That's me.
Whoa, whoa. Oh!
Get him, get him.
Ooh. Ow.
Well, c'est la guerre, Napoleon.
I guess you can't win 'em all.
Ow. Oooh, oooh.
Criminently!
But, Thomas, Madame
will be so worried.
Are you sure we can't
get home tonight?
Mama, I'm tired.
Me, too, and my feet hurt.
Look, baby,
it's late and the kids are bushed.
I'll bet we walked a hundred miles.
I'll bet it's more than a thousand.
Now, now, darlings, cheer up.
Mr. O'Malley knows a place
where we can stay tonight.
How much farther
is it, Mr. O'Malley?
Keep your whiskers up, tiger.
It's just beyond that
next chimney pot.
Well, there it is.
My own penthouse pad.
It's not exactly the Ritz,
but it's peaceful and quiet.
Oh! Oh, no.
Sounds like Scat Cat and
his gang have dropped by.
- Oh, friends of yours?
- Yeah, they're old buddies,
and they're real swingers.
"Schwingers"?
What is a "schwinger"?
You know, not exactly
your type, Duchess.
Maybe we'd better find
another place, huh?
Oh, no, no, no. I would
like to see your pad
and meet your Scat Cat.
Well, OK.
Hey, Scat Cat, blow some of
that sweet stuff my way.
Well, lookie here.
Big man O'Malley's
back in his alley.
Swing on down here, daddy.
Lay some skin on me, Scat Cat.
Yeah.
Buona sera, paesano.
Welcome home, O'Malley.
Duchess, this is the
greatest cat of them all.
Oh, I'm delighted to meet
you, Monsieur Scat Cat.
Likewise, Duchess.
You're too much.
You are charming.
And your music is so...
So different, so exciting.
It isn't Beethoven, Mama,
but it sure bounces.
Say, this kitten-cat
knows where it's at.
Knows where what's at?
Why, little lady,
let me elucidate here.
♪ Everybody wants to be a cat
♪ Because a cat's the only cat
♪ Who knows where it's at
♪ Tell me, everybody's pickin'
up on that feline beat
♪ 'Cause everything
else is obsolete
♪ Strictly high-button shoes
♪ A square with a horn makes
you wish you weren't born
♪ Every time he plays
♪ But with a square in the act
♪ You can set music back
♪ To the caveman days
Ch-ch-ch-chum
♪ I've heard some corny
birds who tried to sing
♪ But, still, a cat's the only
cat who knows how to swing
♪ Who wants to dig a long-haired
gig or stuff like that
♪ When everybody wants to be a cat
♪ A square with a horn makes
you wish you weren't born
- ♪ Every time he plays
- ♪ Oh, a rinky tinky tinky
♪ With a square in the act
you can set music back
♪ To the caveman days
♪ Oh, a rinky tinky tinky
♪ Yes, everybody wants to be a cat
♪ Because a cat's the only
cat who knows where it's at
♪ When playin' jazz you
always has a welcome mat
♪ 'Cause everybody
digs a swingin' cat
Oh, boy, fellas,
let's rock the joint.
Ha-ha, groove it, cats.
♪ Shanghai, Hong Kong, egg foo yung
♪ Fortune cookie always wrong
That's a hot one.
How about you and me, Duchess?
Yes, let's swing it, Thomas.
Groovy, Mama, groovy.
Blow it, small fry.
Blow it.
Boy, he blew it.
But he was close.
Beautiful.
♪ If you want to turn me on
♪ Play your horn
Don't spare the tone
♪ And blow a little
soul into the tune
♪ Let's take it to another key
♪ Modulate and wait for me
♪ I'll take a few
ad-libs and pretty soon
♪ The other cats will all commence
♪ Congregatin' on the fence
♪ Beneath the alley's only light
♪ Where every note is
♪ Out of sight
♪ Everybody, everybody
♪ Everybody wants to be a cat
♪ Hallelujah
♪ Everybody, everybody
♪ Everybody wants to be a cat
♪ I'm tellin' you, everybody
♪ Everybody
♪ Everybody wants to be a cat
♪ Yeah, everybody
♪ Everybody
♪ Everybody wants to be a cat
♪ Everybody, everybody
- ♪ Hallelujah
- ♪ Everybody
♪ Everybody
Everybody wants to be a cat... ♪
♪ Everybody wants to be a cat
♪ Because a cat's the only cat
♪ Who knows where it's at
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
Happy dreams, my loves.
I'll bet they're on that
magic carpet right now.
They could hardly
keep their eyes open.
Such an exciting day.
It sure was, and what a finale.
Thomas, your friends
are really delightful.
I just love them.
Well, they're kinda rough,
you know, around the edges,
but if you're ever in a jam,
wham, they're right there.
And wham, when we needed you,
you were right there.
That was just a lucky
break for me, baby.
Oh, and thank you so much
for offering us your home.
Oh. I mean, your pad.
It's very nice.
Well, now, wait a minute.
This is the low-rent
district, remember?
No, no, no, I like it.
Well, all it needs is
a little tidying up,
and maybe a little feminine touch.
Well, if you're applying
for the job, well...
Goody. Mother's going to
work for Mr. O'Malley.
Boy. Your eyes are like sapphires.
Gee.
That's pretty corny though, huh?
Oh, no. Not at all.
Any woman would like it.
I-I mean...
even little Marie.
Yeah.
All those little kittens, Duchess.
I love 'em.
And they are very fond of you.
- Yeah.
- Shh.
You know, they need...
Well, you know, a sort...
Well, a sort of a...
Well, a father around.
Oh, Thomas, Thomas,
that would be wonderful.
Darling, if only I could.
But why can't you?
Because of Madame.
I could never leave her.
But... But Madame's...
Well, she's just another human.
You're just her house pets.
Oh, no, no.
We mean far more to her than that.
Oh, I'm sorry, my dear.
We just have to go home tomorrow.
Yeah.
Well, I guess you know best.
But I'm gonna miss you, baby.
And those kids...
Gee, I'm gonna miss them too.
Well, we almost had a father.
Yeah.
Let's go back to bed.
Good night, Duchess.
Good night, Thomas.
Hey.
Meow!
What a classy neighbourhood.
Dig these fancy wigwams.
Wigwams?
Are you sure we're
on the right street?
Yes. Yes, let's hurry.
We're almost home.
Duchess! Kittens!
Hallelujah, they're back!
Oh, no. Edgar!
I've got to do something, quick.
Oh, ha.
Edgar, old chap, get used to
the finer things in life.
Someday they're all
going to be yours,
you sly old fox.
Oh!
Oh, he got me.
Hooray! We're home.
Wait for me, wait for me!
Me first, me first!
- It's locked.
- Come on.
Let's all start meowing.
- It can't be them.
- The kittens.
Uh, why?
Don't come in!
Go away!
- Away!
- Look, there's Roquefort.
Hi, Roquefort!
He's glad to see us.
I don't know what to say.
I only wish that I...
Maybe just a short, sweet
goodbye would be easiest.
I'll never forget you,
Thomas O'Malley.
Bye.
So long, baby.
Don't come in. Look out for Edgar!
Duchess, wherever have you been?
Look out for the...
sack.
Well... guess they won't
need me any more.
You came back?
It just isn't fair.
Edgar? Edgar, come quickly.
Coming, Madame, coming.
I'll take care of you later.
Oh, Edgar, they're back.
I heard them. Hurry,
hurry, let them in.
Duchess? Kittens?
Come here, my darlings.
Where are you?
- Come on.
- Uh, allow me, Madame.
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty,
kitty, kitty, kitty.
His name is O... what?
His name is O'Malley. O'Malley.
Abraham de Lacy, Giuseppe Casey...
Oh, never mind. Just run,
move, go get him!
Yes, yes, I'm on my way.
I told you it was Edgar.
Aw, shut up, Toulouse.
Oh, it's no use, Edgar.
I'm afraid it was just the
imagination of an old lady.
But I was so sure
that I heard them.
I'm so sorry, Madame.
Mr. O'Malley!
Hey, stop!
Duchess. Kittens. In trouble.
Butler did it.
Duchess and kittens in trouble?
Look, you go get Scat Cat
and his gang of alley cats.
Alley cats?
But I'm a mouse.
Look, I'm gonna need help.
- You mean, you want me...?
- Move!
Just tell 'em O'Malley sent you,
and you won't have a bit of trouble.
No trouble, he said.
Well, that's easy for...
for what's-his-name to say.
He's got nine lives.
I've only got one.
What's a little swinger like you
doing on our side of town?
Oh, please, I was sent
here for help by a cat.
This is outrageous. It's crazy.
But honest! He told me
just to mention his name.
So start mentioning name, rodent.
Oh, now, wait a minute, fellas.
Don't rush me.
His name is O'Toole.
I don't dig him. Strike one.
Oh, oh... O'Brien.
Strike two.
Oh, boy.
You believe me... don't you?
Keep talkin', mousey.
How about O...
Grady?
Huh?
Mousey, you just struck out.
Any last words?
Why did I listen to
that O'Malley cat?
- O'Malley?
- Hold it, cats.
This little guy's on the level.
You're darn tootin'
I'm on the level.
We didn't mean to
ruffle you, squeaky.
Don't worry about me.
O'Malley needs help.
Duchess and kittens are in trouble.
Come on, cats, we gotta split.
Hey, wait for me!
You don't know the way!
Now, my little pesky pets,
you're going to travel first class.
In your own private compartment.
All the way to Timbuktu.
And this time...
you'll never come back.
Oh, no, we've got to hurry.
The baggage truck will
be here any moment now.
Ooh!
Whoo-hoo. Oww!
Over there. They're in the trunk.
Quiet!
Everybody out of here, fast.
You are going to Timbuktu,
if it's the last thing I do.
Well, Mac, this must
be the trunk, eh?
Yup. And she goes all
the way to Timbuktu.
Heave-ho.
Now, my pets,
a little closer together.
Good. Good.
Look, Georges. What do you think?
Very good, very good.
But I think we should
get on with the will.
Yes, yes, of course, but
you know what to do.
Very well. Scratch one butler.
You know, Georges, if Edgar had
only known about the will,
I'm sure he never would have left.
Duchess, it's wonderful
to have you all back.
And I think this young
man is very handsome.
Shall we keep him in the family?
Of course we will.
We need a man around the house.
And, Georges, we must
be sure to provide
for their future little ones.
Of course. The more the merrier.
Now, don't move.
Smile.
Say "cheese".
Did somebody say "cheese"?
Thank you.
Now, run along downstairs.
There's a surprise for you.
Adelaide, what's that music?
Sounds like a gang
of swinging hepcats.
That's exactly what
they are, Georges.
They're the start of
my new foundation.
What foundation?
My home for all the
alley cats of Paris.
♪ Everybody, everybody
♪ Everybody wants to be a cat
♪ Everybody
Whoopee! Ah-ha.
♪ Everybody wants to be a cat
♪ Everybody, everybody
♪ Everybody wants to be
♪ A cat ♪
Hey, Napoleon, that
sounds like the end.
Wait a minute. I'm the leader.
I'll say when it's the end.
It's the end.
♪ Oh, yeah
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/hrap
Help other users to choose the best subtitles