Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
From the day we arrive on the planet
And, blinking, step into the sun
There's more to see than can ever be seen
More to do than can ever be done
There's far too much to take in here
More to find than can ever be found
But the sun rolling high
Through the sapphire sky
Keeps great and small on the endless round
It's the circle of life
And it moves us all
Through despair and hope
Through faith and love
Till we find our place
On the path unwinding
In the circle
The circle of life
It's the circle of life
And it moves us all
Through despair and hope
Through faith and love
Till we find our place
On the path unwinding
In the circle
The circle of life
Life's not fair, is it?
You see, I... Well, I shall never be king.
And you shall never see the light of another day.
Adieu.
Didn't your mother tell you not to play with your food?
What do you want?
I'm here to announce that King Mufasa's on his way.
So you'd better have a good excuse...
for missing the ceremony this morning.
Oh, now, look, Zazu. You've made me lose my lunch.
Ha! You'll lose more than that...
when the king gets through with you.
He's as mad as a hippo with a hernia.
Ooh. I quiver with fear!
Now, Scar, don't look at me that way.
Help!
Drop him.
Impeccable timing, Your Majesty.
Why, if it isn't my big brother...
descending from on high to mingle with the commoners.
Sarabi and I didn't see you at the presentation of Simba.
That was today?
Oh, I feel simply awful!
Must've slipped my mind.
Yes, well, as slippery as your mind is...
as the king's brother...
you should've been first in line!
Well, I was first in line...
until the little hairball was born.
That hairball is my son...
and your future king.
Oh, I shall practice my curtsy.
Don't turn your back on me, Scar.
Oh, no, Mufasa.
Perhaps you shouldn't turn your back on me.
Is that a challenge?
Temper, temper.
I wouldn't dream of challenging you.
Pity. Why not?
As far as brains go, I got the lion's share.
But when it comes to brute strength...
I'm afraid I'm at the shallow end of the gene pool.
There's one in every family, sire.
Two in mine, actually...
and they always manage to ruin special occasions.
What am I going to do with him?
He'd make a very handsome throw rug.
Zazu!
And just think, whenever he gets dirty...
you could take him out and beat him.
Simba.
Dad! Dad!
Come on, Dad, we gotta go! Wake up!
Sorry.
Dad. Dad.
Your son is awake.
Before sunrise, he's your son.
Dad! Come on, Dad.
You promised.
- OK, OK. I'm up, I'm up. - Yeah!
Look, Simba.
Everything the light touches is our kingdom.
Wow.
A king's time as ruler rises and falls like the sun.
One day, Simba, the sun will set on my time here...
and will rise with you as the new king.
- And this'll all be mine? - Everything.
Everything the light touches.
What about that shadowy place?
That's beyond our borders. You must never go there, Simba.
But I thought a king can do whatever he wants.
There's more to being king...
than getting your way all the time.
- There's more? - Simba...
Everything you see exists together...
in a delicate balance.
As king, you need to understand that balance...
and respect all the creatures...
from the crawling ant to the leaping antelope.
But, Dad, don't we eat the antelope?
Yes, Simba, but let me explain.
When we die, our bodies become the grass...
and the antelope eat the grass.
And so we are all connected in the great circle of life.
- Good morning, sire! - Good morning, Zazu.
Checking in with the morning report.
Fire away.
Chimps are going ape, giraffes remain above it all
Elephants remember, though just what, I can't recall
Crocodiles are snapping up fresh offers from the banks
Shown interest in my nest egg, but I quickly said, no, thanks
We haven't paid the hornbills, and the vultures have a hunch
Not everyone invited will be coming back from lunch
This is the morning report
Gives you the long and the short
Every grunt, roar, and snort
Not a tale I distort
On the morning report
- What are you doing, son? - Pouncing.
Let an old pro show you how it's done.
Oh, the buffalo have got a beef about...
Stay low to the ground.
Yeah, OK. Stay low to the ground. Right.
Not a sound.
The season's colors seen in all the herds...
Take it slow. One more step...
- then... ...in the dung
This is the morning report
Gives you the long and the short
Every grunt, roar, and snort
Not a tale I distort
On the morning report
- Zazu! - Yes!
Sir! News from the underground.
Now, this time...
Sire! Hyenas in the pride lands!
Zazu, take Simba home.
- Dad, can't I come? - No, son.
I never get to go anywhere.
Oh, young master, one day, you will be king.
Then you can chase those slobbering, mangy...
stupid poachers from dawn until dusk.
Hey, Uncle Scar! Guess what?
I despise guessing games.
I'm gonna be king of Pride Rock.
Oh, goody.
My dad just showed me the whole kingdom...
and I'm gonna rule it all.
Yes, well, forgive me for not leaping for joy.
Bad back, you know.
Hey, Uncle Scar, when I'm king, what'll that make you?
A monkey's uncle.
You're so weird.
You have no idea.
So, your father showed you the whole kingdom, did he?
Everything.
He didn't show you what's beyond that rise...
at the northern border?
Well, no. He said I can't go there.
And he's absolutely right. It's far too dangerous.
Only the bravest lions go there.
Well, I'm brave. What's out there?
I'm sorry, Simba, I just can't tell you.
Why not?
Simba, Simba, I'm only looking out...
for the well-being of my favorite nephew.
Yeah, right. I'm your only nephew.
All the more reason for me to be protective.
An elephant graveyard is no place for a young prince.
An elephant what? Whoa.
Oh, dear, I've said too much.
Well, I suppose you'd have found out sooner or later...
you being so clever and all.
Oh, just do me one favor.
Promise me you'll never visit that dreadful place.
- No problem. - There's a good lad.
You run along now and have fun.
And remember, it's our little secret.
- Hey, Nala. - Hi, Simba.
Come on. I just heard about this great place.
Simba! I'm kind of in the middle of a bath.
And it's time for yours.
Mom!
Mom, you're messing up my mane!
OK, I'm clean. Can we go now?
So, where are we going? It better not be anyplace dumb.
No, it's really cool.
So, where is this really cool place?
Oh. Around the water hole.
The water hole? What's so great about the water hole?
I'll show you when we get there.
Oh. Mom, can I go with Simba?
Hmm, what do you think, Sarabi?
Well...
- Please? - Please?
It's all right with me.
- All right! - Yeah!
As long as Zazu goes with you.
No, not Zazu.
Step lively. The sooner we get to the water hole...
the sooner we can leave.
So, where are we really going?
- An elephant graveyard. - Wow!
Shh! Zazu.
Right. So how are we gonna ditch the dodo?
Oh, just look at you two.
Little seeds of romance blossoming in the savanna.
Your parents will be thrilled...
what with your being betrothed and all.
- Be... what? - Betrothed. Intended.
Affianced.
Meaning...?
One day, you two are going to be married.
I can't marry her. She's my friend.
Yeah, it'd be so weird.
Sorry to bust your bubble...
but you two turtledoves have no choice.
It's a tradition going back generations.
When I'm king, that'll be the first thing to go.
- Not so long as I'm around. - In that case, you're fired.
Hmm. Nice try, but only the king can do that.
Well, he's the future king.
Yeah, so you have to do what I tell you.
Not yet, I don't. And with an attitude like that...
I'm afraid you're shaping up to be...
a pretty pathetic king indeed.
Hmm. Not the way I see it.
I'm gonna be a mighty king, so enemies beware
Well, I've never seen a king of beasts
With quite so little hair
I'm gonna be the main event like no king was before
I'm brushin' up on lookin' down
I'm workin' on my roar
Thus far, a rather uninspiring thing.
Oh, I just can't wait to be king
You've rather a long way to go, young master, if you think...
- No one sayin', "Do this" - Now, when I said that...
- No one saying, "Be there" - What I meant was...
- No one sayin', "Stop that" - But what you don't realize...
- No one sayin', "See here" - Now, see here!
Free to run around all day
Well, that's definitely out.
Free to do it all my way
I think it's time that you and I
Arranged a heart-to-heart
Kings don't need advice from little hornbills for a start
If this is where the monarchy is headed, count me out
Out of service, out of Africa, I wouldn't hang about
This child is getting wildly out of wing
Oh, I just can't wait to be king
Everybody, look left
Everybody, look right
Everywhere you look, I'm standing in the spotlight
Not yet!
Let every creature go for broke and sing
Let's hear it in the herd and on the wing
It's gonna be King Simba's finest fling
Oh, I just can't wait to be king
Oh, I just can't wait
To be king
I beg your pardon, madam, but... get off!
All right! It worked!
- We lost him. - I am a genius.
Hey, genius, it was my idea.
Yeah, but I pulled it off.
- With me! - Oh, yeah?
- Pinned ya. - Hey, let me up.
Pinned ya again.
This is it. We made it.
It's really creepy.
Yeah. Isn't it great?
- We could get in big trouble. - I know.
I wonder if its brains are still in there.
There's only one way to know. Come on, let's go check it out.
Wrong! The only checking out you will do...
will be to check out of here.
Oh, man!
We're way beyond the boundary of the pride lands.
Look, Banana Beak is scared.
It's Mr. Banana Beak to you, fuzzy...
and right now we are all in very real danger.
Danger? Ha! I walk on the wide side.
I laugh in the face of danger.
Well, well, well, Banzai, what have we got here?
Hmm. I don't know, Shenzi. What do you think, Ed?
Just what I was thinking. A trio of trespassers!
And quite by accident, let me assure you.
A simple navigational error.
Whoa, whoa, wait, wait, wait.
I know you. You're Mufasa's little stooge.
I, madam, am the king's major-domo.
- And that would make you... - The future king.
Do you know what we do to kings who step out of their kingdom?
You can't do anything to me.
Technically, they can. We are on their land.
But, Zazu, you told me they're nothin'...
but slobbering, mangy, stupid poachers.
- Lx-nay on the upid-stay. - Who are you callin' upid-stay?
My, my, my. Look at the sun! It's time to go!
What's the hurry? We'd love you to stick around for dinner.
Yeah, we could have whatever's lion around!
Wait, wait, wait, I got one, I got one!
Make mine a cub sandwich! What'd you think?
What, Ed? What is it?
Hey, did we order this dinner to go?
- No, why? - 'Cause there it goes!
- Did we lose 'em? - I think so.
Where's Zazu?
The little major-domo bird hippety-hopped...
all the way to the birdie-boiler.
Oh, no! Not the birdie-boiler!
Hey, why don't you pick on somebody your own size?
- Like you? - Oops.
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
That was it?
Do it again. Come on.
Oh, please, please! Uncle, uncle!
- Silence! - We're gonna shut up right now!
Calm down. We're really sorry.
If you ever come near my son again...
Oh, this is your son?
- Oh, your son? - Did you know that?
No. Me? I didn't know... No, did you?
- No, of course not. - No.
- Ed? - Ed?
Toodles.
Dad, l...
You deliberately disobeyed me.
- Dad, I'm sorry. - Let's go home.
I thought you were very brave.
- Yes, sire? - Take Nala home.
I've got to teach my son a lesson.
Come, Nala.
Simba, good luck.
Simba, I'm very disappointed in you.
- I know. - You could've been killed.
You deliberately disobeyed me...
and what's worse, you put Nala in danger.
I was just trying to be brave, like you.
I'm only brave when I have to be.
Simba, being brave...
doesn't mean you go looking for trouble.
But you're not scared of anything.
I was today.
- You were? - Yes.
I thought I might lose you.
Oh. I guess even kings get scared, huh?
- But you know what? - What?
I think those hyenas were even scareder.
'Cause nobody messes with your dad.
- Come here, you. - Oh, no! No!
Come here!
Gotcha!
- Dad? - Hmm?
- We're pals, right? - Right.
And we'll always be together, right?
Simba, let me tell you something...
that my father told me.
Look at the stars.
The great kings of the past...
Iook down on us from those stars.
- Really? - Yes.
So, whenever you feel alone...
just remember that those kings...
will always be there to guide you...
and so will I.
Man, that lousy Mufasa.
I won't be able to sit for a week.
It's not funny, Ed.
Hey, shut up!
Will you knock it off?
Well, he started it.
Look at you guys.
No wonder we're dangling at the bottom of the food chain.
Man, I hate dangling.
Yeah? You know, if it weren't for those lions...
we'd be runnin' the joint.
Man, I hate lions.
- So pushy. - And hairy.
- And stinky. - And, man, are they...
- Ugly! - Ugly!
Oh, surely, we lions are not all that bad.
Oh, Scar. It's just you.
We were afraid it was somebody important.
Yeah, you know, like Mufasa.
- Yeah. - I see.
- Now, that's power. - Tell me about it.
I just hear that name, and I shudder.
- Mufasa! - Ooh! Do it again.
Ooh, it tingles me.
I'm surrounded by idiots.
Now, you, Scar, I mean, you're one of us.
- I mean, you're our pal. - Charmed.
Oh, I like that. He's not king, but he's still so proper.
Did you bring us anything to eat, Scar, old buddy?
Did ya, did ya, did ya?
I don't think you really deserve this.
I practically gift-wrapped those cubs for you...
and you couldn't even dispose of them.
You know, it wasn't exactly like they was alone, Scar.
Yeah. What were we supposed to do, kill Mufasa?
Precisely.
I know that your powers of retention
Are as wet as a warthog's backside
But thick as you are
Pay attention
My words are a matter of pride
It's clear from your vacant expressions
The lights are not all on upstairs
But we're talking kings and successions
Even you can't be caught unawares
So prepare for the chance of a lifetime
Be prepared for sensational news
A shiny new era is tiptoeing nearer
And where do we feature?
Just listen to teacher
I know it sounds sordid
But you'll be rewarded
When at last I am given my dues
And injustice deliciously squared
Be prepared
Yeah, be prepared. We'll be prepared. For what?
- For the death of the king. - Why, is he sick?
No, fool, we're going to kill him... and Simba, too.
Great idea. Who needs a king?
No king, no king, la-la la-la la la
Idiots! There will be a king!
- Hey, but you said... - I will be king!
Stick with me, and you'll never go hungry again.
- Yeah! - Yeah! All right!
All right! Long live the king!
- Long live the king! - Long live the king!
King, king, king, king, king, king, king
It's great that we'll soon be connected
With a king who'll be all-time adored
Of course, quid pro quo, you're expected
To take certain duties on board
The future is littered with prizes
And though I'm the main addressee
The point that I must emphasize is
You won't get a sniff without me
So prepare for the coup of the century
Be prepared for the murkiest scam
Meticulous planning
Tenacity spanning
Decades of denial
Is simply why I'll be king undisputed
Respected, saluted
And seen for the wonder I am
Yes, my teeth and ambitions are bared
Be prepared
Yes, our teeth and ambitions are bared
Now, you wait here.
Your father has a marvelous surprise for you.
Ooh, what is it?
If I told you, it wouldn't be a surprise, now, would it?
If you tell me, I'll still act surprised.
Ho ho ho! You are such a naughty boy.
- Come on, Uncle Scar. - No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
This is just for you and your daddy.
You know, a sort of father-son... thing.
Well, I better go get him.
- I'll go with you. - No!
No. Just stay on this rock.
You wouldn't want to end up in another mess...
like you did with the hyenas.
You know about that?
Simba, everybody knows about that.
- Really? - Oh, yes.
Lucky Daddy was there to save you, eh?
Oh, and just between us...
you might want to work on that little roar of yours.
Oh, OK.
Hey, Uncle Scar, will I like this surprise?
Simba, it's to die for.
- Shut up. - I can't help it.
I'm so hungry. I got to have a wildebeest.
Stay put.
Can't I just pick off one of the little sick ones?
No. We wait for the signal from Scar.
There he is. Let's go.
Little roar.
Oh, look, sire, the herd is on the move.
- Odd. - Mufasa, quick!
Stampede in the gorge.
- Simba's down there. - Simba?
Zazu, help me!
Your father is on the way! Hold on!
Hurry!
There, on that tree.
Hold on, Simba!
Oh, Scar, this is awful! What'll we do?
I'll go back to help, that's what I'll do.
I'll go back...
Dad!
Brother! Help me!
Long live the king.
Dad!
Dad, come on.
You got to get up.
Dad?
We got to go home.
Help!
Somebody!
Anybody.
Help.
Simba, what have you done?
There were wildebeests, and he tried to save me.
It was an accident. I didn't mean for it to happen.
Of course, of course you didn't.
No one ever means for these things to happen...
but the king is dead.
And if it weren't for you, he'd still be alive.
Oh, what will your mother think?
What am I going to do?
Run away, Simba.
Run. Run away and never return.
Kill him.
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/4wqb
Help other users to choose the best subtitles