Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
(ANIMAL WAILING)
(THUNDER CLAP)
(CREAKS)
(SINGING) Who will rescue me
(FOGHORN BLARING)
Who
Will rescue me
I'm lost at sea
Without a friend
(WOMEN VOCALIZING)
This journey
Will it ever end
Who will
Rescue
Me
Rescue me
Rescue
Me
(WOMAN SPEAKING OVER PA
IN FRENCH)
MAN OVER PA: Attention, please.
The economic and social council
will convene in five minutes.
(FRENCH CONTINUES)
(MAN GREETS IN FRENCH)
Good day, sir.
Good day, Mr. Ambassador.
(RESPONDS IN RUSSIAN)
How do you do, madam?
(RESPONDS IN GERMAN)
(GAVEL RAPS)
Order, order.
This emergency meeting
of the International Rescue Aid Society
is now in session.
Delegates, you have been summoned
from all corners of the globe
because we have reason
to believe that someone is in distress.
As you know,
our society has never failed
to answer a call for help.
(APPLAUSE)
Hear! Hear!
We will face the portrait
of the beloved founder of our society,
Euripides Mouse.
Delegates, hands over hearts.
(SINGING) R-E-S-C-U-E
Rescue Aid Society
Heads held high
Touch the sky
(OFF-KEY) You mean everything to me
In a fix, in a bind
Call on us anytime
We'll appear from nowhere
Mighty are we
R-E-S-C-U-E
Rescue Aid Society
Honesty, loyalty
We pledge to thee
R-E-S-C-U-E
Rescue Aid Society
Heads held high
Touch the sky
You mean everything to me
In a jam, in a scrape
And you think, "No escape"
- Do not fear, we'll be here
- Courageous are we
R-E-S-C-U-E
Rescue Aid Society
Heads held high
Touch the sky
Our hearts
we pledge to thee
Mouse scouts, bring in the bottle.
(SQUEAKING)
(MAN EXCLAIMS IN FRENCH)
(ALL CHATTERING)
Mr. Bernard, if you please.
Coming through. Pardon me.
Have a care there.
(LAUGHTER)
I'm sorry. Excuse me, sir.
Oops.
Egad!
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
Delegates, this is no time for levity.
Serious business, you know.
Serious business.
(SIGHS)
Now what?
Sir, there's 13 steps on this ladder.
(SCOFFS) Superstitious nonsense!
(GRUNTING)
Oh!
What next?
Oh, um, sorry, sir.
(FILTERED) I'll have it out in a jiffy, sir.
(CLEARING THROAT)
"To Morningside Orphanage,
New York."
Hmm.
Most difficult to decipher.
Well, I can't make it out.
"I am
"in terrible...
"Terrible trouble."
Oh, dear. It's all watered out.
"Hurry!
"Help! Penny."
Penny? Morningside Orphanage?
Dash it all, it's not much to go on, is it?
Oh! That poor little girl.
Mr. Chairman, please.
Please, may I have this assignment?
You? Miss Bianca?
(LAUGHING)
Dear lady, it's absolutely
without precedent.
I mean, it's not like
the old days when it was a man's world.
However,
I suppose there has to be a first time.
Mr. Chairman, sir.
I don't think Miss Bianca should go.
It could be dangerous.
I mean, anything could happen to her.
You see, dear lady,
before our janitor interrupted,
(CLEARS THROAT)
I was about to suggest
that you should have
a co-agent go with you.
Gentlemen, who will volunteer?
(CHUCKLING) Gentlemen,
this is indeed a most
difficult decision to make.
I choose Mr. Bernard
to be my co-agent.
(STAMMERING) Me?
That's really very...
No, see, I'm only a janitor.
Oh, come on.
We'll be a great team together.
Oh, come on!
DELEGATES: Bravo! Bravo!
Bravo! Bravo! Bravo! Bravo!
A janitor, my lady? Oh, good heavens.
Bless my soul.
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Morningside Orphanage.
Here! Here it is.
Three blocks down
and four blocks over.
Well, why don't we take
the shortcut through the zoo?
Gee, Miss Bianca,
I don't know. I mean, it's...
You know, it could be risky.
Oh, come on. Remember our pledge?
"Through storm and rain
and dark of night..."
"Never fail to do what's right."
All right. Duty calls.
(WHISTLING)
(ANIMAL WAILING)
(WHISTLING FALTERS)
Mr. Bernard, maybe we better go back?
It's so dark in there.
Dark?
Who's afraid of the dark?
Look, you stay here. I'll check it out.
(ANIMAL GROWLING)
(YELLING)
Wait for me!
How about tryin' the three blocks down
and four blocks over?
What did you do to make him so mad?
Nothing. He's just a grumpy, old lion.
Well, after all, waking him up
in the middle of the night,
wouldn't you be grumpy, too?
(CHUCKLING)
I didn't wake him up
in the middle of the night.
I was walking through the thing,
and I just...
All right. I'll take a look around,
see what I can find.
BERNARD: Psst! Psst!
Psst!
Miss Bianca, over here.
I found somethin'.
These are Penny's belongings.
Good work.
Now we're getting somewhere.
BIANCA: Oh, look!
The little girl's treasures.
BERNARD: Boy, the things kids collect.
BIANCA: Do you think she could
be still here in the orphanage?
BERNARD: Well, she can't be. It says
on the box, "Hold until further notice."
BIANCA: Well,
maybe she's been adopted.
BERNARD: No, because she would
have taken these things with her.
- Mice!
- BOTH: Cat!
Now lookee here, you two.
If folks find out
that mice moved in here,
I'll get kicked out, lose my job.
Don't worry, Mr. Cat.
We won't be here long.
I am a mite too old to be chasin' mice.
Sir, could you tell us what
happened to a little girl named Penny?
(MUMBLING)
I sure can.
But you ain't gonna find her
around here.
See, poor little thing ran away.
When was the last time
you saw Penny?
Was there anything unusual?
Try to remember.
Let's see, now.
The last time I saw her,
she was sittin' over there
on her bed all alone.
She looked awful sad.
And so I asked her...
What's wrong, Penny, honey?
- Nothing.
- Come on now. Come on.
No secrets. You tell old Rufus, huh?
Well, it was adoption day
at the orphanage.
- What happened?
- A man and a lady came,
and looked at me, but they
choosed a little redheaded girl.
She was prettier than me.
Oh!
She couldn't be!
You listen to me, darlin'.
You're something extra special.
No, I'm not.
Why, someday a mama and a papa
will come to the orphanage
lookin' for a pretty little girl just like you.
- Honest?
- I'll bet my whiskers on it.
But you've got to believe it.
Keep the faith, sweetheart.
Do you see that bluebird?
- Yes, I do.
- Well,
faith is a bluebird you see from afar.
It's for real and as sure
as the first evening star.
You can't touch it or buy it
or wrap it up tight,
but it's there just the same,
making things turn out right.
Can't touch it or buy it
or wrap it up tight,
but it's there just the same,
making things turn out right.
But whoever adopts me
has to adopt Teddy, too.
They'll love him!
He doesn't eat much, does he?
(GIGGLES)
Here! I brought you something.
Grand notion!
Catnip snaps.
No, they're ginger snaps!
(GIGGLING)
(CHUCKLING)
Well, an old codger like me
could use a little ginger.
(GRUNTING)
I taked two extra ones for lunch today.
(WHISPERING) We're not
supposed to do that.
Well, you can trust me.
I won't tattletale on you.
I love you, Rufus.
(PURRING)
Gee, we better hurry
or we'll be late for supper!
She seemed happy enough, but the
next thing I heard, Penny was gone.
Well, aren't the police
still looking for her?
No. No, no.
No, they gave up weeks ago.
This is terrible. That poor little girl.
I just can't believe
that Penny would run away.
Mr. Rufus, please think.
Now there must be something else.
Well,
come to think of it, there was.
No. It's nothing.
Penny wouldn't get in with her.
Get in what? With who?
A weird lady tried to give Penny a ride,
but she wouldn't have anything
to do with trashy people like them.
Trashy people? Who?
Well, she and her partner run
a sleazy pawn shop down the street.
Miss Bianca, we must
go down there and investigate.
Suit yourself, but you'd be
wastin' your time goin' down there.
She could be in real trouble.
We gotta find her and help her.
(LAUGHING) Yeah, but two little mice.
What can you do?
(CLOCK TICKING)
(TICKING CONTINUES)
(WHISPERING) Bernard!
A child's book.
It's Penny's!
Then she's gotta be here.
(CUCKOOING)
(LAUGHING)
What's so funny?
BIANCA: Your tail.
Here, here. Let me help you fix it.
(RINGING)
(GASPS)
(RINGING CONTINUES)
(SCOFFS)
Who could be ringing
at this time of the night?
Madame Medusa's
Pawn Shop Boutique.
- Hello, boss.
- (GASPS) Snoops!
Don't tell me, Snoops. Let me guess.
You found it!
You've found the diamond!
(SNOOPS MUTTERING)
Give you time? You bungler!
You have been down there
for three months.
(MUTTERING CONTINUES)
Bottles? What bottles?
You caught Penny
sending messages in bottles?
You blundering fool!
Can't you control a little girl?
Shut up! I am taking the next flight
down to Devil's Bayou.
This is terrible.
We've got to go with her.
(WHISPERING) Yeah.
Come on. In the suitcase.
(SCOFFS)
(MUTTERING)
(MUTTERING CONTINUES)
Leave them for a few weeks and...
(SCOFFS)
Why won't this stupid thing close?
(MEDUSA GRUNTS)
(ENGINE CRANKING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORN HONKING)
Out of my way, you road hog!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
WOMAN OVER PA: All passengers
please report for flight 614.
Hurry, Miss Bianca.
Madame Medusa could be down
at the Devil's Bayou by now.
(GASPING) I'm sorry,
but a lady does
have to pack a few things, you know?
WOMAN OVER PA: Will Mr. Jenkins
report to the ticket counter, please?
All passengers, please report for
flight 614. Now departing.
Flight leaves 6:45.
Oh, no. We missed the flight.
- Miss Bianca, if you hadn't...
- Come on. You worry too much.
You know that flights are always late.
MAN: Albatross flight 13 to tower.
Albatross 13.
Now, what did I tell you?
We are lucky, Mr. Bernard.
Luck? Flight 13?
- Maybe we'd better take the train.
- Wake up!
Dab-drat it,
somebody answer down there!
Get offthe dime! Hello? Hello?
Is anybody down there?
Hello?
Where have you been?
Oh, you lazy knucklehead.
Well, we just got here, sir.
See, my co-agent
insisted on packing her...
Look, bud. Am I clear to land?
Traffic up here is thicker than...
(AIRPLANE WHIZZES BY)
Wow! Dab-blast, you dirty road hog!
You crazy...
Look. What is...
You stupid lug-headed.
What did he say, Mr. Bernard?
I wouldn't dare repeat it.
Well, then give him
the permission to land.
Captain?
- You have our permission to land.
- Well, it's about time, bud.
Look! Look! There he is!
Doesn't he fly beautifully?
And you wanted to take
the train, you 'fraidy cat.
'Fraidy cat?
It was just that... No, I like trains.
I mean, they serve Roquefort.
(GASPS) Pull up! Pull up!
(SCREECHING)
(HUMMING)
Are you hurt, sir?
Nope. One of my better landings, bud.
Oh, great.
Come on. We're gonna take the train.
- (WHISPERING) Play it safe.
- Train? Safe?
Listen here, buster. I'm as fit as a fiddle.
And you look
simply wonderful, Captain.
Oh, shucks.
Just call me Orville, little lady.
All right, all right. It's most
important we get to Devil's Bayou.
Well, now will you
just keep your shirt on?
Flight 13 hits the wild
blue yonder in five minutes.
(HUMMING)
Eight, nine, ten, eleven.
Twelve. Oh, no.
There are 13 steps on this ramp.
Well, why don't you jump the last one?
This is your captain speaking.
Welcome aboard, folks.
Fasten your seat belts. No smoking.
Just sit back
and leave the drivin' to me.
(LAUGHING)
Miss Bianca, be sure
it's fastened good and tight.
I can't. It'll wrinkle my dress.
Say, bud. Read the checklist to me.
Yeah. Goggles down.
- Check.
- Wing flaps down.
- Tail feathers.
Double check.
"If at first you don't succeed,
"try, try again."
And here we go!
I sure wish we'd have taken the train.
(PANTING)
I just love takeoffs!
BIANCA: Captain, you fly beautifully.
It's just like being on a "roller scoater."
(TIRES SCREECHING)
He just went through a red light.
I do that all the time, darling.
Now, come on. Stop worrying.
(SINGING) Come along
Will there be
sunshine shinin'?
Will we find a silver linin'?
Come along
Sing a song
When today becomes tomorrow
Will we find joy or sorrow?
Sing a song
Is it wrong
To put all
our hopes together
And wish
for somethin' better?
Is it wrong
To be loved?
To face the future
with another
Who means more
than any other
Is to be loved
We'll paint the gray clouds
With pretty rainbow hues
And we'll brush the gloom away
And save itfor a rainy day
Rainy day
Oh, today
lftroubles cast a shadow
And shadows
make the sun afraid
To stay
But it's okay
'Cause there'll be
sunshine shinin'
And we'll find a silver linin'
Another day
Listen to this.
It says here Devil's Bayou
is uncharted and hazardous.
- Each day's operations...
- Mmm, interesting.
...must be...
- Good night, dear.
...planned with care and...
Tomorrow is another day
Good night, Bianca.
How I hope
you'll always stay
(ANIMAL WAILING)
MEDUSA: Penny!
Penny?
Penny, answer me!
Snoops! Snoops, get down here!
What's up, Medusa? What's going on?
That little brat has escaped again.
Nero, Brutus, bring her back, boys.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
Why won't it start?
Snoops, what's wrong?
What's wrong? I don't know.
It was workin' good yesterday.
(ENGINE STARTS)
Shut up!
Send up flares!
Light up the swamp so I can find her!
Well, folks, we'll be landing in
Devil's Bayou in just a minute.
Your crew thanks you
for flyin' Albatross Air...
What in the...
Sufferin' sassafras! My rudder's on fire!
Bail out! Bail out!
Help!
Bernard!
Mayday! Mayday!
Bufferin' catfish!
What on earth!
Luke! Luke, wake up!
Luke, get down here!
It's Orville!
Oh, that Orville.
No! No, he's in trouble!
You get down here right now!
I'm a-comin'!
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHING)
Wowee!
This new batch really packs a wallop!
(SIGHING)
BERNARD: Look out below!
Oh! Tsk, tsk, tsk!
What a shame!
Here, honey, let me help you.
Say, cousin, you look
like you could use a swig of this.
It's good for what ails ya.
There! Where you folks from anyway?
(CLEARS THROAT)
(HOARSELY) We're from New York.
Now stand back, folks! I ain't gonna
hang around this creepy place long.
Clear the runway!
(COUGHING)
Great balls of fire!
(PANTING)
(WHIMPERING)
(SHRIEKING)
Holy smoke!
Why don't you watch
where you're goin'?
Bernard, it's that terrible Medusa!
I'd like to give her
a few whacks with my rollin' pin.
We swamp folks would like to
run her clean out of our bayou.
Hold it! Hold it!
Somebody's comin' this way!
Why did you have to go
and spoil everything?
Nero, don't you dare
get my teddy bear wet.
Oh!
It's that poor little young 'un!
She's tried to run away again.
It's Penny. Oh, how terrible!
Hurry! We've got to find out
where they're taking her!
You need a boat. Evinrude's got
the fastest boat around here.
Evinrude! Wake up!
Start up ya engine, boy!
(BUZZING)
Send Evinrude back
as soon as you need help.
I'll round up the neighbors.
Faster! Evinrude, faster!
(COUGHING)
You stop that, Brutus!
BIANCA: This fog is awful.
You can't see a thing.
Whoa! Slow down, Evinrude.
(SIGHS)
(PANTING)
They gotta be around here somewhere.
(PANTING CONTINUES)
Oh, dear! We've lost them!
Jehoshaphat!
Hang on! Higher point, Evinrude!
Help me, Bernard!
Help! Bernard!
Bianca!
Come, come on, Evinrude!
Give it all ya got!
(PANTING)
BIANCA: Keep trying, Evinrude.
(PANTING CONTINUES)
Poor Evinrude!
Your carburetor is all pooped out.
Bring her right on in, boys.
(LAUGHING)
Come on.
So you tried to run away, huh?
Well, it didn't work.
Did it, huh?
(LAUGHING)
Put me down, Brutus!
Freaky little dragon!
Nice work. Good boys.
(GROWLING)
Good boys. Steady, boy.
Down, down, boys. Heel, heel!
There, there, Teddy.
I won't let them do that to you again.
Don't cry.
Teddy, Teddy, Teddy, Teddy.
Poor Teddy.
All she ever thinks about
is that simple bear.
Now you behave or I'll let Nero
and Brutus have your old teddy bear.
You will not!
Besides, I'm not scared of 'em
like you are, Mr. Snoops!
Don't you sass me!
(GROWLING)
Boys, take this naughty little girl
to her room.
I can go by myself. Thank you!
(FLARES CRACKLING)
Stick around, Evinrude.
We'll signal if we need ya.
Look out! Here she comes!
(SCREECHING)
Where is she? Where is she?
(STAMMERING) Where is she?
I sent her up to her room.
Why did you let her escape?
What is your alibi this time, nitwit?
Nitwit? Well, don't blame me, Medusa.
Those leather-headed lizards of yours,
they're supposed to be
patrolling the island.
They let her get away.
Ha!
My precious pets.
We know who caught that ungrateful
little brat, don't we?
SNOOPS: Well, it was your brilliant idea
to use the little girl for this caper.
- If you had left it to me...
- MEDUSA: Snoops, you're not thinking.
SNOOPS: No, I know, I know.
She's the only one small enough
to squeeze down the black hole.
MEDUSA: Yes, but why can't she find
my big diamond?
SNOOPS: I don't know,
but just look at these beauties
that she brought up from the cave.
They'll sell for a lot of cold cash.
SNOOPS: Ow!
I wish you wouldn't do that!
She's insane. Utterly mad.
I want that diamond.
I've got to have the Devil's Eye.
You didn't leave the girl
down in the cave long enough.
She won't take orders.
You are too soft.
But the water was rising,
and the tide was coming in
and all she did down there was fuss
about her teddy bear getting wet.
Snoops, you don't have a way
with children.
You must gain their confidence,
make them like you.
Yeah? How do you do that?
You force them to like you, idiot!
At the next low tide,
I'm going to put her down there myself,
and keep her there
until she finds it,
and it is as simple as that.
It's as simple as that, is it?
Well, you're the boss, boss.
Yes.
(SINGING) Now come along, pets
(HUMMING)
We gotta get Penny out of here tonight.
Hmm?
(SNIFFING)
Uh-oh.
- Bianca, they smell your perfume.
- Oh, dear.
(SNIFFING CONTINUES)
(GROWLING)
(YELLING)
- Oh, no!
- BERNARD: Hey, Bianca!
(BERNARD YELLING)
BIANCA: Let go, you big bullies, you!
(PANTING)
(PIPE WHISTLING)
(GROWLING)
(GROWLING CONTINUES)
(WHISTLING CONTINUES)
MEDUSA: Brutus! Nero!
Stop that infernal racket!
I mean now!
(SCREAMING)
Snoops! Snoops, a mouse! Kill it! Kill it!
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
Curses! Kill it!
(GRUNTS)
MEDUSA: There is another one!
(CLICKING)
What is wrong with this thing?
(CLICKING CONTINUES)
Snoops, what's wrong?
I don't...
(BUZZING)
Evinrude, over here!
Are you all right, dear?
Gosh! She tried to kill us!
That terrible woman!
If I was only a 10-foot mouse,
I'd show her.
It's no use, Bianca.
Maybe Rufus the cat was right.
What can two little mice do?
(SINGING) R-E-S
Rescue Aid Society
But, Bernard,
the Society's counting on us.
We can't quit now.
And that little girl.
We've just got to rescue her.
Rescue Aid Society
MEDUSA: Penny, dear.
Auntie Medusa wants to talk to you.
High tide or not,
that little brat's going
to find me that diamond.
Tomorrow, or else!
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Come in. Come in.
Did you wanna see me, ma'am?
Why, yes, my dear. Don't be so shy.
Now, I am going to let
bygones be bygones.
Do you know what would make
Auntie Medusa very happy?
Yes, you want me to find that diamond.
That's right, dear.
But I've tried as hard as I could. Honest!
Of course, you have.
But we must try harder, mustn't we?
Then please, will you take me
back to the orphanage,
like you promised?
Penny, don't you like it here?
A big, beautiful boat all to yourself.
But if I don't get back to the orphanage,
I'll never get adopted.
Adopted?
What makes you think
anyone would want
a homely little girl like you?
(SINGING) Be brave, little one
Make a wish for
each sad little tear
Hold your head up
Though no one is near
Someone's waiting foryou
Don't cry, little one
There'll be a smile
where a frown used to be
You'll be part of
the love that you see
Someone's waiting foryou
Always keep a little prayer
In your pocket
And you're sure
to see the light
Soon there'll bejoy
and happiness
And your little world
Will be bright
Have faith, little one
Till your hopes
and your wishes come true
You must try to be brave
little one
Someone's waiting
To love
You
Good night, Teddy.
Sleep tight.
Oh! We almost forgot to say our prayers.
Please bless Rufus and Teddy,
and all the kids at the orphanage,
Jennifer, Bobby, Mary, Julie.
And please let someone find my bottle.
There's a message in it.
Because running away
isn't working. Amen.
Don't worry, Teddy.
(SNIFFLES)
We'll be all right.
(SOBBING)
Penny? Penny?
- Yes?
- Penny.
Penny, dear, now don't cry.
We are here to help you.
Hi. Where'd you come from?
We found the bottle with your message,
and we've come to rescue you.
Did you hear that, Teddy?
Our bottle worked!
Didn't you bring
somebody big with you?
Like the police?
No. There's just the two of us.
But if the three of us work together
and we have a little faith...
That's what Rufus said,
"Faith makes things turn out right."
Penny, I know it's late, but we have to
escape tonight. Right now.
But I just got caught
by Brutus and Nero.
Look what they did to my pants!
Yeah, and they're still down there
guarding the gangplank.
Oh, those vicious monsters!
They ought to be locked up in a cage.
I know! I know! Come on. I'll show you.
- See there? The elevator.
- BIANCA: It's a perfect cage, Penny.
Great idea.
Now, what can we use for bait?
They'll eat anything.
- Yeah, I know.
- I've got it!
My perfume. Remember?
They'll follow the scent
right into the elevator.
And I'll slam the door.
And will that make Medusa mad.
Brutus! Nero!
Did you let that little brat escape again?
You're too soft.
Wap! Wap!
(CHUCKLING)
Hey, Penny, that's not bad.
That's exactly like Medusa.
Track her down, boys. Bring her back.
And we'll be so far ahead,
they'll never catch us.
Wait a minute. She might catch us
in her swamp-mobile.
We'll swipe it!
I've always wanted to drive it.
(IMITATING ENGINE)
What if Medusa wakes up
while we're starting it? We're in trouble.
We gotta stall 'em somehow.
How about Mr. Snoops' fireworks?
We'll shoot 'em off in her bedroom.
That'll keep her busy.
Bernard, it's so exciting.
Perfume, crocs, swamp-mobiles.
(CHUCKLES)
It's just got to work.
It's our only chance.
But we're gonna need help.
MEDUSA: Snoops! Snoops!
Get down here!
What's up, Medusa? What's goin' on?
MEDUSA: Oh, shut up!
- High tide or not...
- I bet those two are up to something.
Gee, I don't wanna go down
that awful black hole again.
Don't worry about that, dear.
You must hurry and get dressed.
Come on! We haven't got much time.
Evinrude? Up here.
We need help. Go get Ellie Mae.
And hurry!
(SQUEAKING)
(SCREECHING)
(CHEERING)
(SHOUTING)
Are you ready to help rescue
that little young 'un?
- Sure enough, Ellie Mae!
- Hallelujah!
(SNORING)
Luke!
On your feet, you lazy critter!
Oh, uh...
Shucks, Ellie Mae.
I was just a-waitin'
for someone to holler, "Charge!"
Dag nab it!
Let's cut out the jawin' and get it goin'.
(CHUCKLING)
When old Gramps gets head up,
his nose gets plum out ofjoint.
Take it easy, Gramps.
We gotta stay here
till Evinrude brings us word
from the mice.
If that bug don't get here soon,
they'll put that poor little girl
down the black hole again.
All right, you little brat.
Now, you are gonna go
down in that hole
and you are gonna dig till
you find me the diamond.
You understand that?
And no sassing me.
Ah-ah-ah, Snoops.
That is no way to speak
to our little Miss Penny.
Okay, boss. Okay.
Now, my dear,
you're going to find
the big shiny diamond
for your Auntie Medusa, aren't you?
PENNY: Teddy doesn't
like it down there.
He's afraid. Aren't you, Teddy?
Aw. Tsk, tsk, tsk.
Poor Teddy.
I'll just keep him up here with me,
where he'll be safe.
Give me back my teddy bear!
He's mine! He's mine!
You get down there
and find the big diamond
or you will never see the teddy again!
All right. All right.
I'll go.
SNOOPS: Boss,
you've really got a way with kids.
Don't worry, Teddy.
I won't be gone long.
I'll find her old diamond.
What a dreadful, frightening place.
Yeah, it used to be a pirate's cave.
How do you know that, Penny?
- Him!
- BIANCA: (GASPS) Oh, dear!
Come on, girls. Let's look for
that diamond so we can get out of here.
I've looked there already.
Medusa doesn't want these little ones.
(RUMBLING)
(STAMMERING) What's that?
PENNY: That's where the water
comes in.
Ooh!
I'm afraid to go over there.
Well, if I was a pirate,
that's just where I'd hide
the Devil's Eye.
I'll go over and check it out.
(RUMBLING INTENSIFIES)
Come to think of it,
if I was a pirate,
I wouldn't hide anything back there.
Bernard, look! I can see something.
Come on. Come on.
- Let's see what it is.
- No, no, Bianca.
You stay here.
I'll see if I can find a safe way over.
(RUMBLING)
(GASPS)
- Bianca!
- BIANCA: Hang on!
- Help!
- I'm coming!
MEDUSA: What are you
doing down there?
I'm looking!
MEDUSA: Well, look faster!
Wow!
Penny, hold your lantern up again.
- Holy mackerel! That's it!
- The Devil's Eye!
Penny, we found it! We found it!
Medusa, I found it!
Have me a look.
Have me a look, Medusa.
Back! Good girl!
Good girl! Good girl!
Let's get it up here.
(RUMBLING)
(GASPS)
BERNARD: Look. It won't go through.
We can't get it out.
- MEDUSA: What's taking so long?
- It's stuck tight!
Stuck tight? You get that diamond
or you'll never see daylight again!
BERNARD: No, no! Back! Back, Penny!
BIANCA: Oh, Penny! You'll fall!
(SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
(COUGHING)
Forget the diamond.
Let's get out of here before we drown!
The water's coming in!
Please, pull me up!
Not until you get the diamond.
Penny, the pirate sword. Use the sword.
(GRUNTING)
(STRAINING)
(CHOKING)
Penny! Penny, help!
I've got it! I've got it!
Hurry! Pull me up!
Faster. Faster!
I'm going as fast as I can.
(LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY)
At last! The Devil's Eye!
(SNOOPS LAUGHING)
It's worth millions!
Just look at it,
filled with power for its owner.
Let me look at it.
I get...
Hey, that wasn't a very good look.
(SCREAMS)
But I know there's enough there
- to cut it into two equal shares.
- You idiot!
Cut up a perfect gem? And it's mine!
It's all mine!
(LAUGHING HYSTERICALLY)
All yours? Well, half of it is mine,
you double-crossing crook!
- Put me down, Brutus!
- MEDUSA: It's mine! It's all mine!
SNOOPS: Double-crosser!
MEDUSA: Cheap pickpocket!
SNOOPS: Swindler!
MEDUSA: Cheap crook!
(WHEEZING)
(COUGHING)
Land sakes! It's Evinrude!
Old Ev sure is a mess.
Where in tarnation ya been, boy?
- What's happening?
- Do they want us now?
MAN 1: Where are they?
MAN 2: They're on the boat?
MAN 3: Speak up, boy.
Buck up.
We mustn't be quitting now, must we?
(EXHALES)
Stand back!
Give poor Evinrude some air.
He's plum tuckered out.
Here's something.
This'll make a new bug out of ya.
(TRUMPETING)
ALL: Charge!
We are gonna have us
a rip-snortin' fight!
Charge!
Where did everybody go?
I don't need any help from anybody!
Charge!
SNOOPS: Welsher! Swindler! Chiseler!
Shut up, Snoops, and don't move.
If either of you try to follow me,
you'll get blasted!
You give me my teddy bear.
You promised.
Teddy goes with me, my dear.
I've become quite attached
(LAUGHING) to him.
(SCREAMS)
My diamond! My diamond!
Charge!
(SCREAMING)
(GUNFIRE)
(WHISTLES)
Now!
Now! Now!
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
BERNARD: Look out!
Please start.
Advance the spark!
(HONKING)
Not the horn! The spark lever.
Digger, hold this.
It's that doohickey
on the steering wheel.
MEDUSA: You!
You, and your infernal fireworks!
You...
(SCREAMS) You...
Oh, you...
We're not getting any gas!
Fill 'er up, Luke. Hurry! All of it!
(ENGINE STARTS)
(SCREAMING)
(BOTH GASP)
BIANCA: Look out! The river boat!
(GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
(LAUGHING)
- We did it, Bianca!
- Hooray!
Oh, Bernard!
Bernard, you're wonderful!
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(SOBBING) There goes
my diamond!
And because ofa courageous little girl
named Penny,
the world's largest diamond,
the Devil's Eye,
is now in the Smithsonian Institute.
But what's even more important, folks,
this little orphan's dream
has come true.
Today, she's being adopted.
And here she is with
her new mother and father.
(SINGING) For Penny's
a jolly good fellow
For Penny's a jolly good fellow
From Morningside Orphanage
She's got a new mom and dad
Hooray for mom and dad
For Penny's a jolly good fellow...
Bernard, I am so happy for Penny.
Yeah, so, you might say
that Penny brought us together.
You are a darling.
Penny, you are a brave little girl to do
what you did all by yourself.
I didn't do it all by myself.
Two little mice from
the Rescue Aid Society helped me.
Mice? Rescue Aid Society?
Yes. They rescued me.
Could I say hello to them?
Hello, Bianca!
- Hi, Bernard!
- You can talk to these little mice?
All the time.
Mice can talk like anybody.
(LAUGHING)
Didn't you know that?
TV ANNOUNCER: Well, I didn't.
But I do now, Penny.
(AUDIENCE ON TV APPLAUDING)
Evinrude! What are you doing here?
(PANTING)
It's another call for help!
Here.
You're gonna need some volunteers.
But, Bianca, we just...
Oh, Bernard! Adventure!
Thrills! Intrigue! Travel! Exotic places!
Come on, darling. Let's go.
(PANTING)
(WIND HOWLING)
Sure wish we would've taken the train.
(SCREAMING)
(COUGHS)
(SINGING) Tomorrow is another day
How I hope you'll always stay
Tomorrow is another day
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org