Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
♪ Morning in Paris
The city awakes ♪
♪ To the bells
of Notre Dame ♪
♪ The fisherman fishes
The baker man bakes ♪
♪ To the bells
of Notre Dame ♪
- ♪ To the big bells
as loud as the thunder♪
♪ To the little bells
soft as a psalm ♪
♪ And some say the soul
of the city's the toll ♪
♪ Of the bells ♪
♪ The bells
of Notre Dame ♪
Listen.
They're beautiful, no?
So many colors of sound,
so many changing moods.
Because you know they do not
ring all by themselves.
- They don't?
- No, you silly boy.
- Up there, high,
high in the dark bell tower,
Lives the mysterious
bell ringer.
- Who is this creature?
- Who?
- What is he?
- What?
- How did he come to be there?
- How?
- Hush. Clopin will tell you.
- Ow!
It is a tale,
a tale of a man...
and a monster.
- ♪ Dark was the night
when our tale was begun ♪
- ♪ On the docks
near Notre Dame ♪
- Shut it up, will you?
- We'll be spotted!
- Hush, little one.
♪ Four frightened Gypsies
slid silently under♪
♪ The docks
near Notre Dame ♪
Four guilders
for safe passage into Paris.
♪ A trap had been laid
for the Gypsies ♪
♪ And they gazed up
in fear and alarm ♪
♪ At a figure
whose clutches ♪
- ♪ Were iron
as much as the bells ♪
- Judge Claude Frollo!
♪ The bells ♪
- ♪ Of Notre Dame ♪
- ♪ Kyrie eleison ♪
♪Judge Claude Frollo
longed to purge the world
of vice and sin ♪
♪ Kyrie eleison ♪
♪ And he saw corruption ♪
♪ Everywhere
except within ♪
Bring these Gypsy vermin
to the Palace ofJustice.
You there!
What are you hiding?
Stolen goods, no doubt.
Take them from her.
She ran.
♪ Dies irae
Dies irae ♪
♪ Dies illa
Dies illa ♪
♪ Solvet saeclum
in favilla ♪
Aah!
- ♪ Quando tremor
est futurus ♪
♪ Quando judex
est venturus ♪
Sanctuary!
Please, give us sanctuary!
♪ Quando tremor
est futurus ♪
♪ Dies irae ♪
A baby?
A monster!
♪ Solvet saeclum
in favilla ♪
♪ Dies irae
Dies irae ♪
- Stop!
- ... cried the Archdeacon.
This is an unholy demon. I'm sending it
back to hell, where it belongs.
♪ See, there, the innocent blood
you have spilt ♪
♪ On the steps
of Notre Dame ♪
I am guiltless.
She ran. I pursued.
♪ Now you would add this child's
blood to your guilt ♪
- ♪ On the steps
of Notre Dame ♪
- My conscience is clear.
♪ You can lie to yourself
and your minions ♪
♪ You can claim
that you haven't a qualm ♪
♪ But you never
can run from ♪
♪ Nor hide what you've done
from the eyes ♪
♪ The very eyes ♪
♪ Of Notre Dame ♪
♪ Kyrie eleison ♪
♪ And for one time
in his life ♪
♪ Of power and control ♪
♪ Kyrie eleison ♪
♪ Frollo felt a twinge of fear
for his immortal soul ♪
- What must I do?
- Care for the child
and raise it as your own.
What? I am to be saddled
with this misshapen...
Very well. But let him live
with you in your church.
- Live here? Where?
- Anywhere.
♪Just so he's kept locked away
where no one else can see ♪
The bell tower, perhaps.
And who knows? Our Lord works
in mysterious ways.
♪ Even this foul creature
may yet prove one day to be ♪
♪ Of use to me ♪
And Frollo gave
the child a cruel name,
a name that means,
"half-formed."
Quasimodo.
♪ Now here is a riddle
to guess if you can ♪
♪ Sing the bells
of Notre Dame ♪
♪ Who is the monster
And who is the man ♪
- ♪ Sing the bells, bells
bells, bells ♪
♪ Bells, bells
♪ Bells of Notre Dame ♪♪
Good morning.
Will today be the day?
Are you ready to fly?
You sure? Good day to try.
Why, if-if I picked a day
to fly, oh, this would be it.
The Festival of Fools.
It will be fun with jugglers
and-and-and music and dancing.
Go on. Nobody wants
to be cooped up here forever.
Oh, man!
I thought he'd never leave.
I'll be spittin' feathers for a week.
Well, that's what you get
for sleeping with your mouth open.
Go scare a nun. Hey, Quasi,
what's goin' on out there?
- A fight? A flogging?
- A festival.
- You mean a Feast of Fools?
- Uh-huh.
All right, all right!
Pour the wine and cut the cheese.
It is a treat to watch the colorful
pageantry of the simple peasant folk.
- Boy, nothin' like balcony seats
for watching the ol' F.O.F.
- Yeah, watchin'.
Oh, look. A mime.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
What gives?
Aren't you going to watch
the festival with us?
- I don't get it.
- Perhaps he's sick.
Impossible. If 20 years of
listenin' to you two hasn't made
him sick by now, nothin' will.
Watching the Festival of Fools
has always been the highlight
of the year for Quasimodo.
What good is watchin' the party
if you never get to go?
Here, get away from me!
Go on, ya bunch of buzzards!
He's not made of stone, like us.
Quasi, what's wrong? You want to tell
ol' Laverne all about it?
L... I just don't feel
like watching the festival, that's all.
Well, did ya ever think
of goin' there instead?
Sure. But I'd
never fit in out there.
I'm not... normal.
Oh, Quasi, Quasi, Quasi.
Do ya mind?
I would like to have a moment with
the boy, if it's all right with you!
Hey, quit beatin' around
the bell tower. What do we
gotta do, paint ya a fresco?
As your friends and guardians,
we insist you attend the festival.
- Me?
- No, the Pope. Of course, you!
It would be a veritable potpourri
of educational experience.
- Wine, women and song.
- You can learn to identify
various regional cheeses.
- Bobbin' for snails.
- Study indigenous folk music.
- Playin' dunk the monk!
Quasi, take it from an old spectator.
Life's not a spectator sport.
If watchin'
is all you're gonna do,
then you're gonna watch
your life go by without ya.
Yeah, you're human, with the flesh
and the hair and the navel lint.
We're just part of the architecture.
Right, Victor?
Yet, if you chip us,
will we not flake?
- If you moisten us,
do we not grow moss?
- Whoo, whoo, whoo!
Quasi, just grab a fresh tunic
and a clean pair of hose, and...
Thanks for the encouragement.
But you're all forgetting one big thing.
- What?
- My master, Frollo.
- Oh.
- Oh, yeah.
- Oh, dear, yes.
W-Well, when he says you're forbidden
from ever leaving the bell tower,
d-does he mean
"ever," ever?
Never ever. And he hates
the Feast of Fools.
- He'd be furious if I asked to go.
- Who says ya gotta ask?
- Oh, no.
- Ya sneak out...
- It's just one afternoon.
- I couldn't.
And ya sneak back in.
- He'll never know you were gone.
- And if I got caught?
Better to beg forgiveness
than ask permission.
- He might see me.
- You could wear a disguise.
Just this once.
What Frollo doesn't know
can't hurt ya.
- Ignorance is bliss.
- Look who's talkin'.
Nobody wants to stay
cooped up here forever.
You're right. I'll go.
- I'll get cleaned up.
I'll stroll down those stairs.
- Yes, sir!
- There ya go!
- I'll march through the doors and...
Good morning, Quasimodo.
Oh, good m-morning, Master.
Dear boy,
whomever are you talking to?
My... friends.
I see. And what are your
friends made of, Quasimodo?
Stone.
- Can stone talk?
- No, it can't.
That's right.
You're a smart lad.
Now, lunch.
Shall we review
your alphabet today?
Oh, yes, Master.
I would like that very much.
- Very well. "A"?
- Abomination.
- "B"?
- Blasphemy.
- "C"?
- C-Contrition.
- "D"?
- Damnation.
- "E"?
- Eternal damnation.
- Good. "F"?
- Festival.
- Excuse me?
- F-Forgiveness.
- You said, "Festival."
- No!
You are thinking
about going to the festival.
L-It's just that
you go every year.
I am a public official.
I must go.
But I don't
enjoy a moment.
Thieves and cutpurses,
the dregs of humankind,
all mixed together
in a shallow, drunken stupor.
I didn't mean
to upset you, Master.
Quasimodo,
can't you understand?
When your heartless mother
abandoned you as a child,
anyone else
would have drowned you.
And this is my thanks for taking you in
and raising you as my son?
I'm sorry, sir.
Oh, my dear Quasimodo.
You don't know
what it's like out there.
I do. I do.
♪ The world is cruel ♪
♪ The world is wicked ♪
♪ It's I alone whom you can
trust in this whole city ♪
♪ I am your only friend ♪
♪ I, who keep you, teach you
feed you, dress you ♪
♪ I, who look upon you
without fear ♪
♪ How can I
protect you, boy ♪
♪ Unless you always
stay in here ♪
♪ Away in here ♪
Remember what
I've taught you, Quasimodo.
- ♪ You are deformed ♪
- ♪ I am deformed ♪
- ♪ And you are ugly ♪
- ♪ And I am ugly ♪
♪ And these are crimes
for which the world
shows little pity ♪
♪ You do not
comprehend ♪
♪ You are
my one defender ♪
- ♪ Out there they'll
revile you as a monster ♪
- ♪ I am a monster ♪
- ♪ Out there they will
hate and scorn and jeer ♪
- ♪ Only a monster ♪
♪ Why invite their calumny
and consternation ♪
♪ Stay in here ♪
- ♪ Be faithful to me ♪
- ♪ I'm faithful ♪
- ♪ Grateful to me ♪
- ♪ I'm grateful ♪
♪ Do as I say
Obey ♪
- ♪ And stay in here ♪
- ♪ I'll stay in here ♪
You are good to me, Master.
- I'm sorry.
- You are forgiven.
But, remember, Quasimodo,
this is your sanctuary.
My sanctuary.
♪ Safe behind these windows
and these parapets of stone ♪
♪ Gazing at the people
down below me ♪
- ♪ All my life, I watch them
as I hide up here alone ♪
♪ Hungry for the histories
they show me ♪
♪ All my life
I memorize their faces ♪
♪ Knowing them
as they will never know me ♪
♪ All my life, I wonder
how it feels to pass a day ♪
♪ Not above them ♪
♪ But part of them ♪
♪ And out there ♪
♪ Living in the sun ♪
♪ Give me one day
out there ♪
♪ All I ask is one ♪
♪ To hold forever ♪
♪ Out there ♪
♪ Where they all
live unaware ♪
♪ What I'd give ♪
♪ What I'd dare ♪
♪Just to live ♪
♪ One day ♪
♪ Out there ♪
♪ Out there among the millers
and the weavers
and their wives ♪
- ♪ Through the roofs and gables
I can see them ♪
♪ Every day they shout and scold
and go about their lives ♪
♪ Heedless of the gift it is
to be them ♪
♪ If I was
in their skin ♪
♪ I'd treasure ♪
♪ Every instant ♪
♪ Out there ♪
♪ Strolling by the Seine ♪
♪ Taste the morning
out there ♪
♪ Like ordinary men ♪
♪ Who freely walk
about there ♪
♪Just one day
and then ♪
♪ I swear
I'll be content ♪
♪ With my share ♪
♪ Won't resent
Won't despair ♪
♪ Old and bent
I won't care ♪
♪ I'll have spent
one day ♪
♪ Out there ♪♪
Hmm. Uh-uh.
You leave town for a couple of decades,
and they change everything.
Excuse me, gentlemen, I'm looking for
the Palace ofJustice. Would you...
Mmm. I guess not.
Ahh!
Stay away, child. They're Gypsies.
They'll steal us blind.
All right, Gypsy.
- Where'd ya get the money?
- For your information, I earned it.
- Gypsies don't earn money.
- They steal it.
You'd know
a lot about stealing.
Troublemaker, eh?
Maybe a day in the stocks
will cool ya down.
- Oof!
Come back here,
Gypsy!
- Achilles, sit.
- Whoa!
Oh, dear, I'm sorry.
Naughty horse!
Naughty!
He's just impossible. Really,
I can't take him anywhere.
Get this thing off me!
I'll teach you a lesson, peasant!
You were saying...
Lieutenant?
Oh, C-Captain!
Ow! At your service, sir!
I know you have a lot
on your mind right now,
but the Palace ofJustice?
- Make way for the Captain!
- Go on, make way!
Make way!
- Everybody out of the way!
- You, make way for the Captain!
- Make way!
- Make way, now!
Come on, boy.
Achilles, heel!
- Stop.
- Sir?
Ease up.
Wait between lashes.
Otherwise the old sting
will dull him to the new.
Yes, sir.
Ah, so this is the gallant Captain
Phoebus, home from the wars.
Reporting for duty,
as ordered, sir.
Your service record
precedes you, Phoebus.
I expect nothing but the best
from a war hero of your caliber.
- And you shall have it, sir.
I guarantee it.
- Yes.
You know, my last
Captain of the Guard was, um,
a bit of a disappointment to me.
Well, no matter. I'm sure
you'll whip my men into shape.
Uh, thank you.
It's a grea...
tre... uh,
tremendous honor, sir.
You've come to Paris
in her darkest hour, Captain.
It will take a firm hand
to save the weak-minded...
- from being so easily misled.
- Misled, sir?
Look, Captain. Gypsies. The Gypsies
live outside the normal order.
Their heathen ways inflame
the people's lowest instincts.
And they
must be stopped.
I was summoned from the wars to capture
fortune-tellers and palm readers?
Eh, the real war, Captain,
is what you see before you.
For 20 years, I have been
taking care of the Gypsies,
one... by... one.
And yet, for all my success,
they have thrived.
I believe they have a safe haven
within the walls of this very city.
A nest, if you will.
They call it
the Court of Miracles.
What are we going to do
about it, sir?
You make your point
quite vividly, sir.
You know, I like you, Captain.
Shall we?
Oh, duty calls.
- Have you ever attended
a peasant festival, Captain?
- Not recently, sir.
Then this should be quite an education
for you. Come along.
♪ Come, one ♪
♪ Come, all ♪
♪ Leave your looms
and milking stools ♪
♪ Coop the hens
and pen the mules ♪
♪ Come, one ♪
♪ Come, all ♪
♪ Close the churches
and the schools ♪
♪ It's the day
for breaking rules ♪
- Whoa!
- ♪ Come and join
the Feast ♪
♪ Of ♪
Fools!
♪ Once a year we throw
a party here in town ♪
♪ Once a year we turn
all Paris upside-down ♪
♪ Every man's a king
and every king's a clown ♪
♪ Once again
it's Topsy-turvy Day ♪
♪ It's the day the devil in us
gets released ♪
♪ It's the day we mock the pig
and shock the priest ♪
♪ Everything is topsy-turvy
at the Feast of Fools ♪
Uh-huh!
♪ Topsy-turvy ♪
♪ Everything is upsy-daisy ♪
- ♪ Topsy-turvy ♪
♪ Everyone is acting crazy ♪
- ♪ Dross is gold
and weeds are a bouquet ♪
♪ That's the way
on Topsy-turvy Day ♪
Whoa!
Hey!
Are you all right?
I didn't mean to.
L-I'm sorry.
Well, you're not hurt, are you?
Here, here, let's see.
- No, no! N-No!
- There.
See? No harm done.
Just try to be
a little more careful.
L-l-I will.
By the way, great mask.
- ♪ Topsy-turvy
- ♪ Beat the drums
And blow the trumpets ♪
♪ Topsy-turvy ♪
- ♪Join the bums
and thieves and strumpets ♪
- Whoa!
♪ Streaming in
from Chartres to Calais ♪
♪ Scurvy knaves are extra scurvy
On the Sixth ofJanu-ervy ♪
♪ All because
it's Topsy-turvy Day ♪
♪ Come, one ♪
♪ Come, all ♪
♪ Hurry, hurry
Here's your chance ♪
♪ See the mystery
and romance ♪
♪ Come, one
Come, all ♪
♪ See the finest girl
in France ♪
♪ Make an entrance
to entrance ♪
♪ Dance
La Esmeralda ♪
♪ Dance ♪
- Look at that disgusting display.
- Yes, sir.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
the piece de resistance!
♪ Here it is
The moment you've been
waiting for ♪
♪ Here it is
You know exactly
what's in store ♪
♪ Now's the time we laugh
until our sides get sore ♪
♪ Now's the time
we crown the King of Fools ♪
- ♪ You all remember
last year's king ♪
♪ So make a face that's
horrible and frightening ♪
- ♪ Make a face that's gruesome
as a gargoyle's wing ♪
- Hey!
♪ For the face that's ugliest
will be the King of Fools ♪
- Why?
- ♪ Topsy-turvy ♪
- ♪ Ugly folks
Forget your shyness ♪
- ♪ Topsy-turvy ♪
♪ You could soon be called
Your Highness ♪
♪ Put your foulest features
on display ♪
♪ Be the King
of Topsy-turvy Day ♪
Bleah!
- That's no mask.
- It's his face!
He's hideous!
It's the bell ringer
from Notre Dame!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Ladies and gentlemen,
don't panic.
We asked for the ugliest face...
in Paris, and here it is!
Quasimodo,
the hunchback of Notre Dame!
Ev-ery-bo-dy!
- ♪ Once a year
We throw a party ♪
- Who-o-a!
- ♪ Here in town ♪
- ♪ Hail to the king ♪
♪ Once a year, we turn
all Paris upside-down ♪
- ♪ Oh, what a king ♪
- ♪ Once a year, the ugliest ♪
- ♪ Will wear a crown ♪
- Girls, give a kiss.
♪ We never had
a king like this ♪
♪ And it's the day we do
the things that we deplore ♪
♪ On the other three hundred
and sixty-four ♪
♪ Once a year we love to drop in,
where the beer is never stopping ♪
- ♪ For the chance
to pop some popinjay ♪
- Oh!
♪ And pick a king
who put the "top" ♪
♪ In Topsy-turvy ♪
♪ Topsy-turvy
Mad-and-crazy
Upsy-daisy ♪
♪ Topsy-turvy Day ♪♪
Quasimodo!
Quasimodo! Quasimodo!
You think he's ugly now?
Watch this.
- Quasimodo!
- Oh!
Now that's ugly!
Hail to the King!
- Bon appetit!
- Whoa!
Where are you goin', hunchback?
The fun's just beginning.
Master!
Master, please,
help me!
Sir, request permission
to stop this cruelty.
In a moment, Captain. A lesson
needs to be learned here.
Don't be afraid.
I'm sorry.
This wasn't
supposed to happen.
You! Gypsy girl!
Get down at once!
Yes, Your Honor. Just as soon
as I free this poor creature.
I forbid it!
How dare you defy me?
You mistreat this poor boy the same way
you mistreat my people.
You speak of justice, yet you are cruel
to those most in need of your help.
- Silence!
- Justice!
Mark my words, Gypsy.
You will pay for this insolence.
Then it appears
we've crowned the wrong fool.
The only fool I see
is you!
Captain Phoebus,
arrest her.
Now, let's see. One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine.
So there's ten of you and one of me.
What's a poor girl to do?
Witchcraft!
Oh, boys. Over here.
- There she is!
- Get her!
I'm free!
I'm free! Ooh!
Dang it.
Whoa! Whoo-hoo!
What a woman.
Whoa!
Find her, Captain.
I want her alive.
Yes, sir.
Seal off the area, men.
Find the Gypsy girl
and do not harm her.
I'm sorry, Master.
I will never disobey you again.
Stand back. Stand back.
Oh, he's hideous.
You, there, get away! Move on.
Hmm.
You!
Easy, easy.
L-l-I just shaved this morning.
- Oh, really? You missed a spot.
- All right, all right.
Just calm down. Just give me
a chance to apologize.
- For what?
- That, for example.
- You sneaky son of a...
- Ah, ah, ah. Watch it.
You're in a church.
Are you always this charming,
or am I just lucky?
Whoa!
Candlelight,
privacy, music.
Can't think of a better place
for hand-to-hand combat.
Ooh! You fight
almost as well as a man.
Funny, I was going to say
the same thing about you.
That's hitting a little below
the belt, don't you think?
No. This is.
Touche. Ohh!
- I didn't know you had a kid.
- Well, he doesn't
take kindly to soldiers.
Uh, I noticed.
Ah, permit me.
I'm Phoebus.
It means "Sun God."
- And you are?
- Is this an interrogation?
I believe it's called
an introduction.
- You're not arresting me?
- Not as long as you're in here.
I can't.
Huh. You're not at all
like the other soldiers.
Thank you.
So... if you're not going to arrest me,
what do you want?
I'd settle for your name.
- Esmeralda.
- Beautiful.
Much better
than Phoebus, anyway.
Good work, Captain.
Now arrest her.
Claim "sanctuary."
- Say it!
- You tricked me.
- I'm waiting, Captain.
- I'm sorry, sir. She claimed sanctuary.
- There's nothing I can do.
- Then drag her outside and...
Frollo, you will not
touch her! Don't worry.
Minister Frollo learned years ago
to respect the sanctity of the church.
All right, all right.
I'm going.
You think you've outwitted me.
But I'm a patient man.
And Gypsies don't do well
inside stone walls.
What are you doing?
I was just imagining a rope
around that beautiful neck.
- I know what you were imagining.
- Such a clever witch.
So typical of your kind
to twist the truth...
to cloud the mind
with unholy thoughts.
Well, no matter.
You've chosen
a magnificent prison.
But it is a prison,
nonetheless.
Set one foot outside,
and you're mine.
Frollo's orders.
Post a guard at every door.
Oh!
Don't worry, Djali.
- If Frollo thinks
he can keep us here, he's wrong.
- Don't act rashly, my child.
You created quite a stir
at the festival.
It would be unwise to arouse
Frollo's anger further.
You saw what he did out there,
letting the crowd torture that poor boy.
I thought if just one person
could stand up to him, then...
What do they have against
people who are different, anyway?
You can't right all the wrongs
of this world by yourself.
No one out there is going
to help, that's for sure.
Well, perhaps there's
someone in here who can.
♪ I don't know
if you can hear me ♪
♪ Or if you're even there ♪
♪ I don't know
if you would listen ♪
♪ To a Gypsy's prayer ♪
♪ Yes, I know
I'm just an outcast ♪
♪ I shouldn't speak to you ♪
♪ Still, I see your face
and wonder♪
♪ Were you once
an outcast too ♪
♪ God, help the outcasts ♪
♪ Hungry from birth ♪
♪ Show them the mercy ♪
♪ They don't find
on earth ♪
♪ God, help my people ♪
♪ We look to you still ♪
♪ God, help the outcasts ♪
♪ Or nobody will ♪
♪ I ask for wealth ♪
♪ I ask for fame ♪
♪ I ask for glory ♪
♪ To shine on my name ♪
♪ I ask for love ♪
♪ I can possess ♪
♪ I ask for God
and His angels ♪
♪ To bless me ♪
♪ I ask for nothing ♪
♪ I can get by ♪
♪ But I know so many ♪
♪ Less lucky than I ♪
♪ Please help my people ♪
♪ The poor and downtrod ♪
♪ I thought we all were ♪
♪ The children of God ♪
♪ God help the outcast ♪
♪ Children of ♪
♪ God ♪♪
You! Bell ringer!
What are you doing down here?
Oh!
- Haven't you caused
enough trouble already?
- Wait.
L-I want
to talk to you.
Look, he's got
a friend with him.
Yeah. Maybe today wasn't
a total loss after all.
- A vision of loveliness.
- The one in the dress ain't bad either.
- Way to go, Quasi!
- Congratulations.
- We knew you had it in ya.
- Got the girls chasin' ya already.
- Actually, l...
- You mustn't run too fast,
or she'll get away.
Yes, l-I know.
That's what l...
Give her some slack,
then reel her in.
Then give her some slack,
- Then give her some slack...
- Knock it off, Hugo.
She's a girl, not a mackerel.
Here you are.
I was afraid I'd lost you.
Yes. Well, I, uh...
I have chores to do. L-It was nice...
seeing... you... again.
- Oh!
- No, wait!
I'm really sorry about this afternoon.
I had no idea who you were.
I would never in my life
have pulled you...
up... on... the...
stage.
- What is this place?
- This is where I live.
Did you make
all these things yourself?
- Most of them.
- This is beautiful.
If I could do this, you wouldn't find me
dancing in the streets for coins.
- But you're a wonderful dancer.
- It keeps bread on the table,
anyway. What's this?
Oh! No, please!
L-l-I'm not finished.
- I still have to paint them.
- It's
the blacksmith and the baker!
You're a surprising person,
Quasimodo.
Not to mention lucky.
All this room to yourself.
Well, it's not just me.
There's the gargoyles
and, of course, the bells.
- Would you like to see them?
- Yes, of course. Wouldn't we, Djali?
Follow me.
I'll introduce you.
- I never knew there were so many.
- That's Little Sophia.
And Jeane-Marie,
Anne-Marie, Louise-Marie.
Triplets, you know.
- And who's this?
- Big Marie.
Hello!
She likes you.
Would you like to see more?
How about it, Djali?
- We'd love to.
- Good.
I've saved
the best for last.
Oh!
I bet the king himself
doesn't have a view like this.
- I could stay up here forever.
- Y-You could, you know.
No, I couldn't.
- Oh, yes, you have sanctuary.
- But not freedom.
"Gypsies don't do well
inside stone walls."
But y-y-you're not like other
Gypsies. They are... evil.
- Who told you that?
- My master, Frollo.
- He raised me.
- How can such a cruel man
have raised someone like you?
Cruel? Oh, no.
He saved my life. He took me in
when no one else would.
- I am a monster, you know.
- He told you that?
Look at me.
- Give me your hand. Just let me see it.
- What?
Hmm. A long lifeline.
Oh, and this one
means you're shy.
Hmm. Hmm, mmm, mmm.
- Well, that's funny.
- What?
- I don't see any...
- Any what?
Monster Lines.
Not a single one.
Now you look at me.
Do you think I'm evil?
No! No, no. You are
kind and good and-and...
And a Gypsy. And maybe Frollo's wrong
about the both of us.
- What did she say?
- Frollo's nose is long,
and he wears a truss.
Ha! Told ya!
Pay up.
- Oh, dear.
- Chump.
You helped me.
Now I will help you.
But there's no way out.
There're soldiers at every door.
We won't use a door.
- You mean, climb down?
- Sure.
- You carry him. I carry you.
- Okay.
Come on, Djali.
- Ready?
- Yes.
- Don't be afraid.
- I'm not afraid.
- Now I'm afraid.
- The trick is not to look down.
You've done this before?
No.
Ooh!
Wow, you're
quite an acrobat.
Thank you. Whoa!
Whoa!
- Check the alley!
- This way!
- I hope I didn't scare you.
- Not for an instant.
I'll never forget you, Esmeralda.
- Come with me.
- What?
- To the Court of Miracles.
Leave this place.
- Oh, no.
I'm never going back out there again.
You saw what happened today.
No. This is
where I belong.
All right,
then I'll come to see you.
- Here? But the soldiers and Frollo!
- I'll come after sunset.
But at sunset, I ring the evening mass,
and after that I clean the cloisters.
And then I ring the vespers,
and... Whatever's good for you.
If you ever need sanctuary,
this will show you the way.
- But how?
- Just remember:
When you wear this woven band,
you hold the city in your hand.
- Hurry. You must go.
- Check the alley.
Yes, sir. No one here, sir.
No one here, sir.
Check the street.
Hi, there.
- I'm looking for the Gypsy
girl. Have you seen her?
- Whoa, whoa! Easy!
- No soldiers! Sanctuary! Get out!
- Wait! All I want is to...
- Go!
- I mean her no harm.
You tell her for me,
I didn't mean to trap her here.
But it was the only way
I could save her life.
Will you tell her that?
Will you?
If you go. Now.
I'll go.
Now, will you...
put me down, please?
Oh, and one more thing.
- Tell Esmeralda... she's very lucky.
- Why?
To have a friend like you.
Hey, hey!
There he is!
You ejected that tin-plated
buffoon with great panache.
The nerve of him, snoopin' around here,
tryin' to steal your girl.
- My girl?
- Esmeralda. Dark hair,
works with a goat, remember?
Boy, I do.
Way to go, lover boy.
"Lover boy"?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
- Oh, don't be so modest.
- Look, I appreciate
what you're all trying to do.
But let's not fool ourselves.
"Ugliest face in all Paris," remember?
I don't think
I'm her type.
♪ So many times out there
I've watched a happy pair ♪
♪ Of lovers
walking in the night ♪
♪ They had a kind of glow
around them ♪
- ♪ It almost looked
like heaven's light ♪
♪ I knew I'd never know ♪
♪ That warm
and loving glow ♪
♪ Though I might wish
with all my might ♪
♪ No face as hideous
as my face ♪
♪ Was ever meant
for heaven's light ♪
♪ But suddenly an angel
has smiled at me ♪
♪ And kissed my cheek
without a trace of fright ♪
♪ I dare to dream
that she ♪
♪ Might even care
for me ♪
- ♪ And as I ring
these bells tonight ♪
- Eh?
♪ My cold, dark tower
seems so bright ♪
- ♪ I swear
it must be heaven's light ♪
- ♪♪
♪ Confiteor Deo ♪
♪ Omnipotenti ♪
♪ Beatae Mariae ♪
♪ Semper virgini ♪
♪ Beato
Michaeli Archangelo ♪
♪ Sanctis apostolis ♪
♪ Omnibus ♪
♪ Sanctis ♪
♪ Beata Maria ♪
♪ You know I am
a righteous man ♪
- ♪ Of my virtue
I am justly proud ♪
- ♪ Et tibi patri ♪
♪ Beata Maria ♪
♪ You know
I'm so much purer than ♪
- ♪ The common, vulgar
weak, licentious crowd ♪
- ♪ Quia peccavi nimis ♪
♪ Then tell me
Maria ♪
♪ Why I see her
dancing there ♪
♪ Why her smouldering eyes
still scorch my soul ♪
♪ Cogitatione ♪
♪ I feel her
I see her ♪
♪ The sun caught
in her raven hair♪
♪ Is blazing in me
out of all control ♪
♪ Verbo et opera ♪
♪ Like fire ♪
♪ Hellfire ♪
♪ This fire in my skin ♪
♪ This burning desire ♪
♪ Is turning me
to sin ♪
- ♪ It's not my fault ♪
- ♪ Mea culpa ♪
- ♪ I'm not to blame ♪
♪ It is the Gypsy girl
The witch who set this flame ♪
♪ Mea maxima culpa ♪
- ♪ It's not my fault
If in God's plan ♪
- ♪ Mea culpa ♪
- ♪ He made the devil
so much stronger than a man ♪
♪ Protect me, Maria ♪
♪ Don't let this siren
cast her spell ♪
♪ Don't let her fire
sear my flesh and bone ♪
♪ Destroy Esmeralda ♪
♪ And let her taste
the fires of hell ♪
♪ Or else let her be mine
and mine alone ♪
Minister Frollo,
the Gypsy has escaped.
- What?
- She's nowhere in the cathedral.
- She's gone.
- But how? L... Never mind.
Get out, you idiot.
I'll find her.
I'll find her if I have to
burn down all of Paris.
♪ Hellfire
Dark fire ♪
♪ Now, Gypsy
It's your turn ♪
♪ Choose me
or your pyre ♪
♪ Be mine
or you will burn ♪
- ♪ Kyrie eleison ♪
- ♪ God have mercy on her ♪
- ♪ God have mercy on me ♪
- ♪ Kyrie eleison ♪
- ♪ But she will be mine ♪
♪ Or she ♪
♪ Will ♪
♪ Burn ♪♪
'T ention!
- Good morning, sir.
- Oh.
- Are you feeling all right?
I had a little trouble
with the fireplace.
- I see. Your orders, sir?
- Find the Gypsy girl.
Ten pieces of silver
for the Gypsy, Esmeralda.
Lock them up.
Twenty pieces of silver
for the Gypsy, Esmeralda.
Take them away!
- Poor miller.
He's never harmed anyone!
- Frollo's gone mad.
We found this Gypsy talisman
on your property. Have you been
harboring Gypsies?
Our home is always open
to the weary traveller.
Have mercy, my lord.
I am placing you and your family
under house arrest until I get
to the bottom of this.
If what you say is true and you are
innocent, then you have nothing to fear.
But we are innocent. I assure you,
we know nothing of these Gypsies.
- Burn it.
- What?
Until it smoulders. These people are
traitors and must be made examples of.
With all due respect, sir, I was
not trained to murder the innocent.
But you were trained
to follow orders.
Insolent coward.
The sentence
for insubordination is death.
Such a pity. You threw away
a promising career.
Consider it
my highest honor, sir.
Get him!
And don't hit my horse!
Don't waste your arrows.
Let the traitor rot in his watery grave.
Find the girl.
If you have to burn the city
to the ground, so be it.
♪ Kyrie eleison ♪
♪ Kyrie eleison ♪♪
Sir, we've looked everywhere
and still no sign of the Gypsy girl.
I had the entire
cathedral surrounded.
Guards at every door. There was no way
she could have escaped.
Unless...
Oh, it doesn't
look good.
- It's hopeless. Absolutely hopeless.
- You're tellin' me.
I'm losin' to a bird!
- Oh, but that poor Gypsy girl.
I'm beginning to fear the worst.
- I know.
But now don't you say
anything to upset Quasimodo.
He's worried enough already.
- Yeah, you're right.
We better lighten up.
- Shh. Here he comes.
- Now just stay calm.
- Not a word.
- Easy does it.
- Stone-faced.
- Any sign of her?
Oh, it's a lost cause!
She could be anywhere!
In the stocks,
in the dungeon, on the rack!
Oh!
- Nice work, Victor.
- No, he's right. What are we gonna do?
What are you guys
talkin' about?
If I know Esmeralda, she's
three steps ahead of Frollo
and well out of harm's way.
- Do you really think so?
- Hey, when things cool off,
she'll be back. You'll see.
- What makes you so sure?
- Because she likes ya.
We always said
you were the cute one.
- I thought I was the cute one.
- No, you're the fat, stupid one
with the big mouth!
What are you sayin',
exactly?
Take it from us, Quasi.
You got nothin' to worry about.
- Yeah. You're irresistible.
- Knights in shining armor
certainly aren't her type.
And those guys
are a dime a dozen.
But you, you're
one of a kind. Look.
♪ Paris, the city of lovers
is glowing this evening ♪
♪ True, that's because
it's on fire ♪
♪ But still there's I'amour ♪
♪ Somewhere out there
in the night ♪
♪ Her heart
is also alight ♪
♪ And I know the guy she
just might be burning for ♪
♪ A guy like you ♪
♪ She's never known, kid ♪
♪ A girl does not meet
every day ♪
♪ You've got a look ♪
♪ That's all your own, kid
Could there be ♪
♪ Two like you
No way ♪
♪ Those other guys ♪
♪ That she could dangle ♪
♪ All look the same from every
boring point of view ♪
♪ You're a surprise ♪
♪ From every angle ♪
♪ Mon dieu above
She's gotta love
a guy like you ♪
♪ A guy like you ♪
♪ Gets extra credit ♪
- ♪ Because it's true you've got
a certain something more ♪
- You're aces, kid.
♪ You see that face
Ya don't forget it ♪
♪ Want something new ♪
- ♪ That's you ♪
- ♪ For sure ♪
♪ We all have gaped
at some Adonis ♪
♪ But then we crave a meal
more nourishing to chew ♪
♪ And since you're shaped ♪
♪ Like a croissant is ♪
♪ No question of
She's gotta love
a guy like you ♪
♪ Call me
a hopeless romantic ♪
♪ But, Quasi
I feel it ♪
♪ She wants you so ♪
♪ Any moment she'll walk
through that door ♪
♪ For ♪
♪ A guy so swell ♪
♪ A guy like you
With all you bring her♪
♪ A fool could tell
it's why she fell ♪
♪ For you-know-who ♪
♪ You'll ring the bell ♪
♪ You're the bell ringer ♪
♪ When she wants ooh-la-la
And she wants you-la-la ♪
♪ She will discover, guy ♪
♪ You're one heck
of a guy ♪
♪ Who wouldn't love
a guy like ♪
- ♪ You ♪
- ♪ You got a lot ♪
- ♪ The rest have not ♪
♪ She's gotta love
a guy like you ♪♪
Quasi?
Quasimodo?
Esmeralda?
Esmeralda, you're all right!
I knew you'd come back!
You've done so much
for me already, my friend.
- But I must ask your help
one more time.
- Yes, anything.
This is Phoebus. He's wounded and
a fugitive like me.
He can't go on much longer.
I knew he'd be safe here.
Please, can you hide him?
This way.
Oh. Esmeralda.
Shh-h-h. You'll hide here
until you're strong enough to move.
Great.
I could use a drink.
Aah! Yes. Mmm.
Feels like a 1470 burgundy.
Not a good year.
That family owes you
their lives.
You're either the single bravest soldier
I've ever seen or the craziest.
Ex-soldier, remember?
Why is it, whenever we meet,
I end up bleeding?
You're lucky.
That arrow
almost pierced your heart.
I'm not so sure
it didn't.
♪ I knew I'd never know
that warm and loving glow ♪
♪ Though I might wish
with all my might ♪
♪ No face as hideous
as my face ♪
♪ Was ever meant
for heaven's light ♪♪
Frollo's coming.
You must leave.
Quick, follow me.
Go down the south tower steps.
Be careful, my friend. Promise you won't
let anything happen to him.
- I promise.
- Thank you.
Quick, we gotta stash
the stiff.
Oh. Oh, Master, l-l-l-I
didn't think you'd be coming.
I am never too busy to share
a meal with you, dear boy.
I brought a little... treat.
Oh!
Is there something
troubling you, Quasimodo?
- Oh. No!
- Oh, but there is.
I know there is.
I think
you're hiding something.
Oh, no, Master.
L... There's no...
- You're not eating, boy.
It's very good. Thank you.
Mmm.
Seeds.
What's different
in here?
Nothing... sir.
Isn't this one new?
It's awfully good. It looks
very much like the Gypsy girl.
I know
you helped her escape!
And now all Paris is burning
because of you!
She was kind
to me, Master.
You idiot! That wasn't
kindness. It was cunning!
She's a Gypsy! Gypsies are
not capable of real love!
Think, boy.
Think of your mother.
But what chance could
a poor, misshapen child like you...
have against her
heathen treachery?
Well, never you mind,
Quasimodo.
She'll be out of our lives
soon enough.
I will free you
from her evil spell.
She will torment you
no longer.
What do you mean?
I know
where her hide-out is.
And tomorrow at dawn,
I attack...
with a thousand men.
Ah. We have to find the Court
of Miracles before daybreak.
If Frollo gets there first...
Are you coming with me?
- I can't.
- I thought you were Esmeralda's friend.
Frollo's my master.
I can't disobey him again.
She stood up for you. You've got
a funny way of showing gratitude.
Well, I'm not going to sit by and watch
Frollo massacre innocent people.
You do what
you think is right.
What? What am I
supposed to do?
Go out there and rescue the girl from
the... from the jaws of death,
and the whole town will cheer
like I'm some kind of a hero?
She already has her knight
in shining armor, and it's not me.
Frollo was right. Frollo was
right about everything.
I'm tired of trying to be
something that I'm not.
I must be
out of my mind.
- Phoebus!
- Aah!
- Shh! I'm coming with you!
- Glad you changed your mind.
- I'm not doing it for you.
I'm doing it for her.
- You know where she is?
No, but she said that this
will help us find her.
Good, good, good.
Ahh, great.
What is it?
- I'm not sure.
- Hmm. It must be some sort of code.
Maybe it's Arabic. No, no. It's not
Arabic. Maybe it's ancient Greek.
- " When you wear this woven band,
you hold the city in your hand."
- What?
- It's the city.
- What are you talking about?
It's a map. See, here's
the cathedral and the river,
and this little stone must be...
- I've never seen a map
that looks like...
- I've lived in the tower for 20 years.
- And I think I know what
the city looks like from above.
- This is it.
- This is not it.
All right. Okay.
If you say it's a map, fine. It's a map.
But if we're going to find Esmeralda,
we have to work together.
Truce?
- Well, okay.
- Aah! Mmm.
Sorry.
No, you're not.
- This looks like the symbol on the map.
- But what does it mean?
Hmm. I'm not sure.
I can make out an inscription,
but it's going to take
a few minutes to translate it.
Yes, well. Or we could
just go down those stairs.
Is this the Court of Miracles?
Offhand, I'd say it's
the Court of Ankle-deep Sewage.
Must be the old catacombs.
Cheerful place.
- Kinda makes ya wish ya got out
more often, eh, Quasi?
- Not me.
I just want to warn Esmeralda
and get back to the bell tower
before I get in more trouble.
Speaking of trouble, we should
have run into some by now.
- What do you mean?
- You know. A guard. A booby trap.
Or an ambush.
Well, well, well.
What have we here?
- Trespassers!
- Spies!
- We're not spies.
- You've got to listen...
- Don't interrupt me.
You're very clever
to have found our hideaway.
- Unfortunately, you won't
live to tell the tale.
♪ Maybe you've heard
of a terrible place ♪
♪ Where the scoundrels of Paris
collect in a lair♪
♪ Maybe you've heard
of that mythical place
called the Court of Miracles ♪
- Hello, you're there.
- ♪ Where the lame can walk ♪
♪ And the blind can see ♪
♪ But the dead don't talk ♪
♪ So you won't be around
to reveal what you found ♪
♪ We have a method
for spies and intruders ♪
♪ Rather like hornets
protecting their hive ♪
♪ Here in the Court of Miracles
where it's a miracle
if you get out alive ♪
Gather around, everybody.
There's "good noose" tonight.
- It's a double header.
A couple of Frollo's spies.
And not just any spies.
His Captain of the Guard and his
loyal, bell-ringing henchman.
♪Justice is swift
in the Court of Miracles ♪
♪ I am the lawyers and judge
all in one ♪
♪ We like to get the trial
over with quickly ♪
♪ Because it's the sentence
that's really the fun ♪
Any last words?
That's what they all say.
- ♪ Now that we've seen
all the evidence ♪
- ♪ Wait, I object ♪
- ♪ Overruled ♪
- ♪ I object ♪
- ♪ Quiet ♪
- Dang.
♪ We find you
totally innocent ♪
♪ Which is the worst
crime of all ♪
♪ So you're going to hang ♪
Stop!
- These men aren't spies.
They're our friends.
- Why didn't they say so?
- We did say so.
This is the soldier
who saved the miller's family.
And Quasimodo helped me
escape the cathedral.
We came to warn you.
Frollo's coming!
He says he knows where you're
hiding, and he's attacking
at dawn with a thousand men.
Then let's waste no time.
We must leave immediately.
You took a terrible risk
coming here.
It may not exactly show,
but we're grateful.
Don't thank me.
Thank Quasimodo.
- Without his help, I would never
have found my way here.
- Nor would I.
After 20 years
of searching,
the Court of Miracles
is mine at last.
Dear Quasimodo.
- I always knew you would
someday be of use to me.
- No.
- What are you talking about?
- Why, he led me right to you, my dear.
- You're a liar.
- And look what else
I've caught in my net.
Captain Phoebus,
back from the dead.
Another "miracle," no doubt.
I shall remedy that.
There'll be a little bonfire
in the square tomorrow.
And you're all
invited to attend.
Lock them up.
No, please, Master!
No, no.
Take him back to the bell tower.
And make sure he stays there.
The prisoner, Esmeralda, has been found
guilty of the crime of witchcraft.
The sentence: Death!
The time has come, Gypsy.
You stand upon the brink of the abyss.
Yet even now
it is not too late.
I can save you from the flames
of this world and the next.
Choose me...
or the fire.
The Gypsy, Esmeralda,
has refused to recant.
This evil witch has put the soul
of every citizen in Paris...
in awful jeopardy.
Come on, Quasi.
Snap out of it!
- Your friends are down there.
- It's all my fault.
- You gotta break these chains.
- I can't. I tried. What
difference would it make?
- But you can't let Frollo win!
- He already has.
So you're givin' up?
That's it?
- These chains aren't what's
holding you back, Quasimodo.
- Leave me alone.
Okay. Okay, Quasi.
We'll leave ya alone.
After all, we're
only made out of stone.
We just thought maybe you were made
of somethin' stronger.
Forjustice, for Paris,
and for her own salvation,
it is my sacred duty...
to send
this unholy demon...
back where she belongs.
No!
Quasimodo!
Sanctuary!
- Captain.
- Sir?
- Seize the cathedral.
Don't worry.
You'll be safe here.
Charge!
Come back, you cowards!
You, men, pick up that beam.
Break down the door.
Alone at last.
Citizens of Paris!
Frollo has persecuted our people,
ransacked our city!
- Now he has declared war
on Notre Dame herself!
Will we allow it?
- I think the cavalry's here.
Hey, isn't that... Feeble?
- Doofus.
Phoebus!
Sorry. Sorry.
Harder!
Ooh!
L-I'm free! I'm free!
Oof! Dang it!
Aah!
Ready, aim,
fire!
Are you sure that's how it works?
Works for me.
- Achilles, sit.
- Aah! Get off me!
Fly, my pretties! Fly, fly!
Put your backs into it!
Frollo, have you
gone mad?
- I will not tolerate this
assault on the house of God!
- Silence, you old fool!
The hunchback and I
have unfinished business to attend to.
And this time
you will not interfere.
We've done it, Esmeralda!
We've beaten them back!
Come and see.
Esmeralda, wake up.
You're safe now.
Esmeralda?
Oh, no.
- You killed her.
- It was my duty, horrible as it was.
I hope you will forgive me.
There, there, Quasimodo.
I know it hurts.
But now the time has come...
to end your suffering...
forever.
Now, now,
listen to me, Quasimodo.
No, you listen! All my life,
you have told me the world
is a dark, cruel place.
But now I see that the only thing dark
and cruel about it is people like you.
- Quasimodo?
- Esmeralda!
- She lives.
- No!
Leaving so soon?
Look, up there!
Hang on!
I should have known you'd risk your life
to save that Gypsy witch,
just as your own mother died
trying to save you.
What?
Now I'm going to do what I should
have done 20 years ago!
- Whoa!
- Whoa! Oh!
Hold on. Hold on.
And He shall
smite the wicked...
and plunge them
into the fiery pit!
Quasimodo! Quasi!
No!
Three cheers...
for Quasimodo!
♪ So here is a riddle
to guess if you can ♪
♪ Sing the bells
of Notre Dame ♪
♪ What makes a monster
and what makes a man ♪
♪ Sing the bells, bells
bells, bells ♪
♪ Whatever their pitch ♪
♪ You can feel them bewitch you
The rich and
the ritual knells ♪
♪ Of the bells ♪
♪ Of Notre ♪
♪ Dame ♪♪
Don't you ever migrate?
♪ Ooo-ooo ♪
♪ Someday when we are wiser♪
♪ When the world's older♪
♪ When we have learned ♪
♪ I pray someday ♪
♪ We may yet live ♪
♪ To live ♪
♪ And let live ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ Life will be fairer♪
♪ Need will be rarer♪
♪ And greed will not pay ♪
♪ Godspeed ♪
♪ This fine millennium ♪
♪ On its way ♪
♪ Let me come someday ♪
♪ Ooo-ooo ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ Our fight will be won then ♪
♪ We'll stand in the sun then ♪
♪ That bright afternoon ♪
♪ Oh-oh-oh ♪
♪ Till then ♪
♪ On days when the sun is gone ♪
♪ We'll hang on ♪
♪ And we'll wish
upon the moon ♪
♪ Whoa-oh ♪
- ♪ And some days
are dark and dreary ♪
- ♪ Dark and dreary ♪
♪ Seems we haven't
got a prayer♪
- ♪ Haven't we got
but a prayer♪
- ♪ But a prayer♪
♪ For somethin' better♪
♪ Is the one thing
we all share ♪
- ♪ Someday ♪
- ♪ When we are wiser♪
- ♪ When the world is older♪
- ♪ When we have love ♪
♪ I pray ♪
- ♪ Someday we may yet ♪
- ♪ Let live ♪
♪ Let live, to live, to live
To live, to live ♪
♪ And yet live ♪
♪ Oh-oh ♪
♪ Someday ♪
- ♪ Life will be fairer♪
- ♪ Need will be rarer♪
- ♪ Greed will not pay ♪
- ♪ No, no, no ♪
♪ Godspeed ♪
♪ This fine millennium ♪
♪ Let it come ♪
♪ Wish upon a moon ♪
♪ One day someday ♪
♪ Soon ♪
♪ Ooo-ooo ♪
- ♪ One day ♪
- ♪ Someday ♪
♪ Someday ♪
♪ Soon ♪♪
Good night, everybody!
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today